Hey, guys, welcome to the 50 projects, 50 days course, so this course is really meant for beginners
or intermediate level Web developers that want a cool, unique project to do every day.
And these are just HTML in JavaScript.
There's no front end frameworks used or anything like that.
And they're really meant to sharpen your skills, your JavaScript skills and just working with the doorman
general.
So I actually created this course with a friend of mine, Floren Pop.
He might know him from Twitter or Twitter or YouTube, and he actually created all these projects.
So I definitely want to give him credit for that.
And as far as what you should know, before taking this course, I would say just the very basics of
those three technologies, HTML, access, JavaScript.
I mean, I'm not going to explain what a variable is or how to import a stylesheet or anything like
that.
So you should know the very basics.
But just about anyone can take this course and there's 50 different projects.
We might add more later.
We might switch up some later.
But like I said, they're really meant to sharpen your skills and just give you something fun to create.
So if that sounds good, then let's go ahead and jump in and get started.