All right, so before we jump in to our projects, I just want to go over my environment and what I'll
be using and there's not much to talk about because this is just vanilla JavaScript and HTML and access.
So there's no frameworks or anything like that.
Basically, the text editor I'm using is VSG Code Visual Studio Code, and that's what I recommend.
It's really popular on the Web dev community.
I'm sure a lot of you, if not most of you, are already using it.
But you don't have to you can use sublime text or Adam or something like that or some other idea.
That's absolutely fine.
But if you want to follow along to a tee with this course, then I would suggest using voice code,
which you can get from Code Dot, Visual Studio, Dotcom.
Now, I just want to jump into voice code real quick and I just have my project starter, which we're
actually going to create in the next video.
But I want to talk a little bit about the extensions I'm using as well as Emet.
So Emet is a tool that's preinstalled with VAR code.
If you're using something like Ademir Sublime text, you have to install Emet as a plug in or an extension
and it just helps you write faster html.
So if I want an H1, just H1 enter will give me my tags.
If I want to add a class I can do Dorte and then you know my class enter.
If I want to do two classes I could say my class to enter.
If I want to do an ID, I can do no sign and say my ID gives me an H1 with an ID.
If I want an ID and the class, I can do that.
OK, and if I'm using a div, I don't even need to.
I mean I can do div and then my class like that, but we don't even need to add the div we can just
to dot my class enter and it will automatically give us a div.
Same with the ID.
OK, and if we wanted like three divs, we can say d'Hiv and then times three, that'll give us three
d'Hiv.
So that's about the extent that I'll be using to I do have a complete crash course on YouTube on Emet,
if you want to learn more about it.
All right.
Now, let's take a look at the extensions I'm using so you don't need pretty much the only one I would
really suggest is live server that will allow you to open our project on a development server that will
auto reload.
Whenever we save either the HTML access or JavaScript, it'll auto reload so we don't have to keep clicking
the reload button.
Other than that, I'm using auto rename tag, which just renamed the end HTML tag.
Once you rename the beginning tag pretty self-explanatory bracket pair colorize are just colorize is
your brackets, your parentheses and curly braces.
You can see these outer curly braces are purple, the inner ones are blue.
If I had another set nested in the if those would be a different color as well.
And then I'm also using prettier which is a code formatter.
As far as formatting your code, I mean it's completely up to you.
I like to use single quotes as opposed to double quotes in my JavaScript.
I also don't use semicolons.
And to set that stuff you can just go to your settings with either command, command, comma, or you
can just click on the gear down here and go to settings.
And if you search for prettier, there's a bunch of, you know, options here for for your code.
I'm going to go down to this option here.
You can see I have semi unchecked.
I'm not using semicolons.
I also have single, quote, checked tab with of two.
So, I mean, it's completely up to you on how you want to format your code.
And I'm also using format on save.
You can see that's checked.
What that means is if something is wrong, it'll fix it when I save.
So for instance, even in the HTML, if I'm like over here and I save, it goes back into place.
If I go into my JavaScript and I create a variable here, like const X equals double quotes, I will
just say test and put a semicolon.
If I save it, format's it to the way that I specified, which is no semicolons and single quotes.
All right.
So I'm just going to get rid of that and that's it.
I mean, pretty simple stuff.
You can of course use whatever text editor you want, whatever settings you want.
I just wanted to show you what I'm working with.
All right.
So in the next video, we're going to start to create this little project starter, which we're going
to use as a boilerplate for all of our projects in this course.