All right, so in this project, we're going to build some expanding cards, basically we were going
to style these panels to have a background image and a heading.
We're going to use flex blocks to align everything and then add a little bit of JavaScript so that when
we click one of these, it changes the class to active and it then expands with the CSFs transition
case.
We'll be using JavaScript for the event.
Listeners will be using CSS transitions to give it the smooth through the fact you'll see the heading
doesn't come in until the card is fully expanded as well.
And we're using just background images and headings.
But you could make these into testimonials or fake hues or whatever it might be.
So hopefully you enjoy it.
Let's go ahead and jump in and get started.