All right, so in this project, we're going to build some progress steps and you might see these in
different kinds of websites with forms, you know, multi basically like multilevel forms, shopping
carts, things like that, just a progress bar that starts at one and just goes along here.
So we're not going to have any form or anything, but we'll have these buttons to control the steps.
So it starts at 1:00.
He's got this blue outline.
If I click next, then it goes to two.
So the line we get transition goes over to two to border lights up, click next again.
And notice at the beginning, previous is disabled, so there's no reason to click previous.
And then we can keep going.
And when we click, when we get to the last one, the next is disabled.
OK, so we can just go back and forth.
And if we're at the end disabled, if we're at the end here, then next is disabled.
All right.
So we'll start off with the HTML style, style it with CSFs and then we'll add the functionality with
JavaScript.