All right, so we're going to jump into our HTML and it's going to change the title to progress steps
and in the body here, we're going to want a container around everything.
And then inside that container, we'll have a progress Dasch container and then inside there, we'll
have a class of progress.
I'm also going to give it an idea of progress, OK?
And nothing is going to go inside here.
We're just going to use it for for styling and for creating the line.
And now we do have the circles with the numbers inside.
So inside inside progress container.
But after the progress div, we're going to have a class of circle and depending on which one is active,
it'll have different styling.
So the first one here, I'm going to just manually put a class of active on and this is going to be
one and then we'll copy that down three more times.
And we don't want active on these other ones.
And this one will be step two and this one will be three and this one will be four.
And then let's go outside of the progress container still within the regular container and have our
buttons.
So this is going to be class.
Let's give it a class of BTN and I'm going to give it an idea of pre for prevue.
And I'm also going to make this disabled by default because we're going to start at one and we can't
go previous if we're at one.
And let's just say Prešov in here, copy this down and this will be the next.
So we'll get rid of disabled here and change the ID to next.
OK, so we'll save that.
It's going to look absolutely horrible for now.
But let's jump into our success and start to sharpen this up.
So I'm going to use the multi font.
So I'm going to just get rid of this here and say CSFs, questionmark, family equals Ally.
And I'll add that here and then I'm going to add a background color to the body.
So background color is going to be F six, F seven F, B and C display Fleck's.
We can get rid of the column, justify a line center.
OK, that stuff is all good.
So for the container, we're just going to text a line to the center and then for the progress container.
Let's display that as a flex box.
OK, so it's going to remember the progress container wraps around this right here, not the buttons.
So put that into a flex row.
Now, as far as the remaining content, let's do justify content.
So I want to take the remaining space here and put it in between the elements.
So we're going to use space between, OK.
So that will separate them out.
We're going to position relative so that we can position other things inside of it.
Absolu.
Let's add a margin bottom of 30 pixels and let's set a max width of 100 percent and set a width of 350
pixels.
And you could change this, of course, if you wanted to.
So now we want to start to work on the line that's going to go through the middle of these and then
we'll work on the circles.
Now, the way we're going to do this is the progress.
This div right here is going to be the blue line that that changes, that has a transition.
When we click next, it'll go to two, three, so it'll go to a certain percentage and then we're going
to have a faint gray line behind it, which is basically represents the empty line and that's going
to be on the before pseudo selector of the progress container.
All right.
So let's go ahead and create the blue line first.
So that's going to be on progress.
All right.
We're going to set a background color.
Let's set it to hexadecimal three, four, nine, eight DB.
And we want to position this to be absolute within the progress container, which is positioned relative.
And as far as where I want to put it, I want it in the middle, you know, vertically.
So let's do 50 percent from the top and let's do from the left zero and it'll have a height of four
pixels.
Now the width is going to start out as zero percent because we're going to start, you know, at the
beginning here, but just for now, so we can actually see it.
I'll set it to 50 percent.
Now, this isn't directly in the middle.
The top of the line is in the middle, but we want the middle to be in the middle.
So we want to add a transform and set translate on the Y axis, which is the vertical axis.
Want to move it up 50 percent.
OK, so now it should be right in the middle.
And let's also set a Z index because we want to make sure this is behind the circles, behind the numbers.
So we'll set that to negative one.
And then this is going to have a transition on it, because when we do click previous or next, we want
the line to transition in a certain duration, not just flip to the next one.
So we'll just two point four seconds with an EZ effect.
All right.
So that should be good as far as that goes.
Now, I'm going to just change this to zero percent with because that's going to be the starting point.
And I'm going to copy this and go right above it.
And this is going to be the progress container and we're going to use the before selector and then this
is going to be the faint gray line behind it.
So I'm going to use E zero three times as the background.
These coordinates are going to be the positioning is going to be the same, the height, the same.
The width, however, is going to be one hundred thousand one hundred because it's going to represent
the empty line.
And we don't need a transition because it's not actually going to do anything.
It's just the the line behind it.
So I saved it.
But the reason we're not seeing anything is when you use before or after, you have to add content,
which I, I often forget and just set it to an empty string.
So now we can see the line behind it.
Now, if I were to set this to, you know, 50 percent, you can see now it fills in that gray line.
But we're going to keep that at zero for now and let's style the circles.
OK, so all we have left now is the circles and the buttons.
So say circle.
And for this, let's give it a background color of white, and we're going to do a color of nine nine
nine.
So just like a gray color and.
Let's see, let's do a border radius.
Border radius, we want us to be rounded so 50 percent and let's set a height of 30 pixels and we'll
also set a width of 30 pixels.
All right.
Now we want to center the the numbers in the circle.
So one of the easiest ways to do that is just display Fleck's a line items center and justify content
center.
So those are put the numbers right in the middle.
Let's see.
Let's give it a give them a border.
So border will be three pixels solid and let's do a light gray.
So E zero basically the same color as the as the line.
And I think that should do it.
We do want to add a transition.
The border is going to change depending on where the blue line is.
If it's up to two, then that border should be two.
And that that's going to pertain to the active class, which will style in a second.
But for the transition, let's do point four seconds ease and then let's do the active class.
So circle, if it has the active class on it, then let's make the border the color and sit that two
three four nine eight DB
and that should be the same as or is it right here three four nine eight that we could actually use
some custom properties here.
So defiant to define custom properties which are basically just variables.
We need a scope.
So I'm going to put it on the root scope.
And let's set the wheels, a line fell and set that actually it's the line in the buffet line.
Water fell and grab this.
And put that in their.
And then let's say.
Line border empty.
And that's going to be that e0.
OK, so now we can just replace this with vare dash, dash line border empty.
I'm just going to copy that.
And this one here, this is going to be oops, this is going to be Phil.
So line border Phil.
And this one here will be line border empty.
That's the border of the circle, and then if it's active, it'll be filled.
So that way you can just if you want to change the colors, you can do that easily up above.
All right.
So now for the buttons.
Those are the last thing we want to style.
So BTN and this is actually going to have the same background color as the film.
So we'll go ahead and just add that here as well.
OK, and let's set the color to white and let's remove the button border, let's set the border radius
to six pixels and set the cursor to a pointer.
Let's set the make sure we inherit the font family.
So inherit good.
Let's add some padding.
So we'll do eight pixels, top and bottom, 30 pixels left and right and add a little bit of margin.
So five pixel margin and that should do it actually.
Let's make the font size 14 pixels, OK, and then we'll just have a little scaling effect on the active.
So like when we click it so btn cool and active and add a transform, we want to scale it down a little.
So from one will go two point ninety eight.
That way when we click we have you know that little factoid.
This is disabled.
Remember the previous.
So I can't click that but that has that little effect.
Let's also get rid of the outline.
So BTN when it's in its focus state, we want to set the outline to zero or none.
All right.
Let's also let's make it if it's disabled, if the button is disabled, we'll make it grey.
So let's say button Colen disabled because we can target that and we're going to set the background
color to vare and let's use the empty.
And I'm also going to set the cursor from a pointer, set it to not allowed.
So that way, if it's disabled, we can't you know, it gives us that not allowed cursor can't click
it.
So that does it for the styling.
So in the next video we can go ahead and add the JavaScript so we can click next, have this move to
the second one, third one, have it moved back with previous and so on.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next video.