All right, so we're going to get started here, I have my project starter open.
I also have a link here to the font awesome CDN so that we can use some icons for the open and close
buttons.
So in the title here, I'm just going to say rotating navigation and down here, let's get rid of this.
Each one, we're going to have a container that wraps everything.
And in here we're going to have a circle dash container that's going to wrap the circle of the class
of circle.
And this is basically the, you know, the circle.
It's going to be up in the corner with the buttons.
So in here, we're going to have a button with the idea of close.
And I just want to use an icon from font.
Awesome.
So eFax and then a dash times will be the icon and right under that will have a button with the idea
of open.
And this is going to be the icon eFax and then a dash barres to give us like that, you know, at Hamberger.
Look.
So if I save that, we're just going to see our two buttons here and now we want to be still within
the main container, but outside of the circle container.
So right above the last div, we're going to have our content and you could put absolutely anything
here in this content, Dev, we're just going to put in each one say amazing article and small tags
will put the author, our good friend, Foreign Pop and then paragraph, let's do Lorem 100 just to
throw some dummy text in there under the paragraph, we'll have another H3 and we'll say my dog and
we're going have a picture of a dog.
I'm just going to piece this this image tag in here.
And of course, like I said, you can put anything you want here.
This is just an on splash image of a dog.
And then underneath that will have a paragraph will do Lorem 75.
And save and get a cute little dog on the screen, so underneath the container, so the container ends
here, the last div, we're going to put our nav, so let's just create a H2O five nav tag with the
URL and then an ally.
And I'm going to use icons here as well.
So we'll do I f a s and F a dash home and then next to that icon will just stay home and copy that down
twice.
So this one is going to be about I mean, these are probably B links, but that's fine.
You can add the links if you want.
So fails, let's do user dash Alz and then for this is going to be contact, these aren't going to be
actual pages.
The point of this project is the the actual animation and the position of the nav and all that, not
the actual inner pages.
So this will use the envelope.
OK, so that should do it for the HTML.
Let's jump into our stylesheet and we'll do a good part of this.
Now we probably have to break it into another video because there's quite a bit of success, but I'm
going to use the latest font.
So success Questionmark Family equals Lato and then we'll add that to our body.
All right.
And then let's see.
We're actually not going to use all this Fleck's stuff here.
So I'm going to get rid of pretty much all of this except for.
Except for the overflow hidden, which I'm actually going to change to overflow accident, so what that
does is it only hides the scroll bar on the x axis.
So going this way.
So we want to be able to scroll this way and then margined zero.
And then let's also add a background color of three three three, which is a dark gray.
And then let's have color.
Ta ta two, and I know that that doesn't look right, but we're going to set the container background
color to a light color.
So let's do background color and we'll do a three times now with this container.
Basically, it's going to rotate a little bit over when it has a specific class of Chenab.
So before I add anything else to the container, let's do container when it has shown NAV and we can
rotate it with the transformed property and then rotate and I'm going to rotate it negative 20 degrees.
All right.
And then let's see if we go back here and we just add that class manually to this show NAV, then you
can see it rotates.
And I'm just going to keep that there for a second.
We're going to want to change the transform origin.
So transform origin when you when you rotate the origin by default is going to be like in the middle.
It just it just turns it.
It rotates it.
However, we want it to rotate from the top left position.
So it rotates.
I can't really explain.
If you go to the Amdocs for Fortran transform origin, you'll be able to see how it works with different
values.
But we want to set the transform origin property to the top left.
OK, so now you can see the rotation point is up here instead of in the middle.
Now we do want to transition on that because we don't want to just flick, you know, rotate real quick.
We want it to be smooth.
So let's add a transition onto that.
And we want to transition the transform property, say zero point five seconds and we'll just use linear.
So it's just, you know, all one speed or whatever.
And you can see it actually does it when I save because we have that class on it.
Now, I'm going to just go ahead and get rid of that class for now.
But we know that it does rotate when it has that specific class added.
So some other things I want to do here is just set the width to 100 viewport widths.
So basically take up the whole, you know, the whole viewport horizontally.
And then let's set the min height to I'm going to set that to one hundred viewport heights.
So we want to take up the whole viewport and then for padding, let's say padding fifty pixels all the
way around and that should do it for the container.
Now let's work on the circle container which is around this so circle Dasch container.
And I want to position this in a fixed position and we want it to be like a half circle on the edge
of the page.
So we'll set this to negative one hundred pixels for the top and then left same thing, negative 100
pixels.
And right now we just don't see anything.
Basically the buttons are not showing right now.
So far the circle itself, because remember, we have a circle container, but then we also have a class
of circle that wraps around the icon.
So this is where we're going to have like the background color, which is going to be hexadecimal F
F seven nine seven nine.
And let's set a height of two hundred pixels in a with of two hundred pixels and now you can see it
up in the corner there.
We want this to be a circle.
So Border Dasch radius, we're going to set that to fifty percent, make that a half circle.
I mean it's a full circle but half of it's off the screen.
That's what we did.
Negative 100 because we have two hundred for the height and the width.
If you increase or decrease this, you want to adjust that as well.
And we want to position this relative so we can position the buttons inside absolute.
And this is going to rotate.
So I want to add a transition on the transform.
Property and let's make that same thing, zero point five seconds linear, it's the same as the container
rotation.
All right.
And then for the buttons, let's say a circle button.
And for these, I want to I know we can't see them at the moment, let's actually position them for
our sole position, them absolute sort of a position, absolute, and let's put them top 50 percent.
And from the left, 50 percent.
And then let's make the height one hundred pixels.
And then let's set and I know it doesn't look right yet, let's set the background to transparent.
And they're both right and they're both from the same exact spot right now, we want to take off that
border.
So Border zero, let's set the font size bigger as well.
So font size will set that to twenty six pixels.
And let's put the color to white.
OK, and then I just want to get rid of this border, one intense focus state, so let's say dot circle
and the button we want to target focus and set out line to none.
OK, good.
Let's see.
So each one has one has an idea of open, one has an idea of close.
So I want to target the open.
So circle button the idea of open and I'm going to set that left value to 60.
Percent, Hey, the open button is what we're going to see initially, and that's where I want it positioned.
So for the close, let's say, circle and we want the button that has the idea of close.
And I'm going to set that to top and at that to 60 percent, and this is relative to the circle, OK?
And we want to rotate this this close button.
So let's use, transform, rotate, and we're going to rotate it 90 degrees or 90 degrees.
And let's set this transform origin.
Transform Origin is going to be top left as well.
So now I save it and you can't see it.
It's up here.
In fact, if I take my container here and let's set just temporarily set this to 200 pixels.
I can see exactly where it's positioned, so just put that back to negative 100 and we should just see
the lines here and it's going to stay fixed there no matter what.
This image, though, let's let's just fix that real quick.
We're going to do the rest of this season in the next video.
But I just want to target the content image and set a max width of one hundred percent of its container
because that's bugging me.
But, yeah, you could have absolutely any content you want here.
And we can see the nav and stuff down here.
But in the next video, we'll finish the access and then we'll add a little bit of JavaScript to be
able to click this and, you know, add the show NAV class and will do to do its whole rotation effect.
Let's actually add, though, onto onto the button.
Let's add a cursor pointer like that.
All right.
So that's it.
I'll see you in the next video.