All right, so we need to finish up our success, we have to deal with the actual NAV down here, but
before we do that, I'm just going to add a couple more content styles.
So for for the content itself, let's do a max width of 1000 pixels and we'll set margin.
Let's do 50 pixels on the top and bottom.
Auto on the left and right.
Keep it in the middle.
So even if we stretch it out, you know, it's going to have a thousand pixel thousand pixel with Max.
And then for the one sided content, each one of those is going to take the margin away from that.
So margin zero.
And then for the small tag for the author,
let's set a color of five five five and let's set a font style of italic.
And then for the paragraphs.
So content paragraph, we're going to set color to three, three, three.
And let's set let's increase the line height to one point five.
And we already have the image at 100 percent with good.
So now we just need to really deal with the navigation, which is right now is down here.
And what I want to do, since we're only going to see this when this actually rotates, when we click
this, I'm going to add the show now.
So show dash nav.
I'm going to manually add it for now and then the actual navigation.
We want that to be positioned over here.
Right.
So let's let's do this above where we did the content stuff.
And I'm just going to use the nav tag as a selector.
And I want to position this to be fixed because we want it fixed down to the bottom.
So we'll say fix and bring it from the bottom 40 pixels up and from the left zero.
So that puts it, you know, near where we're actually going to want it.
And then I'm just going to set a high Z index here.
So it's on top.
Let's do a Z index of one hundred and then for the you'll say nav unordered list.
I'm not class just now.
So for that, let's do a margin, not a margin, let's do a lifestyle type of nun, so that will get
rid of those bullet points and then I'm going to set patting left to 30 pixels and then we want to style
the list items.
So NAV, you'll ally.
And I want them all uppercase, so let's do a text, transform uppercase, and let's change that color
to whites.
And let's set a margin of 40 pixels on the top and bottom, so we're really going to separate them from
each other and then let's.
Let's bring it over here.
We need to have it initially over here.
More to the left, because it's going to come in as this rotates or right after rotates.
So to do that, we can use transform and we want to translate on the X axis.
So translate X, we want to bring it left.
So that would be negative.
Will do negative 100 percent.
So if I save that now, you can see that it's, you know, it's way over here.
We can still see it a little bit.
That's fine.
It's just going to come in.
But we want that to come in smoothly.
So let's add a transition on that.
So transition the transform property and we'll do a zero point four second duration and we'll use these
in here.
And then let's see for the you know, let's comment this out for a minute just so we can actually see
this.
I want the this or some more space between the icon.
So let's do nav u l l i.
Well, I am going to set the font size, do 20 pixels and let's set margin right to 10 pixels.
OK, so makes the icon a little bigger, also put some space in between them.
Now.
We're going to want each with each one of these to stick out a little more, kind of going at an angle,
so what we can do is take the nav, let's say NAV, Ueli and then the direct ally after that.
And let's add a margin left of 15 pixels.
So if I save that, what happens is the allies after the initial lie are going to stick out 15 pixels.
Now, I want this last one to stick out even more.
So what I'll do is take this, copy it.
And let's say Elai, plus Elai plus elai.
So basically, anything after, you know, this one here, so the contact when I want to stick out,
double that of 30 pixels, now you can see that it's at an angle kind of at the same angle as the pages
here.
So we have an initially we have this negative 100 percent translate X.
So if I can comment that it goes almost off the screen, but we're going to want these ones to initially
start out more over as well to the left.
So I'm going to copy that.
And for this one, here we have our our margin left 15.
Let's do negative 150 percent.
And then for this one here, let's add let's do negative two hundred percent because we need those to
be over more.
Now, when we have the show NAV applied, we wanted to actually show the navigation.
Everything we just did is the default.
When you first come to the page, when this class is actually there, which it is now, because we manually
added it, we want to see all the navigation stuff.
So let's go.
We want to do this, we'll go right above the nav here and let's say so, the Container d'Hiv, when
it has show Dasch NAV, then we want to take the direct navigation allies after that and we want to
bring them into view.
So let's set transform translate acts on all of those to zero, which is going to bring it to its,
you know, its original place.
And I want to add a little bit of a delay.
So we'll say transition delay.
Spell that right, transition delay, I'm going to set that to zero point three seconds so that it comes
in, you know, a little bit after I forgot my semicolon.
So it comes in a little bit after the rotation.
So now we're able to see it because we have that show NAV.
So if we take this off, then we just have, you know, just looks normal and then if we have it, you
can see it rotates and shows the the navigation.
Now we want to have the functionality where we click this.
Then it adds that class, which is going to be pretty easy.
So let's jump into our script here and let's create a variable called Open and we'll use documents dot
get element by D we have an idea of open.
We also have an idea of close.
So close, and then we also want to grab the container so consed container
kit element bidi actually no that's a that's a class.
So let's do I mean you could add an ID or you could just use Querrey selector and we want dot container.
It's a class.
All right.
So let's take open and let's add an event listener to that.
So we want to listen for a click, and when that happens, we're going to run a narrow function and
then we just want to take the container and from the class list, we want to add the class of the show.
Dasch now and then close is going to be similar.
So I'm someone's going to copy that.
And let's change this to close and then let's do container class list remove.
All right.
So I save that and I click, OK, so that happens.
So let me just reload, so I click and that rotates these shoot in, but we can't see the the close
here.
So to handle that, let's go back to our success.
And we basically just want the circle this to rotate when there's that show now of class.
So I'll go right below the circle.
So it's a circle and
dot show nav
and then we're not actually style I'm sorry, not circle container.
So when the container has shown that I've applied to it, then we want to style the circle.
And what we want to do with the circle is rotate it.
So let's say transform, rotate and we're going to rotate it negative 70 degrees.
OK, so now once it rotates, we can see the close button just because of where it's positioned.
When this circle rotates, it just comes into view.
All right.
So that looks pretty good.
So not too bad.
I mean, we're just adding or removing a class and we're setting certain certain styles on the circle
and on the navigation, you know, when we have that class applied.
So you could use this on with any website, any application.
So that's it.
Let's go on to the next video.
Next project.