OK, so this is going to be one of the shortest projects in this course, but it's a cool little widget
that you can add to your website or to your application.
It's a hidden search.
And we just have this button here with a little search icon from font.
Awesome.
And as soon as I click it, if I was offered JavaScript event, that activates a specific class where
we add a transition for the width of this input to get wider and the button to move over using a transform
translate X, and if I click it again, it's going to shrink back up.
OK, so we'll be using CSFs transitions along with just a little bit of JavaScript to add the event
and toggle the class.
All right, so let's get started.