All right, we're going to get started on our hidden search form.
So in our time out here, I have my project started.
You can also see I have the font awesome link here because we're going to be using the search icon for
the button.
So let's change this to a hidden search.
And then down here in the body, let's create a div with the class of search and this div is going to
wrap both the input and the button, and that's really all we have.
So let's add the input.
I'm going to give this a we'll give this a class of input and the type is going to be text.
Let's also add a placeholder.
So placeholder will just be search, dot, dot, dot.
And then right after the input will have the button and the button is going to have a class of beats
and inside that button will have an ID tag with the font.
Awesome icon.
So fase and a dash search for the icon.
So I save it.
We're going to see this.
Just a regular looking ugly search form.
So let's jump into our success.
Basically, what we want to do is have a class of active and when we when it's active, the the input
here will expand and the button will move over.
And we wanted to start with just just showing the button.
So let's just get some general styles in here first as far as the body goes.
I want to add a background, let's say background image, and I'm going to use a linear gradient so
we'll see a linear gradient.
Let's do a 90 degree gradients and four colors will do the hexadecimal value of 75 F, F, F, and let's
do hexadecimal seven one five eight E two.
OK, so those are going to be our colors and we need to put a semicolon here that I forgot.
Where am I?
Where's my cursor.
OK, so now we have that background gradient, you can probably make this a little smaller here.
OK, so background now we want to display Fleck's align everything to the center.
We don't need we don't need where is it?
Flex Direction as a column height 100 viewport.
It's good.
The search class.
I'm going to position this relative so we can position things inside of it absolu.
And let's set the initial height here to 50 pixels.
And then for the input, I mean, that has a class of input actually.
Let's do search input and let's set a background color of white and let's set a border of zero.
Take away any border and I'm going to make the font size 18 pixels will make that a little bigger.
And let's set the padding on this to 15 pixels all around and we'll set the height to 50 pixels and
let's set the width to 50 pixels.
So it's going to start off short like this, but then we'll have an animation or a transition to expand
it.
So I want to add here a transition on the width property.
OK, so we want the width to have a transition that's going to last zero point three seconds with an
EZ effect.
Now for the button, let's style that, so that has a class of BTN and we're going to set a background
color of white.
And let's set a border of zero.
We want the cursor to be a pointer when we hover over it, we want a font size of twenty four pixels.
So remember, this is the button with the icon.
And I want to position this absolute within the within the search class here, the search container
and let's say from the top zero and from the left zero.
And then we're going to give this a height and width of 50 pixels.
OK, so it puts it right in the middle there and then I want to transition on this, because what we
want to do with the button is move it over.
We want the the input to it to expand the width.
We have the transition for that up here, the button we want to push over.
OK, so the input gets wider, the button gets pushed over.
So we'll use transform on that.
So we want to add a transition for transform same amount of time as the width on the input and and ease
effect.
OK, and then we want to get rid of any outline, so let's grab, let's say, the BTN when it's in its
focus state and also the input when it's in its focus state.
We want to set the outline to none.
OK, so now we don't see that outline.
And then finally, we want to take the search.
Inputs, but when it's active, so the search class, if it has an active class, then we want the input
to go to 200 pixels from what was it, 50?
Yeah, so it starts at 50.
And then when and when the search element has an active class on it, then the width will go to 200.
And then we also want the button to move over.
We have a trend, a transition on the transform, but we haven't actually created that yet.
So also when the search has the class of active on it that we want to take the button, we want to set
transform and we want to move it.
We want to move it along the X axis.
We want to move it to the right so we can use translate X.
So translate on the X axis and we'll move it over one hundred and ninety eight pixels.
All right.
So if I save that, we're not going to see any difference here because we need a little bit of JavaScript
to be able to give it that class and you'll see if I manually put on the active class here.
There we go.
It expands.
So JavaScript is going to be really simple.
Let's go ahead and bring in the search.
So document dot.
Query selector.
And we want to grab the class of search and then let's also grab the BGN.
PETN, and then let's grab the input input and then I'm going to take the button and we want an event
listener on that, so we want to add an event listener of a click event.
And when we click, we're going to call an arrow function here.
And all we want to do is take the search.
Remember the search div, which I just showed you?
If I put an active class on that, it widens it out, pushes the button over.
So that's what we want to do.
We want to say from search, we have our class list and then there's a method called toggle to toggle
a class, basically just add and remove it.
So we'll toggle the class of active.
I also want to set focus on the input, which we can just use the focus method.
All right.
So if I go over here and I click, it not only opens it and, you know, pushes the button over, widens
the input, but it also focuses in the in there.
And if I click goes back and you can see just from the projects we've done so far and some of the ones
that we're going to do a lot of this just it's all just putting specific classes through our JavaScript,
through events, you know, clicking or hovering over something and making an event far off where we
just add or remove or toggle a class and then we have a transition to give us a cool little animation.
So there's very little need for something like Jan to do stuff like this anymore.
You just use vanilla JavaScript to mix with success and you can do just about any kind of animation
that you can do with J query pretty easily.