So in this project, we're going to be building a blurry loading page or loading image, so if I come
to this page here, you'll see that the image starts blurred and we also start with, you know, zero
percent and then that goes up to 100 percent and the image comes into focus.
So you could use this to load just about anything.
We're just doing a blur effect on the image.
But you could load in your site.
You could have any other elements in the DOM load in that specific amount of time from when we go to
zero to 100 and we'll have to map different number ranges to the zero to 100 load.
For instance, the image blur is going to be 30 pixels when it starts and it's going to go down to zero
as we go from zero to 100.
And there's a stack overflow function that we're going to use to help us do that, to help us map one
number range to another.
All right.
So that's it.
Let's get started.