So we're going to get started on the blurry loading project and the trial is going to be really simple,
is actually only two lines in the body.
Well, let's add a title here.
So call this blurry floating and then down here, let's get rid of the H1.
And this is going to be a section I'm going to give this a class of B.G. So this is going to be the
background image that we blur and then we'll have around.
The text will have a class of loading dash text and we just want to put in here zero percent and that
should do it as far as the as far as the HTML goes.
So let's jump in to our stylesheet and there's not too much we have to do here either.
I'm going to change the font.
So I just want this to be Google APIs dot com exists and we want to use a font family.
I'm going to use a family of Ubuntu.
I can smell family correctly and then let's change down here, change for to Bunta and then this stuff
can really all stay the same.
You don't have to change anything here.
We don't need Fleck's direction column, but it's not going to hurt if you do leave it.
Now for the background level, we have that section with the class of B.G. and we want to set a background.
So let's just use the background property and say we want this to be a neutral.
And the actual image that I'm going to use, I'm just going to copy and paste.
And of course, you can use any image you want.
If you want to use this one, you can get it from the link from the repository.
So let's make this have no repeat.
Let's make it center center on the X and Y axis and cover for the background position.
And we want to position this absolute.
And then let's set the top, so I'm going to initially just set the top and left to zero.
I'm going to change this and I'll show you why in a couple of minutes.
And then the width will set that to 100 viewport widths and the height to 100 viewport height.
So we just wanted to take up the whole viewport.
And let's add a Z index here of negative one, because we want this to be behind the zero percent or
whatever the percentages, the text.
And we want to add a filter here.
And initially the blur is going to be set to zero pixels.
And then for the loading text, we just want to increase the font size.
Let's set that set the font size to 50 pixels and let's set the color to white.
Really depends on the background image we use.
All right.
So that gives us this.
Now, I just want to show you something, Afie, because this is going to start blurry and then it's
going to make its way up or make its way down, I should say.
The higher the pixels for the blur, the more blurry it is.
So if I put like 70 pixels in here, that's what it looks like now.
Notice on the edges, this comes out quite a bit.
So I actually want to fix that.
I don't want it to come out that much.
So for the top and left, I'm going to set that to negative 30 pixels.
And it's also set the left to negative 30 pixels.
Now, if I do that, you're going to see there's less spacing on the left in the top, but there's more
over here.
So for the width and the height, what we can do is calculate so we can use calc and just wrap this
and we just want to add 60 pixels like that.
And now you can see that it's even on the left and right.
We want to do the same for the top and bottom.
So we'll do the same thing.
We'll just calc and we want to add 60 pixels here as well.
And now there's not as much space.
All right.
So I think that that looks a little better.
So let's put this back to zero pixels.
So in the next video, we want to add our JavaScript so that we can have this image basically start
blurry and then have it work its way up to being clear as this percentage loads here.