So now we want to work on actually having this percentage change, so we want it to go from zero to
100 and then the background image is going to start blurry and then it's going to go to clear as this
loads.
So first thing, we'll just bring in the two elements we have, which are the load text.
So let's say document, dot, query, selector, query selector, and we have a class of text or what
we call loading text.
And then we also want the background.
So that has a class of B.G. and we'll just call this B.G..
OK, now I'm going to initialize a value here called load, which is going to start at zero.
Obviously it's going to go from zero to 100 and we're going to have a function here called blurring.
And right now, I just want to take that load value and increment it by one, and then I'm going to
go ahead and just cancel log load.
Now, the way we want to run this function is in an interval, and I want it to run every 30 milliseconds.
So let's create a variable here called INT.
We'll say let in and set this to set interval and the function we want to run is the blurring function
and let's say every 30 milliseconds.
OK, this is not 30 seconds.
This is 30 milliseconds, which is very quick.
I'm going to save this.
And if we go and we open up our dev tools here we go to the console, you're going to see it's just
going to go from zero and it's going to increment every 30 milliseconds forever.
It's just going to keep going.
Obviously, we don't want that.
We want it to go from zero to 100.
So what we'll do here actually leave the console log for now.
And let's say if let's say if the load value is greater than 99, then we want to stop that interval.
In the way we do that is with the clear interval function.
So we want to pass in int because that represents this set intervals.
Now if I save that when it gets to 100, it should stop.
OK, so that's what we want now.
Instead of just console logging, obviously we have some stuff in the DOM that we want to work with,
that we want to change.
One is going to be the text.
So let's take the load text and set the inner text value and I'm going to set that to let's use some
template string, template string here.
And we want the load, OK, whatever that is at the time, and then just a percentage sign.
So if I save that, you'll see that this will start counting up to one hundred.
And also the way that I want this to to show is not only count up to one hundred, but it's going to
start fully, fully opaque and then it's going to start to fade out as it loads up.
All right.
So what we'll do is take the load text and set the opacity.
So let's say style dot opacity, oops, dot opacity.
And this is going to be tricky because the opacity value isn't going to be the load value because that
goes from zero to 100.
Opacity goes from zero to one.
Right.
So it's going to start at or actually in our case, we want it to start full, you know, fully opaque.
So one and we want it to go to zero.
So we have to map a range of numbers, basically zero to 100 to going from one to zero in the same amount
of time.
Now, there's actually a stack overflow post that we're going to use here to reference.
And this person asks either in JavaScript or J query to map a range of numbers to another range of numbers,
because that's what we want to do.
We want to map zero to 100 to one to zero for the opacity.
And this is the question here.
But the answer that I want to show you is this one here.
So it's pretty simple.
It takes in a number, it takes in the minimum and the maximum of the number, which in our case is
going to be zero and one hundred.
So the load and then outman is going to be one opacity one, and then, oh, Max is going to be zero,
OK, because we want it to go from solid to disappear.
So I'm going to actually put this link here.
I'm going to put this at the bottom of the file just in case you need to look at it.
And then I'm going to grab this function here called scale and we're going to put this right here.
And then what we can do is when we're setting this opacity, we'll run it through scale and we're going
to pass in the number, which is load.
So that's basically that's the amount of time that we want this stuff.
To happen, so when that goes from zero to 100, we want a map opacity to from one to zero, if we were
starting invisible and going to opaque, then we would do zero one.
But we're doing it the other way around.
Hopefully that makes sense.
So let's go to the page here and I'm going to save this little run.
And now you can see it's going to just slowly fade out as it gets closer to 100.
All right.
So this is actually a really handy little function.
Let's put this let's.
Put this right up here so we know that that goes with that and stack overflow is great for a little
functions like this to do a specific task.
Now we have to do the same thing for the blurr because I don't want the blur to be from 100 pixels.
I want it to be 30, 30 is the max.
So I'll just show you right here.
If I sit in the access, that's the max blur I want to do.
I don't want to set this to, you know, 100 like that.
So we have to map the zero to 100 to 30 to zero because we're going to start blurred.
So we want to start at 30 pixels and bring it down to zero when the load is done.
So let's take the B.G. the background and let's take style.
We want to do style dot filter and we're going to set that to template literal and let's say blurr.
And inside here, inside Blur, we're going to open up our variable syntax, our expression syntax,
and we're going to call scale.
And we want to scale the load just like we did with the opacity.
And it's going to be from zero to 100 for that load.
And then we want the blurr to go from 30 to zero in that same amount of time that that load goes from
zero to 100.
So let's save that.
And, oh, I forgot pixels, so we have to have the NUM, you have to have pics in here, so after this
expression we'll do X and there we go.
So now you can see that the background image is going to go from blur, a blur of 30 pixels down to
zero in the same amount of time that the load goes from zero to 100.
Same thing with the opacity of the number.
All right.
So that's pretty much it.
And of course, you could load in anything you want.
I chose to do just an image and blurred in.
But, you know, you could add other effects with stuff that you add to the HTML that you add to the
DOM, but that's it for this project.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next one.