All right, so in this project, we're going to build a scroll animation, which is is pretty simple.
We can most likely do this all in one video.
However, it's very useful.
You might see these websites where you start scrolling in parts of the site, you know, images or sections
of the website start to come in.
So I just created these content blocks.
And you can see there's three to begin with.
But if I go and I start to scroll down, the next one comes in from the left, go down some more.
Next one comes in from the right and it's going to alternate where it comes in from.
So we're going to use CSFs transitions to have it come in smoothly.
We're going to use JavaScript to basically tell where the trigger point is for the next box to come
in.
And then we're going to add a specific class to show it.
And then if I go back up, it'll remove the class when it hits the trigger point and it'll all, you
know, slide back out.
All right.
So I think it's really useful.
You can use this in a lot of different uses and different websites.
So that's it.
Let's get into it.