OK, so this is a very useful but simple project, so we can probably get this done in one video.
So let's jump into our project starter here.
And for the title, I'm going to just call this scroll animation and we're going to go down here into
the body.
And all we really need is a bunch of boxes which would ultimately contain your website content.
We're going we're not going to waste time creating content.
We're just going to have a bunch of boxes and then apply the animation to them.
I am just going to put an H1 here and say scroll to see the animation and then under that will have
a class of box.
And I'm just going to put an H2 with the word content and we'll just copy this down.
We'll have a bunch of these.
Now, ultimately, like I said, you would have these would be cards or just sections of your website,
whatever it is that you want to bring in with that slide animation.
So let's go into our style sheet here and I'm going to add a background color.
And let's make that hexadecimal e f f e d six to kind of a tannish background and then let's do C display
flex justified direction.
OK, so that's good.
I'm going to get rid of the height and the overflow hidden because we do want a scroll bar.
Obviously this is a scrolling animation.
And then for the H1 when it's just set margin to 10 pixels and then let's create the style for the boxes.
So I'm going to use a background color of steel blue to make the text color white.
And I'm going to display Flex because I just want to align the H2 that's inside to the center, both
horizontally and vertically.
So display flex line items center and justify content center.
And let's set a width of 400 hundred pixels on the box and let's do a height of two hundred pixels.
OK, we want to separate them out.
So let's do a margin of 10 pixels and let's do a border radius.
So what a radius will do 10 pixels and let's add a little box shadow.
Obviously this stuff isn't needed, but I just want to make it look decent.
So don't two pixels and four pixels for the offsets, five pixels for the blur, RGB for the color,
which is going to be zero zero zero zero point three for the alpha value.
And then for the animation, we're going to use the transform property with translate X, because that's
what we want to do, is move these along the X axis.
So initially, let's set box the class of box transform and we want to set the translate.
Why?
I mean, I'm sorry, translate X, which is horizontal.
It's the X axis.
Those of you want my semicolon in here and I'm going to set this to two.
So zero is the default.
If I set it to zero, there's no change.
If I set it to, let's say, 100 pixels and say you can see it gets moved over one hundred pixels gets
moved over to the right.
So what I'm going to do is set this to two hundred percent, which is going to move it way off the screen
to the right.
And then what's going to happen is if we have the class of show, so let's say box with the class of
show, then we're going to set the transform and translate why I translate X to zero, which is the
default.
So if I go over here and I apply a class of show to this first one, it's going to show because it's
in the regular position, the rest of them are still two hundred percent over here.
And then what we'll do is we'll have a transition so that when that class gets added, it transitions
in smoothly from over here.
All right.
So we want to add a transition on the transform property.
We'll do a zero point four second duration with an EZ effect.
OK, now the way it is now, if we add the JavaScript and we add the scroll functionality and they come
in, they're all going to come in from this side.
I actually want every other one to come in from the from different sides.
So what we can do is right here, let's take our box class and let's use anthe of type, which is a
pseudo selector, and we can select all of the even elements, all the even boxes.
OK, so basically, you know, every other one.
And what we'll do is instead of setting the initial, the initial transform translate X to two hundred
percent, we're going to set it to negative two hundred percent, which is going to put OK, put them
over here.
So all the even ones are now over here, all the odd ones are on this side.
OK, and then when we have them come in, when we dynamically add the class of show, they're going
to come in from different sides.
All right.
And we have to also figure out where we when we want them to come in as we scroll.
So that should do it for the success.
Actually, I just want to make the H2 a little bigger.
So let's say box to set the font size to forty five pixels and then we'll jump into our JavaScript and
first thing we want to do is bring in our boxes.
So let's say const boxes and document dot query.
We want query selector all because there's more than one.
So this will put it into an array or a node list, and then we want to fire off an event when we scroll.
So on the window, we're going to add an event listener of scroll.
And when that happens, we'll have a function called checkboxes because we want to check the positioning
of each box and a box could be anything.
It could be any section of your website or an image or whatever.
So we're going to have this function checkboxes and we need to figure out where is the trigger point?
Where do we want when we're scrolling down, where do we want them to start to come in?
So we're going to be using window dot in our height.
In fact, we can just console log.
That so you can see and we're going to run checkboxes to begin with anyways right here, so we'll go
ahead and run that.
And then if I open this up, you'll see Eighty-eight is the window height, not counting the console.
If I move this console up and I reload now that the height is four or six.
So we're getting the inner height and we want the trigger point.
So basically where we want you know, it's a it's a scroll in, we're going to want that to be a little
less than the inner height.
And and we can't just use a fixed number because the height could be, you know, different on at any
at any point.
So what we're going to do is divide this by five and then multiply it by four.
So now we just reload this so you can see the height here is 666.
If I save that now, this gives us this equation here, gives us five thirty two.
All right.
So that's going to be our trigger point.
So I'm actually going to put this into a variable.
We'll call it trigger bottom.
So where in the in the window do we want to trigger?
So we have that now.
Let's go ahead and take our boxes, which we brought in, which is a no list that we can loop through.
And we'll save for each box.
Yeah, for each box.
Let's get the top of the box, and when I say box, you know, I mean this the elements here, so consed
box top, I'm going to set this to the the whatever box we're dealing with because remember, we're
looping through them and we there's this method called get bounding client wrecked.
So I actually have this I want to show you this real quick
just so you understand what this does.
So this method returns with what's called the Dom ract object, and it's just basically a rectangle
described as the size and position of a rectangle.
So it returns that providing information about the size of an element and its position relative to the
viewport.
So where in the viewport is it?
And there's a bunch of properties that we can use on this.
If we go down here, we have the x y width height where it is, where the top of it is, where the right,
where the bottom, where the left of it is.
So we want to see where the top of that particular box is.
So we're going to add here dot top.
OK, so that will give us the top value.
And then all we need to do after that is see if the top of the box is less than the trigger bottom.
If it is, we want to add the class of show.
If it's not, if it's more than we want to remove the class of show.
So let's say if the box top is less than the trigger bottom, then let's take that box and let's add
a class or classless list, add of show or else then we want to remove it.
So box stock class list.
Dot remove show.
OK, so now I'm going to go and just remove this show that we added manually, now notice that it's
only showing the first three because those are in range.
Now, when we start to scroll, it's going to fire off an event.
And the reason we see these come in initially is because of this right here.
If we don't have that, we're not going to see them because it hasn't this hasn't fired off yet.
If I scroll, it does.
I mean, if you want that functionality where it doesn't show it until you scroll, that's fine.
But usually you would show everything above the fold.
So we run that initially first, then we start to scroll.
And as soon as this is true, as soon as the top of the next box is less than the trigger bottom point,
which is a little less than the, you know, the entire height of the viewport, it's going to come
in because it adds that class of show.
And what that class of show does is sets it to its normal position.
Now, if it's even if it's starts over here, so it comes in from that way, if it's not even it starts
over here and comes in from that way.
So every other one comes in from a different direction.
And as we scroll up, it's still going to fire off this event and it's still going to check this.
So if this is not true, it'll remove the class.
So as we scroll up, you'll see that they'll start to go out.
Now, one thing I just noticed is I do have a horizontal scroll bar here and I don't want that.
So in my success, I'll just add on to the body here and I'll say overflow, overflow X, because this
is the X axis scrollbar.
We're going to set that to hidden so that we'll get rid of that horizontal scrollbar.
All right.
So pretty easy.
And I mean, a lot of people use Shakeri for something like this or a library like Animate on scroll.
Animate on scroll is actually a really cool library.
And if you want to do some funky stuff, then you can use that.
But I mean, if it's just something simple and you're just bringing in elements when you scroll down,
this is very lightweight.
You know, no extra libraries or anything and it's really easy to do so.
Hopefully you guys found this useful and I'll see you in the next project.