Hey, guys, in this project, we're going to be creating a split landing page and I did something similar
to this on my YouTube channel a while ago, and we're going to actually format it to be PlayStation
five and Xbox series.
So maybe you have a store and you know, these these are just released.
I can't even get my hands on a PlayStation five right now.
But, you know, we might have a store where you can come and you can choose one of these.
And we're going to create this split screen with a background image, with an overlay, with some content
inside.
And if we click on one side, it's going to stretch out to 75 percent.
The other side, 25 percent.
If I hover on the right side, it's going to do the same thing.
All right.
We'll add a little hover effect onto these.
So I think it's just a nice looking little landing page.
So that's what we building.
It's going to be very CSFs heavy.
We'll do a little bit of JavaScript at the end for the hover effects, but lots of success in this project.
So let's jump in.