OK, so now we want to start to deal with the hover effects we want when we hover on this side on the
left, it's going to spread out.
It's going to the width will be wider.
Same thing if we hover over here.
So I'm going to manually just add on the on the container, the div with the class of container, I'm
going to add hover left and save that just so we can style it and see what we're doing.
So let's say for the class of hover dash left when that one when that's active then we want to take
the left side and we want to increase the width and this is going to be in a custom property or a variable
called hover dash width.
Now at the same time, when when Hover Left is active, the right side is going to be smaller.
So we then want to set that with to a variable called other with.
All right.
And then we'll go up here and we'll set those variables.
When I say variables are custom properties, I mean the same thing.
So dash, dash, hover, dash width is going to be seventy five percent and you can change this ratio
if you want.
So other with is going to be twenty five percent.
Now if I save that hover left is applied to this, to the container.
So the left side is now wider and 75 percent.
The other side is 25, which is what we want now.
At the same time, let's copy these two lines and say if hover right is applied, then we want the right
side to be over with.
And then down here, if hover right is applied, we want the left side to be the other with.
So now if I go when I apply here, I have a right and save.
Now this side is wider.
So that's exactly what we want.
Now I am going to add the JavaScript now so that this gets added dynamically instead of us having to
actually put it in here.
So now it's going to go back to normal.
And if we go into our JavaScript here, let's bring in the left side.
So conse left.
I'm going to use document dot query selector and we want to select the class of left.
Copy that down.
We also want to grab the right side.
So that'll be right.
And then we also want to grab the container because that's where we're adding the classes to and removing
the classes from.
So container and then we'll take the left, we'll add an event listener with ADD event listener and
this time we're listening on a mouse enter event, which is basically a hover.
And then when that happens, we're going to call an arrow function and take the container.
I don't need to put curly braces, since this is just one line in this function.
I'm going to take the container and I'm going to call class list dot add to add a class and I'm going
to add the class of hover dash left.
So I'm just dynamically doing what I just manually did in the in the, in the HTML.
All right.
Now if I save this and I go and I hover over it, you can see that it gets wider and just stays there.
So we need to take care of removing it as well.
So say left out event listener in this time it's going to be mouse leave, right.
So mouse leave and then we want to remove the hover left.
So now you can see that I can go in, gets wider, I move, it gets thinner and we want to do the same
for the right.
So I'm just going to copy that and we will take, let's say this, this and this and this and change
it all to.
Right.
OK, so when we add we mouse enter the right, it's going to add however right.
When we leave it's going to remove Huba.
Right.
So now I can go on either side.
Now it's just flicking back and forth which I don't like.
So we just want to add a smooth transition.
So we just need to take let's take a split.
Right.
I'm going to go right here and say split right, split.
Dasch left.
And let's also grab the pseudo selectors to split up.
Split right.
Kalanchoe and before and split it left.
Colon, colon before and we're just going to add a transition, so transition on all and the speed is
going to be inside of a variable called speed and we'll do an easing out effect.
So let's go up here and apply a speed variable.
That way you can just change it here if you want.
So speed is going to be 1000 times or 1000 milliseconds, which is one second and now.
OK, it looks like the overlay.
Let's see what they mess up down here.
So transition.
So I've split.
A split dash left should be split, Ditlev, so the overlay was working, but the actual left wasn't.
So now you can see that it's working.
So it looks pretty good.
The last thing I want to do is on smaller screens, like under 800.
I want to just make the H1 smaller and the buttons smaller.
So let's add a media query here.
So we'll say media, let's say Max with 800 pixels, then let's take the H1 and let's set the font size
to set it to two ram.
So from forum to two ram and then for the button.
So BTN let's set the width to twelve ram.
I think it was 15 to begin with and we'll also lessen the padding.
So padding will do one point two ram
and let's see.
So these are kind of far away so.
I guess we can move the H1 down a bit, so from the top, I believe it was 20 percent, let's do 30
percent and that will move it down.
All right.
So I think that looks pretty good, even on smaller screens.
So that's when we hit 800 pixels.
So that's going to be it.
And if you guys want to change up the content, obviously, I just thought this was a good idea because
of the time of year.
And, you know, the systems are coming out.
They're really popular.
I, I have yet to find find a PlayStation five myself.
So I just thought it'd be a good idea.
But of course, you can change the content up.
All right.
That's it.
Thanks for watching.
Hopefully you enjoyed this project and I will see you in the next one.