All right, welcome to your next project.
So in this one, we're going to build a simple login form here with a wave effect on the labels.
So if I go ahead and I click in here in the input, you can see the label will then wave up.
OK, so we have that cool little animation when we click in here and when we click out.
So basically the way we're going to do this is wrap a span around each one of these using JavaScript
and add a transition so that the label moves up when we focus on the input.
But we're also going to add a dynamic transition delay.
So it gives it that wave effect so each each letter goes up at a different time.
All right.
So that's what we'll be doing.
Let's go ahead and get into it.