OK, so let's get started on our form input wave project, I have my project start are open here.
It's going to say form input wave and then let's get rid of this, each one.
And we're just going to wrap a container around our form.
So we'll have a container with an H1.
We'll just say please log in basic login form and we'll have a form tag here.
We don't need an action.
And and here we're going to have a form Dasch Control, which will wrap around the input which is going
to be typed text.
I'm also going to add required, which will just give it some basic validation and then the label is
going to go underneath and we don't really need a four.
So we'll get rid of that and say email and then I'm going to go ahead and copy that down.
And this one is going to be password.
So type password and label password underneath that form control.
We're going to have a button and I'm going to give it a class of B10 and let's just say log in and then
we'll have a live with the class of text.
Actually it's to a parallel to a paragraph class of text and say don't have an account and if they don't
have an account then we'll just have a link.
Doesn't have to go anywhere and say register.
All right.
So that's our form.
Pretty simple.
Now, before I get into CSFs, I just want to kind of explain what we're going to be doing as far as,
you know, how to do this.
And we want to use JavaScript to basically wrap each letter in a in a span and we're going to have a
transition on that span to move it up.
So or transform translate y value to move it up with a transition to make it smooth.
And in JavaScript, when we wrap the span around each letter, we're also going to add a transition
delay to each one that increases every letter so that, you know, the first one goes up and then this
the end would be delayed.
Then it would go up a would be even more delayed, then it would go up.
So it gives it that wave effect.
So that's ultimately what we're going to end up with.
In fact, I'll go ahead and just paste in what these labels will look like afterwards.
So basically we'll have, you know, the label tag.
You don't have to put this in.
I'm just showing you as an example, we'll have each letter wrapped in a span with a transition delay
that increments.
So I'm just going to comment that out.
But just so you can see what we're going to end up with.
But before we get into any of that, let's just do some basic styling on this form because it looks
horrible.
So I'm going to use the mollifies so we'll do family equals and Muli and then let's set the set that
on the body and then I'm going to set a background color for the body to steal blue and the color of
the text to white.
That's and then let's style, uh, let's see, we'll do the container and let's add a background color
of our GBA.
I want it to have just kind of a transparent look, so black and then zero point four for the alpha
value and let's add padding.
So padding.
We're going to do twenty pixels, top and bottom, forty left and right.
And let's add a slight border radius of five pixels.
All right.
And then let's do container each one.
So for that I want to text a line to the center.
I also want to add a margin on the bottom of thirty pixels.
OK, and then the link, let's say container A which is just the register link.
I want to text decoration none.
Take away the underline and the color will be let's put the color to light blue.
So now we want to get into the form fields first we have the form control, which wraps around the input
and the labels, so it's a form control and I'm going to position that relative because I want the label
to be positioned absolute within it.
And then for margin, let's do 20 top and bottom zero left and right, 40 bottom.
And I'm going to just settle with of three hundred pixels.
All right.
And then let's do the inputs.
So form control input.
I'm going to set the background color to transparent and then get rid of that border.
But I do want a border on the bottom.
So let's say border
border dash bottom.
And I'm going to set that to two pixels.
Let's do whites and solid.
OK, now I want on its own line.
So instead of inline, we want to display block.
I also want it to go all the way across, all set with to 100 percent.
And we'll add some padding.
Let's do 15 pixels on the top and bottom and the font size for the input I'm going to set to 18 pixels.
And I think we should be good there.
Let's get the color to white.
And then the border here are the outline, I should say, we want to get rid of that also, if I submit
and it's invalid, you get that border as well.
So let's target form control inputs.
And when it's in its focus, also, we want form, control, input, valid, and we're going to just
set the outline on that to zero.
OK, so now we don't have that ugly border.
Now, before we do, I think we're going to do the label stuff in the next video.
But let's finish like the button and the text down here.
So we have a class of actually we put this up, we'll do all the form stuff down at the bottom.
So let's do BTN.
And I'm just going to set the cursor to a point where I'm going to display as an inline block.
For our button here, and I want it to go all the way across, we'll say, with 100 percent and let's
set the background of the button to light blue and let's set the padding.
We'll do padding 15 pixels and let's Refaat family, we're going to inherit.
And then for fun size, let's put that to 16 pixels and the border.
We want to get rid of that.
So border zero.
And I'm going to make the border radius, same as the container, five pixels.
And I think that's all we want to do.
Let's say let's add on let's say BTN focus set that outline.
Actually, we can add that down here.
No, because we're going to add something else there.
Yeah, let's just do outline zero on BTN focus and we can have a little hover effect too.
So I mean, not hover, click effect or hover, whatever you want.
So we're going to do button and when it's active.
So when we click down on it, we're going to add a transform and just scale it down a bit.
So scale it from one two point ninety so we get that little effect.
All right.
Yes, I think what else the text here, we can move that down a little bit, so under the button stuff,
we have a class of text and it's going to set the margin top to 30 pixels, push that down a bit.
Now, the label, don't worry about that.
We're going to we're going to style that next.
And like I said, we need to use JavaScript to turn the label into letters with span's around them with
a transition delay.
We're also going to have a transition, obviously, on the label span.
So we'll get into that in the next video.