OK, so we're going to finish this form up, so I'm going to work on the labels here, so down here
we'll just take form control labels and we want to position those to be absolute
and absolute.
And that's because the the form control itself is relatives or positioning absolute within that.
And we're going to put from the top 15 pixels and from the left zero.
Now, right now, the way it is, if I start to type in here, it's going to just cover the label.
But ultimately the label is going to wave upwards when we click in here.
All right.
Now, before we actually style the span, I want to add it, because right now there is no span.
You know, we don't have this.
It's just label and then the word.
So we're going to use JavaScript to basically turn this into this.
So let's jump into our script, J.S. And first thing we want to do is bring in our labels.
So let's use document dot, query selector all because it doesn't matter how many labels are we want
to get them all so formed dash control label and that will give us a no list of all the labels.
So since it's a no list, we can go ahead and use for each on it.
And we'll say for each label, for each label, I'm going to take the label dot in our HTML and set
it.
Now first, there's a couple of things we want to do.
We want to get the inner text in our text, which is just going to be, you know, each letter.
So e mail in this case for the first one.
And then I'm going to split it into an array.
I'm going to go on to the next line and call DOT split.
And what that does, if we put an empty string in here, is it splits the letters into an array.
So it'll be an array with the first value will be the second will be M and so on.
Now from that I want to manipulate it.
So I'm going to use dot map, which you can use on an array, which now this is to turn it into an array
of something else.
And what we want to turn it into for now is an array of the letters with a spin around it with a transition
delay.
So let's say map and this just takes in an arrow function and we're just going to use tactics here because
we want to just turn it directly into an array of span's that we're going to have here.
But we need to pass in here for each letter.
And then I also want the index, which just starts at zero and increments for every item in the array.
And I want to turn it into, let's say, spane.
And inside here, we want to have whatever the letter is.
So this will turn it into an array of letters with a spin around it.
Now, obviously, we don't want an array.
We want it to be a string so we can use join and just pass in an empty string and that will turn it
back into a string.
OK, so basically we have the inner text, so we're looping through the label, we have the inner text,
e-mail, e-mail for the first one was splitting it into an array which will put each letter on its own
item in the array.
Then we're mapping it to create an array of the letter with a span around it.
Then we're turning it back into a string.
So if I save this now, we don't see any difference here.
But if I open up my elements tab and they click on the label here, you'll see that now they're wrapped
in Span's.
So I'm not going to add the delay, the transition delay just yet.
Let's go back to our success.
And now that we have the span's, we can add stot, we can add styling for it.
So let's see.
Let's do the just the span in general first.
So we'll say form control labels, spane.
And I'm going to display let's do display in line block its in line by default and then I'm going to
increase the font size to eighteen pixels because before this wouldn't have worked because we didn't
have spins around them.
And then let's do a min dash width of five pixels and we're going to add a transition on this because
when it, when we add the transform value actually we'll add that first.
So let's go up here or down here rather and let's say form, control, input, focus.
So focus meaning, you know, when we click.
Inside, we want the direct label span and we also want to do this on the validation, so I'll actually
just copy this down.
And we also want the valid state, so input valid.
And what we'll do is just, first of all, change the color to light blue.
So if I click in here, you can see the label turns light blue.
I also want to turn the the border light blue as well.
So up here where we did the outline on the input, focus and valid, let's do bottom or I'm sorry for
the bottom border bottom and let's set that or border bottom color rather and set that to light blue.
So that way when we click in here, both the border and the text here is light blue.
Now, see, we want to move this up basically when we click in here.
So to do that, we can add a transform and we want to use translate.
Why?
Because we're translating we're dealing with it on the Y access.
So translate why.
And I want to move it up.
So it has to be a negative number.
If I want to move it down, it would be positive.
So let's do negative 30 pixels.
So when I click in here, you can see they move up and they just flicker up.
It's not smooth.
So that's why I'm going to have to transition onto the span right here.
So let's say transition and we'll do zero point three seconds and then we could do like an ease ease
in, ease out.
I'm going to use a cubic busia, so cubic bezier.
And then for the values here, basically what this is, is it defines a cubic bezier, defines a curve
and we can use it as a transition effect with a variable speed from start to end.
And it takes in four points which are p0 p1 p2p three, P zero and P three of a start and the end of
the curve.
So I mean you can get a lot more complicated if you're doing like really cool animations.
But this is pretty simple.
We're just going to do a couple values here.
Zero point six eight negative zero point five five zero point two six five and one point five five.
So we'll have a variable speed on this transition.
So if I click in here, you can see now it doesn't just flick up.
It has that cool, almost like a bounce effect.
Now, we don't want the whole thing to go up at once.
You could do that.
I mean, you could leave it like that if you want.
But I want to have that wave effect.
So that's where the transition delay comes in, because we already have the transition and it's transitioning
the this right here, the transform translate where it moves up.
So in our script here, let's add onto the spane and inline style and we'll set that to say transition,
dash, delay.
Now, when we set this, we don't want to send it to a fixed value because it'll do the same thing.
It'll just wait and it'll flicker them all up at the same time.
So what I'm going to do here is use the index, which starts at zero, then one, two, three and so
on, and I'm going to multiply it by fifty.
So the first one will be zero.
Second one fifty third one will be, you know, 150, then 200, 250 and so on.
So now I'll save that.
And if I click OK, that didn't work.
Oh, we need to add the milliseconds, so after the transition delay, no, we need to have mass.
All right.
And there we go.
And of course, you could change this.
Like we could do 30.
We could do three hundred.
Which is going to be very slow.
So three hundred milliseconds, I think that 50 is good, though he can make it faster, like 10.
But it's you can barely see the wave, so I think 50 is is a good number, so keep it at 50, Ms.
All right, so that's how you can add this cool little effect.
So that's it.
Hopefully guys like this project and we'll move on to the next one.