OK, so in this project, we're going to work a little bit with the HTML5 audio tag and we're going
to create this sound board so we have these different effects.
We just give you a sample.
Hopefully you can hear that, so basically we click a button, it makes a sound effect, and if the
sound is still playing and we click another one, it's going to stop that effect and start the next
one.
So we can do this by using audio tags.
So an additional five, you have the audio tag, you can show controls.
We're not going to do that.
We're going to do everything through JavaScript.
So basically, if you capture an audio element with, you know, get element by idea, whatever, you
have some methods and properties on that object that you bring in, such as play, pause and so on.
So this is the Amdocs.
If you want to take a look at that and see the different methods, what we're doing is pretty simple,
but I think it's a nice addition to the course working with the audio element.
So let's go ahead and get into it.