OK, so we're going to start on our sound board and there's actually not a lot of code for this project,
so we can most likely get this done in one video.
So let's call this sound board.
And in the HTML here, we're going to want to use the HTML5 audio tag.
So let's say audio enter and we need a source and that's going to come from sounds.
Now, I have this folder called Sounds with the with applause mp3 bu MP three, you can get these within
the GitHub repository for this course or the live demo as well.
You can just, you know.
Right.
Click and download the sounds or you can use your own sounds.
So I'm going to point to that folder and then applause.
I'm also going to give it an I.D. with whatever that sound effect is in this case.
Applause All right.
And then we're going to copy this down.
That's one, two, three, four, five, six.
And we want to change these up.
So this one here, I'm going to come and select the next applause and change both of those to bu.
OK, then we'll grab this one here in this, let's change this one to gasp
and then this one here.
I'm going to change those.
Ta ta da.
And then let's grab this one and this one is going to be victory.
And then this last one here is going to be wrong.
OK, so make sure you change the I.D. and the actual name of the file.
And then the last thing we need is just a container for our buttons.
I'm going to have an I.D. of buttons.
Now, if I save this, we're not going to see anything because the buttons are going to be generated
from the JavaScript based on each sound.
So I'm actually going to jump into the script J.S. and create an array here called SOUNDS.
So it's going to be just a bunch of strings with the, you know, applause boo
gasp Todai victory
and wrong.
All right.
So it has all of our sound effects.
And then what we'll do is loop through these.
So let's say sounds for each for each sound.
I'm going to run a function and I'm going to create a button.
So we'll create a variable and set it to document create element.
We want to create a button and then I want to give that a class.
So we'll take that button variable and classless add.
We want to add the class of B10 for styling and then the inner text set the inner text to the sound
itself.
OK, so it'll have these up here will be the inner text of the button.
Right.
And then we want to have an eventless and actually you know what, let's just insert these first in
style them.
So we'll just say document and then get element by D we're going to get the buttons container and we're
going to append child and passing the button.
All right.
So as soon as I do that we can now see our buttons.
So let's jump into our stylesheet.
This is going to be pretty simple.
We're going to use the Poppins font, so let's change or boto here and here to Poppins and then let's
change the weight to 200, 400 and the body.
I'm going to give a background color of RGV one six one one hundred two to three.
And let's do so.
We have display flex and basically the buttons are going to be placed.
Well yeah, we'll set the flex wrap here so that they go on to the next line.
All right, and then the flex direction, we can get rid of that, we want it to be a row, a line item
center and justify content.
Let's also text a line to the center.
And I think that should do it for the body.
Now for the buttons.
Remember, those have a class of buttons.
So we're going to set the background color of that to Rebecca Purple.
All right.
Let's set the border radius to five pixels.
Let's set the border to none.
Set the color to white.
We'll break them apart.
Margin will do one room.
And let's set the padding to one point five REM top and bottom and then three REM left and right.
I'm going to increase the font size to one point two REM and let's for the font family we want to inherit
and that should do it.
All right.
So we have our buttons down.
They don't do anything yet actually.
Let's get rid of the outline.
So button focus set the outline to none and then let's let's also add a cursor or a cursor pointer and
let's do a hover to so say, button hover and I'm just going to set opacity to zero point nine.
OK, now back in our JavaScript here, where we loop through each button, we want to add an event listener
onto each one.
So right under where we set the entire text, let's take the button and let's add an event listener
and we want to listen for a click.
And when we click, we want to run a function.
And then I'm going to basically take the audio.
So we want to select let's do document dot get element by D.
Now, remember, all of these audio tags have an I.D. of whatever the sound effect is, which is they're
all in the disarray we're looping through.
So the idea is that we want to find is going to be that particular sound.
Now with HTML five we have a JavaScript API for four audio elements and one of the functions or methods
in that API is play well.
So we want to say dot play.
And you can only do this obviously if it's a if it's an audio element, which these are.
So that will actually play.
It's I'm going to save this.
I'm going to go over.
Hopefully you guys can hear this will turn this up a little.
So if I click applause, you can hear it.
Now, one thing I want to show you is if I click multiple buttons, it's going to just play them over
each other, so.
OK, so they do play over each other and that may be fine, but I want to make it so when we if if something's
playing and we click another button, then it's going to stop the one that's playing or all of them
that are playing before that and then play that one.
So let's go right above where we actually play it.
And let's run a function called We'll say stop songs.
All right.
And then we'll go down here, make sure you're outside of the four each and create a function called
Stop Songs.
And we're going to take our sounds array and foreach through them and say for each sound, create a
variable called song.
And this is going to be, you know, this right here.
So we're going to select the element bidi.
We want that particular sound and we'll take that sound or that song just because we called it song
here.
And again, we're talking about an audio element.
So we we were able to do a play on it.
We can also do dot pause, OK, and there is there actually isn't a dot stop, which you would think.
So what we do is we pause and we set the current time because audio tags have a property of current
time and we just reset it to zero.
OK, so that's how we can stop a song now if I save this.
OK, so now you can see that when I click one, if something's playing, it stops the one that's playing.
All right.
So just this gives you a little glimpse into the HTML5 audio API and you can do a lot of cool things
in my my JavaScript 20 projects.
Course we have, you know, an audio player that plays different songs.
You can pause and play and stop and all that and show the time.
So there's a lot of things you can do with it in terms of creating a little music players and stuff.
But this is kind of an introductory project, so I hope you guys enjoyed this.
Let's move on to the next project.