OK, so in this project, we're going to be building dad joke application where it gives us a joke.
So I had a clock yesterday.
It was so time consuming.
They're just silly little jokes and we can click a button to get a new joke and we can keep getting
new jokes.
And we're we're getting this from is actually a third party API that I can has dad joke dotcom.
And if you go to that you URL slash API, you can see basically the documentation for this API and we're
going to use the fetch API that's built into the browser to make a request and get an object with an
I.D., a joke and a status.
And we're going to take that joke and we're going to put it into our application here.
All right.
So I'm going to actually have a section in this project where I strictly go over HTTP request and response,
how that works, as well as how the API works.
And then, you know, after we build out the interface with H2O and access, we'll add our JavaScript.
I'm going to show you how we can use fetch normally and how we can also use it with something called
a sink away.
Because when you deal with that, you deal with something called promises, which we'll get into as
well.
All right.
So let's get started.