So like I said, in this project, we're going to get into working with the API, making an HTTP request
to a third party API that gives us dad jokes.
But before we get into any of that, I just want to create the the HTML access, which isn't going to
be too much.
So we can probably get all that done in this video.
So let's go ahead and change the title here to Dad jokes.
And there's not going to be much here.
We're going to have a container that wraps in H3 and in this H3 will say, don't laugh challenge and
let's have a div here with an idea of joke and then I'm going to give it a class of joke for styling.
So basically, this is where the joke is going to go.
I'll just put a you know what?
We'll just do this joke goes here and that's going to be replaced once, you know, once we make the
request and we're able to put the joke into the DOM and then we want a button to get another joke.
So let's create a button here and let's give this an idea of joke BTN and then we'll give this a class
of BTN for styling and say, get another joke.
OK, so save that doesn't look too good.
So we're going to jump into our stylesheet here.
And let's see, let's give the body of background color.
So background color is going to be six eight six d e zero.
That's going to be our background is a blue.
And let's see, we want to leave all this stuff center center.
Good.
And then our container that wraps around everything to set that background color.
To white, white, OK, we'll go ahead and save that, some of the things we want to add to this container
is a border radius so we can give it some rounded corners.
Let's do 10 pixels and I'm going to add box shadow.
I'm going to add two shadows, which I'm actually just going to paste in here.
Ah, yeah.
Two shadows.
We have the first one here.
So zero 10 pixel for the offsets, 20 pixel blur color and this one here.
So if we save that, you can see we have rounded corners and we have a bit of a shadow.
Now we need some padding to take all the content away from the edges there.
So let's do 50 on the top and bottom 20 on the left and right, and then let's align everything text
aligned to the center and let's set a max with two one hundred percent and I'm going to set the width
to 800 pixels.
And let's actually add a little bit of padding on the body just so we have some space on the side on
these small screens.
So I'll say padding 20 pixels.
All right.
Now for the content in the container, let's do the H3.
So H3, I'm going to set the margin to zero.
And I'm also going to give it an opacity of zero point five just to kind of give it that transparent
look.
And I want to set letter spacing to two pixels.
OK, now for the joke of the class of joke.
Watch right now.
Just says JoCo joke goes here, but this will be the joke that we fetch from the API.
So I'm going to set this font size to be 30 pixels and let's set the letter spacing.
I'm going to set that to one pixel and I'm going to set the line height to 40 pixels and margin is going
to be 50 on the top and bottom.
And we'll say auto on the left and right.
So gives us plenty of room and give it a max width of six hundred pixels.
OK, so that's the joke.
Now the last thing we have is the button.
So that has a class of BTN and I'm going to give that a background color, same background color, and
that's going to be hexadecimal number which is going to be nine f six eight eight zero.
So purple color and border will be zero.
And let's set the border radius on the button to 10 pixels.
OK, let's make the color whites shall move that up there.
And let's give this a box shadow as well, which I'm going to just copy.
OK, there we go now we obviously need some padding there and change the font size, so it's that for
the padding will do 14 top and bottom, 40 left and right.
And let's up the font size, say, 16 pixels.
OK, that looks pretty good.
Let's make sure the cursor is a pointer and that should do it.
So now we have our button.
We want to get rid of that outline.
So let's say BTN when it's in its focus state, we want the outline to be zero so we don't have that
ugly outline.
And when it's active, when we click it, we'll just make it scaled down a little bit.
So let's say class button when it's active, meaning when we click and hold, we want to add a transform
effect and we're going to use scale and let's scale it from one to point nine eight.
So it'll just go down a little bit like that.
OK, so that's good enough for the styling.
In the next video, we're going to get into the Fetch API.
I'm going to talk a little bit about how that works.
I know a lot of you guys already know this, but just for those that don't, it's important to understand
at least the very basics about how Fetch works and how HTTP requests work.