All right, so this is the first project where we're actually dealing with working with a third party
API using fetch to make an HTTP request.
So I'm just going to go over a little bit of this before we get into the next video and write our JavaScript.
So the API we're working with an API is just application programming interface.
We're working with something called the Jason API.
It serves Jason data, which is essentially like a like a JavaScript object.
It looks like this.
So Curly braces.
Jason does use double quotes on the keys and the values.
But you can see this is just an object with an I.D., a joke and a status.
So if we make an requests, I get requests to this particular you URL.
We should get something like this.
Now, there's a few different formats.
The default is going to be HTML and we don't want that.
We want applications, JSON.
So to get that, we actually have to send a header because when you send HGP request, you can send
headers and we want to send a header of accept equal to applications, Jason.
And there's there's many, many different ways to make requests.
We're going to be using fetch within our application.
You could even use Kerl, which is a terminal program.
So I'll just show you real quick.
Let me open up a new terminal here.
And if I pace that end, so basically I'm just using Carl to make a get request to this Eurail and I'm
adding the header accept application JSON, and if I do, that is I'll get that object with an ID,
a joke and a status.
And each call I make is going to be a different joke because they're random jokes, OK, with a different
ID.
So another really nice tool to work with APIs is postman.
And you guys don't have to download this or anything.
I just want to show you that I can make the same request.
So I'm going to make that request to I want to get rid of that to this you URL.
And if I do that without adding the except header value, I'm going to get HTML back.
This is HTML, so I want Jason back.
So I'm going to add in headers for a key I'll except and for a value it's going to be application JSON
and if I send that then I get Jason back.
So I just get this simple object just like you saw when I used Kerl.
And as far as these methods get, just means you're getting data or getting something from the server
post you typically use when you're submitting data.
So if you're submitting like a contact form or maybe you have an admin screen where you're we are adding
a new blog post or something that would be a post request put is used for updating data that's on the
server.
Same with Patch.
And then delete is to delete data on the server and then these these down here you don't really have
to worry about.
Those are rarely used, at least for, you know, the stuff that I do.
So that's Posman and you can download it if you want.
I think it's get Posman dot com if you want to mess around with it.
But what we want to do is make that request from our application.
And the way we can do that is with using the API.
So the API provides a JavaScript interface for accessing and manipulating parts of the pipeline, such
as requests and responses.
And there's an example right here and it doesn't have to be a third party API like we're using.
It could be your own back end.
So you could build an API with, like Express, no Jasin Express or Python, Django or Laravel or whatever
it might be.
Or you can actually get just standard Jason files with Fach.
It doesn't have to be some, you know, some complicated API.
Now when you call fetch to neutral, it returns a promise because it fetches the data asynchronously.
So you have this dot then when when it finishes and the API is a little weird because you have to then
the first one you get the response and then you say, well, I want the Jason data.
So this is just an arrow function that we pass in and we're saying response dot Jason.
And then we have another dot then because this returns a promise as well, and that gives us the actual
data.
So in this case, we would be logging the data that's in this movie's Jason file.
So this is a get request by default.
If he wanted to make like a post or request, you would you would pass in the URL just as we did above.
But then you'd have this extra options, value our object and you'd pass in the method that you want.
So in this case, it's a post request.
And if you are submitting form data, you would pass that in the body.
Like if you had a registration form with the name email password, that stuff would all go in the body.
OK, and I'm not going to get too deep into this because what we're doing is pretty simple.
So we're going to make a get request to get our joke, put it in our interface or in our, you know,
in our application.
I'm also going to show you afterwards how we can use a different syntax than this dot then.
So there's something called a sink, a await, which makes it a little cleaner, at least in my opinion.
And I think it's it seems to be, you know, the more popular thing to do when using promises is to
use a sink away rather than DOT then because this can get quite messy.
So we'll look into that as well.
So hopefully that makes sense.
If it doesn't, don't worry about it.
We're going to be doing a few projects with, you know, dealing with APIs, dealing with fetch.
And there's also a library called Axios, which I actually prefer over fetch, but fetch is built into
the browser.
You don't have to add a CDN or install it or anything like that.
All right.
So in the next video, we'll go ahead and make our request to our API using fetch and put it into the
application here.
Get a joke.
We'll also have this button, make another request to get another joke.