OK, so now that I give you just a very brief overview of HTP request and response and the Fetch API,
we're going to go ahead and finish up our application here.
So I have my script, J.S. And first thing I want to do is bring in what I need from the Don.
So we have our joke.
I'm going to call this joke Al for joke element and set this to document doGet Element by D and that
should have an idea of joke.
Let's just make sure.
So we're getting this div right here that wraps this text.
So we're bringing that into our JavaScript.
We also want the button.
So let's say Korn's joke B10 equals document yet element by D and I think I used to joke B10 right here.
So we're getting the button as well because we need an event listener on that.
All right.
So right when we come into this application, we want to call a function called generate joke, so that's
going to get called.
So we want to create that.
So let's say function generate joke and this is where we want to make our request.
Now, like I said, this is built into the browser.
It's it's a native API.
So we don't have to include any kind of CDN or anything.
And what we want to do is make a feature request to a specific URL, which is going to be Seydou.
We still have this browser window open.
Yeah, so it's going to be to this I can has Dad Yocum, just like it tells us down here, to make a
request to.
So let's paste that in there.
Now, remember, if we just make a get request to this without the except header of applications, Jason,
it's going to give us HTML.
And that's not what we want.
So we can add in an object here with a headers value and headers is going to be an object.
And then we can put in for the key what what the header we want.
Remember when we were in Postman, they caused us and also we in Postman I set a header of except as
the key and application Jason is the value.
So we're doing the same thing here.
We're saying except as the key and setting application slash Jason as the value.
OK, now usually what I like to do if I'm adding headers is are not even just headers but anything in
this object.
I'll just take this and put it in a variable.
So I'm going to cut this and I'll put it in a variable called config.
And right above it, I'll just say const config equals that object.
I just think it's it's cleaner.
But you can you know, of course you can do what I just had here.
Now remember, this is going to give us a promise back.
So we have to set this to dot then and remember what the fetch API we get the response.
You can call us whatever you want.
Response.
I usually call it Redds and this is an arrow function and we just want to call Resource Jason to get
the adjacent data and then the second dot then is going to give us the actual data.
OK, so this is another arrow function and for now I'm just going to cancel log what data gives us and
I'm going to save this.
So this should run right away.
So I'm going to open up my console.
And what we get is an object with an I.D., a joke and a status, just like you saw with Kerl, just
like you saw with Postman.
It's all the same API.
We're just hitting it with different methods, different technologies, you know, postman Kerl fetch
whatever.
So what do we actually want to do with this.
We want to take the joke from this object and inserted here.
So in this arrow function right here instead of console logging, let's open up a code block and let's
take the joke element that we brought in above and set the inner HTML.
Let's set that to not not just data because data is the entire object.
We want DataDot joke because we're accessing this dot joke from this entire object.
All right.
So let's go ahead and save that.
And as soon as the page reloads, we see a joke here.
And I mean, this isn't going to work yet because we haven't hooked it up.
But we get my pet mouse.
Elvis died last night.
He was caught in a trap.
And if I reload, the page will get a different one, because remember, every time you hit this API,
it's going to give you a different joke.
I used to work for a soft drink can crusher.
It was so depressing cause this is so stupid.
But yeah.
So now we're getting this joke in here.
The next thing I want to do is just hook and eventless knob to this button so that it calls generate
joke again.
So let's go up here and just say a joke button and we'll add an event listener onto it and we want to
listen for a click.
And when that happens, we want to call generate joke.
And as soon as I save that, we get a different joke because whenever we save, it's going to call this
function.
But also, if I click this button, it'll give us a new joke.
All right.
And you can check your network tab as well to see any requests that you get.
I'm just going to dislocate this for a second.
And if I just reload this, this is going to show you any files that were loaded, like our stylesheet,
our script.
Yes, but if we look at so if we look at type, you see this fits right here.
This it made a call to this.
You, Aykan, has dad joke dotcom.
And we can see a few things.
We see our response, which is the, you know, the ID, the joke and the status.
We can also check out the headers.
So it was this is the request, the URL that was made.
It was a get request.
So that's the method.
The status code was 200.
What else?
The remote address and then any headers down here.
So there's response headers and there's also request headers.
And in the request header, we should have this except application, Jason, because we sent that that
was a result of what we sent within the options.
And then there's a bunch of other stuff here as well.
So whenever you need to see, you know, data that you get back, when you make any kind of request,
you can check it out in the network tab.
So let's just attach to reattach this.
So that's pretty much it.
Our application is very small and simple, but it works and we are making a request to a third party
API.
Now, the next thing I want to show you is how to use a sink away, because personally, I don't like
this then syntax.
I think it looks kind of messy and we can make it look like it's synchronous when it's really asynchronous
because we have to use this because this could happen, you know, while something else is happening.
So the DOT then basically says when this is finished, then do something.
So I'm going to actually comment.
I'm going to copy this and comment this out because I want to just do it again with a sink away.
Now, here, where we make our request, I'm going to get rid of just everything here and the dot then.
And what we can do is set for this fetch right here.
I'll set a variable called Rez Response, whatever you want to call it, and set it equal to the fetch.
Now, remember, fetch is a sink, so we have to wait until it's done fetching.
So we use the await keyword.
Now, whenever you use a wait inside of a function, you have to label that function async.
OK, that's why it's called the sink away the function, you label a sink and then any promises that
you want to put into a variable, you're going to put this away before it.
Now, this is going to give us just like we have down here, it gives us the response.
But we need to call this resident, Jason.
So what we would do in this case, using the fetch API, we could set another variable called data and
we could set that to rest JSON.
However, this also returns a promise.
So we have to wait on that and then the data will be in that variable.
So again, we'll just go down here and I'm just going to copy this line and I'm going to set that joke
element in our HTML to data and then the joke value.
All right.
So I'm going to save that.
And you can see it works the same exact way.
I think that this looks better and cleaner because instead of the dot thens, we're just basically setting
what we get back from fetch into a regular variable and then whatever we get back from resident Jason
into a variable and then we can just continue on.
We don't have to have this inside of a dot then.
And it's all preference.
Like I said, a sink away is very, very popular.
You're probably going to see it more than not, at least in modern code.
So definitely something to to understand.
I mean, you don't have to use it.
If you prefer using DOT, then that's fine.
I'm just going to put a comment here and say we'll say using DOT then here we'll say using.
A weight.
OK, so both of them do the same exact thing.
I'll keep both of them here for reference.
All right, so that's it.
Pretty simple project.
And we'll use this.
This is kind of a foundation for any other projects that we use when we're making HTP requests.
Like I said, there's a library called Axios, which is is what I prefer to use because it's it's easier
to use.
You don't have to do the two promised thing, the resident, Jason.
Also, there's other things that you can do that are beyond the scope of projects in this course that
I prefer.
So we'll probably have a project using Axios later on, but that's it.
Let's go ahead and get into the next one.