So in this project, we're going to build a little application that shows you the key code and the code
for any key on your keyboard.
So if I come to the page here, it says Press any key to get the key code, I'm going to hit Al and
it'll show me the actual key, which is L the key code, which is 76 and the code, which is key L if
I hit A by one, we get 49 digit one.
If I hit tab, we get tab nine is the key code.
So I mean this is going to be really simple, but it can be useful if you need to get the code for something.
I just want to show you if I search for JavaScript key codes, the first result here is, is the application
that this is based off of.
If I hit a key, gives me the code key code also gives you the the which property which is deprecated.
And I also want to mention that key code.
So this one right here is actually deprecated.
So if we look at the Murdochs, you'll see that this is deprecated and it's recommended to use DOT code,
which we're also showing.
And it says, you know, this property is useful when you want to handle keys based on their physical
positions on an input device rather than the characters associated with those keys common in games and
stuff like that.
All right.
So, I mean, this key code does still work.
If it doesn't, you know, if you're watching this in the future, then you can just simply get rid
of this box and just display the code.
But we're going to go ahead and get started.
So let's get into it.