OK, so let's get started with the HTML and success.
So basically what we're going to do first is just create the three boxes.
We're just going to put it directly in the HTML later on.
That'll be replaced with JavaScript, because when we come to the page, we only want to see that one
box.
And then as soon as we hit a key, we'll see the three with the three values, the key, the key code
and the code.
So let's start here by just changing the title here to say, you know, just say event codes and then
we're going to have a wrapper div here with the idea of inserts.
And in here we're going to have some classes, some divs with the class of QI, which is basically just
the box, the border, the background color and so on.
So this will be let's just say it's the a key that we hit.
This will be dynamic later on.
We'll add this with the JavaScript.
But for now, I'm just going to hard code the letter A and have a small tag here.
And we'll just give this a label of event key, because that's what it is on the event object, it's
going to be the key value.
And then under that, d'Hiv will have another class of key.
And this is going to be the key code, which for A is 65.
So I'm just going to hard code that in there.
And let's say this is the event dot key code and then we'll have another class of key.
And this is going to be the code, which in this case would be Keet.
And inside small tags here will say event dot code and then we'll have one final div with the class
of key.
And this is just going to be like the welcome box.
It'll say press any key to get the key code and code will just say to get the key code.
All right.
So that should be it for the HTML.
Pretty simple.
Let's jump into the stylesheet and the styling is not going to be too bad either.
I just want to use a different font.
So I'm going to say success.
Questionmark family and let's put that to Ammu Ally and set that on the body here and move.
I change the font also on the body.
I'm going to add a background color of one three times and let's set we can get rid of the Flex Direction
column.
And I just want to add a text aligned center here.
So text align center and then all we really need to style is the key class and then the small tags inside.
So for key, let's give this a border so the border will be one pixel solid and it'll be hexadecimal
999.
And then I'm going to give it a slightly lighter background color of Tripoli.
And then let's add a box shadow, just a very slight shadow.
I'm going to do one one pixel for both the horizontal and vertical offset and three pixels for the blur
and then for the color of RGB, a black zero zero zero for red, green, blue and zero point one for
alpha.
So just a very slight shadow on the right and bottom.
So let's set I'm going to set the display actually to an inline flex.
OK, so they're going to be side by side and then let's set a line items to center and let's set the
font size to be bigger.
I'm going to set that to twenty pixels and lots of the padding of this of each one to twenty pixels.
And let's set the I'm actually going to set the flex direction to column and then let's set the margin
will break apart a little bit.
So let's do ten pixels margin
and let's see what else do we want to do here.
Let's set the font weight to Bould.
So I'll go right here and say font weights set that to bold.
What else do we want to do here is that the correct font doesn't look like it?
No, it's not.
So right here we should have an ampersand.
There we go.
And then let's set Menwith here for each box as well to 150.
All right, so now we'll do the small tags, actually, one more thing I want to do is position this
relative because the small tags inside of the key class are going to be positioned absolute.
So when you position something absolute and access, if you want to position it inside this container,
then you would make that position relative.
So let's take the key class and small tags inside of it and let's position that absolute.
As soon as I do that, it's going to, you know, it's going to get put here, but I actually want to
move it up here.
So let's set the top value to a negative.
So negative.
Twenty five, twenty four pixels because I want to bring it out of that box and I'll put the left value
to zero.
But I do want it in the middle.
So I'm going to set text a line to center and also set the width to 100 percent.
That, that'll put it in the middle let's add or let's change the color to five, five, five.
And I want it smaller.
So let's set the font size to 14 pixels dots and I think we should be good.
Yeah.
So that looks OK.
So in the next video, we want to give this some functionality where we don't even show these three
boxes until we actually hit a key.
And then obviously whatever key we hit, this data in here is going to be different.