OK, so now we want to add the Java scripts for this project, and before we do anything, I just want
to add the event listener and show you how we get these actual properties like Qiqi code and code.
So let's let's take the window, which is the top level object in the browser, and we're going to add
an event listener on to that.
And the event we want to listen for is a key down, which is a keyboard event.
And we pass in a function as a second second argument here.
And then in this function, we can pass an event object.
And then I just want to console log that event, object to show you what it gives us.
So one of my console just reload here.
And if I hit the letter A or the A, you're going to see I get a bunch of properties.
And what I want to show you is, for one, the keek are I'm sorry, the code which is Keet.
So that value we want to get put in here and then we also have to go down here a little more.
We have the actual key which is a that's going to go in there and then we should also have the key code
or are the code.
No code is Keet, whereas the key code
here it is right underneath.
So key code is 65.
Now, if I hit another key like Q that's going to give me another oops, I going to go up here and hit
it.
So here you can see I get the key of Q The code is key.
Q And the key code is 81.
So we want that stuff to be put in these boxes, which is going to be pretty easy.
And then actually one more thing I want to show you.
If I hit space, the actual key is the code is space, but the actual key is just an empty string.
So I just want to do a simple check to see if the key is equal to an empty string.
If it is, then we'll go ahead and just put the word space in there, because I don't want it to just
be blank.
So what we'll do is, first of all, bring in insert so document get element by D and we want to bring
in the idea of insert and let's get rid of that and we're going to take insert and say in our HTML because
that's how we can insert HTML and make sure you use back tactics here so that this is we can put dynamic
values in here.
Now I'm going to copy from indexed HTML the three divs with the class of key, not the last one with
just the text, but these three here.
I'm going to cut them, not copy them, because we don't want those in there initially and save and
now you're only going to see this one box.
So in this, in our HTML value, in this template literal, I'm going to paste the sin but I want to
change these.
These are basically just hardcoded a right here.
I want to change that to the key which we can get from E key.
Now remember, this is going to be just an empty string if it's space.
So what I'll do is just do a quick check will say if a key is equal to just an empty string, then let's
put out space or else let's put out whatever the key is.
So it's key.
And this is just a ternary it's just a shorthand conditional.
Whatever you're testing goes here, which in our case, testing to see if he equals an empty string.
This is basically, you know, then so if this then puts put out space or else so this represents else,
then just whatever the key is.
OK, and then down here we have our key code.
So let's say and this syntax is just, you know, a template literal of money sign and curly braces.
As long as you're in back ticks and not quotes, then you can use the syntax.
So we want to take the object or the event object and let's say dot key code.
OK, now there's a line through it and VTS code because it is deprecated, but it will still show up.
It will still work.
If you're watching this in the future and it doesn't work, then you can just get rid of this block
if you want and just show the code.
So for this last one here, let's say e dot code actually since we put a vent here, let's just change
because this can be absolutely anything you want.
We'll change this to events.
And that way, I don't know, just because we used event there doesn't really matter.
But so event key.
And when you see other people's code, you might see you might see event, you might see Eevee, that's
also pretty common.
So now I'm going to save this.
And if I go over here and I hit enter, you can see that the key I hit is enter.
The key code is 13 and the code is enter by hit a we're going to get a 65 K if I hit three three fifty
one digit three.
OK, so it's working.
If we had space we're going to see space here because of this check we did hear.
Otherwise it would just be an empty string.
So it would just be empty and we don't want that.
OK, there's a backwards capsular shift so any key you hit, it's going to give you the key code and
the code.
All right.
So I know this is a really simple project, but it's nice to just get going.
And it can also be useful if you need the code for something, if you're building a game or whatever
it might be.
All right.
So thanks for watching and I'll see you in the next project.