All right, so Dribble Dotcom is actually a great place to get inspiration for projects.
This is a dribble by effort by James called Fake Hugh.
And you can see it's basically just these cards that you can expand that have questions and answers.
So this is what we're going to create based off that dribble.
And we're going to use quite a bit of success because we're going to use font.
Awesome.
But we're not going to just put these these common icons right in the HTML.
We're going to use UCSC using the specific Unicode for these fonts, for these icons, and then we're
going to position them and then we'll add the JavaScript so that we can close and open each of these
tabs to see the answer.
OK, so the CSFs will probably take up most of our time and then the JavaScript is pretty easy.
We just need to toggle the act of class basically on the parent node.
So that's it.
Let's go ahead and get into it.