OK, so we're going to get started on our FAA cue project, so I just have my project starter, but
I also have a link to the font awesome CD.
And so you can, you know, grab this from the repository or from font, awesome dot com or from CBSNews.com.
And then for the title here, let's say F a Q and then in the body we're going to have an H1 and say
frequently asked questions and write under the one we're going to have a container.
Let's call this fake new dash container.
And inside here we're going to have our fake new device.
And whichever ones are showing the answer, we'll have a class of active.
OK, so I'm only going to put active on the first one for now.
And you can have more than one active at the same time.
It's not like they're the expanding, you know, the expanding tabs that we did or expanding cards,
whatever.
So in here in the queue, we're going to have a title.
So each three dot F.A.A. Q Dash title, let's say, why shouldn't we trust atoms?
And then we're going to have a paragraph of the class of fake Q Dasch text.
And this will basically be the answer.
We'll say they make up everything.
So these are just like stupid little jokes.
Of course you can change it to whatever you like.
Then we want our button.
Now we're going to have either a Chevron, either Chevron down button.
If it's retracted and if it's expanded, we'll have an X button or times button.
So let's do an eye tag here.
So fast font.
Awesome.
Efate dash, Chevron dash down.
And under that we're going to have an FAA dash times, which is an X.
OK, so if I save this, it's going to look like that.
Now we're going to have three more of these or four total.
So I'm just going to paste these in.
I'm going to go still within the container, but right under the first fake hair and paste these in
and save.
And I can see we just have actually we have five total.
OK, so I mean you can grab these if you don't want to just copy them from here, you can grab them
from the final repository.
All right.
But basically they're just an F a Q with a title text and the two buttons.
So now it's jumping to the stylesheet.
And as far as the font goes, I'm going to use the Mully font.
So I'm going to say success, questionmark family and set that equal to Muli.
And then let's in the body set that font
and we could do this like display flex to center and all that.
But I'm going to just center it directly on the container.
So I'm just going to add a background color here of F zero three times, which is like gray.
And then for the H1, let's set a margin will do 50 pixels, top zero and then 30 pixels.
And I want to text line that to the center and then let's center the container.
So remember, we have a Q dash container
and for that let's set a max width of 600 pixels and to keep it in the middle, because right now can
see it stuck to the edge.
You want to keep it in the middle.
So we'll set a margin zero for top and bottom and auto on the left and right, which is going to keep
it in the middle of that six hundred pixels.
All right.
So for each F a Q, we want to add some styles.
So let's add a background color of transparent.
Basically, the active one is going to have a white background, but the ones that are active are going
to be transparent.
And let's set the border to one pixel solid.
And for the color, we're going to use nine F A for a eight, gives it a border.
Also going to add a border radius of ten pixels, make the corners a little rounded margin.
Let's do twenty pixels on the top and bottom there on the left and right.
That will separate them out then for padding.
Oops.
For padding.
Let's do thirty pixels all the way around and I'm going to position this relative so that we can position
stuff absolute within the Q and let's add an overflow of hidden so that nothing comes out of the container.
Also we want to.
Transition when we open and close or expand and collapse, so let's add a transition and just to zero
point three seconds each.
So basically anything that's that that can transition will in this amount of time.
Now for the FAA cue that's active, let's say FAA cue.
If it has a class of active, then I want to set a background color of white and the first one is active.
So it's background color of why.
I also want to give it a background icon or actually to background icons positioned in a certain way.
Now we know how to put font awesome icons in directly in the HTML with specific classes we can also
insert them with.
So if you've never done this before, if we go to font awesome dotcom and we search for an icon, I
won't comment.
And let's check out this right, and actually this this one right here comment, so if you notice,
it gives you the class so we can directly insert it in the H2O.
We also get this Unicode value of F zero seven five.
Every icon has a different value.
So we can actually use this to insert an icon using success.
So I want to have actually two of these common icons as a background here on active.
Well, one thing I did forget is the box shadow, which I'm just going to paste in.
So it's just two shadows with zero on the horizontal offset, three on the vertical, six blur, and
then this is the color and then a second shadow.
So just so it looks like it's coming off the page a little bit.
But back to the to the icons where I'm going to add the CSFs for this is on the before and after pseudo
selector for fake active.
So if I had to say colon colon before I can pass in a content value here and I can put anything I want,
like.
Hello.
So before this fake U active you can see it's inserting Halo.
I can also use after.
So I'm going to also say f a Q active after and now you can see Halo after it.
Now instead of using text here for content, we're going to put in that Unicode character.
Now when you use font awesome like this and you put in the Unicode, you want to use backslash and then
whatever the code is, which in our case is F zero seven five.
Now, if I just save that, we're just going to see this square because we need to include the font
family for font.
Awesome.
Which is actually going to be font space.
Awesome space five space free.
And now if I save that, you can see that I've inserted those two icons.
Now we obviously want to style this.
Let's go ahead and add a color here of hexadecimal to E, C, C, seven one.
OK, gives it that green color.
Let's set the font size and let's put that to seven REM units, which makes it much bigger.
So it's basically seven times whatever the root HTML element font size is, which initially is sixteen
pixels.
So in addition to that we want to position oops, what the heck is that.
We want to position absolute
and let's set.
I don't want them to be so dark.
So let's set the opacity here to we'll do zero point two.
That's going to make them much lighter and for the position let's say from the top will do twenty pixels.
Remember this is for both before and after.
So what we're doing now is positioning, positioning them both in the same place, but then we'll grab
one of them and move it a little bit.
So top twenty pixels left twenty pixels.
And if I save that it looks like there's only one, but they're actually both just in the same exact
position.
And I want to set a Z index of zero so that we make sure that it's behind everything else.
Now like I said, they're both in the same position.
So what I'll do is take the one that's before.
So I'm just going to grab this class for this selector and I'm going to change the color of it to let's
do three, four, nine, eight DB.
So give it a blue color and then let's set the position top.
So remember, it's already positioned to absolute right here.
So we don't have to add that here, but we want to change these coordinates.
So from the top, let's say negative ten pixels.
So it's going to move it up negative ten pixels from, you know, from the initial zero and then left.
Let's do negative thirty pixels.
So now I'll save that and you can see that that's been moved.
Another thing that I want to do is rotate it, because right now the little point is over here off the
screen.
I want to basically turn it around so we can use transform translate for that.
So let's say transform and not translate.
I'm sorry, rotate, because we want to rotate this on the Y axis.
So it's going to be rotate y and let's rotate it halfway.
So 180 degrees.
And now if I save, you can see that this blue one has been rotated.
Now we could have just as well used the comments icon this one.
Right.
Air, which looks very similar, and we could have just just done before and added it, but this makes
it a little more interesting using using, you know, multiple icons and just positioning them differently
so you could do whatever you want as a background here or in anything that you create.
So now what I want to do is the title and the text here.
So let's go down here and say a dash title or F a Q sorry for the title.
All I want to do is add margin, say zero top 35
35 right.
Zero bottom zero left.
And for the text say fake you dash text for this.
We're going to I'm just going to add a margin here of thirty pixels zero zero.
But I don't want this to show unless it's unless it has the active class.
So let's initially set this to display none.
And now we can't see any of the text, any of the answers.
However, if it's active, so fake, active and f a Q dash text, then we want to display as a block.
So now we can only see the answer for the one that is active.
OK, if I were to add active on another one like this one here, if I add that class of active that's
going to give it all those properties and it's going to show the question I'm sorry, the answer as
well.
Now I'm going to stop here and in the next video, we're going to handle these buttons because we only
want the X to show if it's active.
We only want the Chevron to show if it's not, we also need to style them and then we'll add a little
bit of JavaScript to be able to click and expand each F you.