All right, so now we want to style these buttons, these icon buttons, position them.
We want to give functionality to them so we can expand and contract these fake cues.
So we have a class of fake cue dash toggle on the button.
And obviously, we don't want to show the Chevron if it's expanded and we don't want to show the X if
it's if it's not expanded.
So we're going to have to deal with that.
But let's just do some basic stuff here first.
Like the background color I'm going to set to transparent and take away the border set.
That's zero.
And let's set the cursor to appointer.
Let's set I'm actually going to display Flex here and then align and justify to the center so a line
items center and justify content center and then let's increase the font size.
So we'll increase that, say, 16 pixels and then we're going to set padding to zero.
Let's set the position to be absolutes.
And then as far as where we want to put these, the initial toggle is going to be top 30 pixels, 30
pixels from the top is going to be on the right.
So let's do 30 pixels from the right.
And then the height will be 30 pixels and the width will be 30 pixels.
So if I save that.
Now, you can see these buttons over here as far as this first one.
I forgot to put the class on that, so that's reclass FNQ Dasch, Tawakkol.
All right, so I'm going to set the X right here, the Times to display none so far.
You dash toggle, which is the button, and then not done.
This should be dash so fake you dash toggle and then the class of F.A.A. dash times, which is the X
icon, I'm going to set that to display none.
So now we only see the Chevron.
Now if it's active, we do want to see the times.
So let's just copy this.
And here we're going to say let's put active in front.
So F a Q fake, Q dot active and then times and then let's display block.
So now you can see that this is the X is showing on the active.
Now we want to remove the Chevron if it's active.
So let's take this and let's set Hefe active so toggle and then we want Chevron dash down and we want
to display none there.
So now we only see the Chevron if it's not active.
We see the if it is.
Another thing I want to do is get rid of the C this outline here.
So that's going to be on F.A.A. Q Dash toggle, which is the button we want to say in its focus state.
We want the outlined property to be set to zero.
OK, that'll get rid of that.
Also on the active toggle, let's grab this here.
So on the act of Torgau, I'm going to set a background color
of hexadecimal value, nine F a.
Four A.
So you can see the ex has that that background, I want that to be rounded or circular.
So I'm going to add on the FAA toggle a border radius of 50 percent.
And then I also want to make the text.
Are the icon white?
If it's if it's the times.
So right here, let's say color white.
All right.
So now we want to make this function.
But what I'd like you to do is pause the video and try this yourself.
If you don't need any hints at all, then go ahead and pause it now and try it if you want some hints.
I'm going to just paste this in for a second.
So you want to bring in your toggle buttons.
Remember, they have a class of fake you dash toggle and you want to use query selector all because
it's more than one.
So that will create a node list.
You want to loop through that no list using for each and then on each toggle you want to add an event
listener, a click event listener because we're clicking on them.
And then you want to toggle the active class on the parent node.
You don't want to add the active class to this to toggle.
You want to add it on the parent, which is this div here, OK, and you can use dot parent node to
access that and then to toggle a specific class, you can do class list toggle and passata.
And so this should give you enough information to to really know how to do this.
So if you want to pause it and go ahead and try it, do that and then come back.
So I'm going to bring in my toggles.
So I'll set toggles to document DOT and we want to use query selector all and they have a class of F
a Q dash toggle and then I'm going to take that node list and I'm going to loop through with four each.
So say for each toggle.
I want to take that specific toggle and add an event listener onto it.
I want to listen for a click event.
And when that happens, I'm going to run a function and take the toggle, which is the button, and
I want to access the parent nodes so we can say dot parent node and I want to access the class list
and then call the not remove.
We want to call the toggle method and we want to toggle the act of class and that's it.
So very, very simple.
If we go over here and I click on that, it's going to take away the active class.
If I click it again, it's going to put it back so I can toggle that this and I can open the mall if
I want.
It doesn't have to be, you know, one by one or whatever can open as many as we want.
OK, and that's it.
And this is something that back when I was learning how to do this stuff, you would use Jacoway for
most likely because JavaScript just wasn't where it is today.
Query selector all didn't even exist.
It was just it was it was a lot of extra code just to do something simple.
So I mean, if you're learning JavaScript now, it's, it's much better than it was back in the day
when you had to use Jacoway for the smallest little just activity in the DOM.
But that's it.
Hopefully guys enjoyed this.
I will see you in the next project.