So this is a cool little project for picking random choices now we have this text area, and as soon
as I start to type, like I'll say choice one and you'll see it'll format down here is like a tag.
And to create another choice, I just need to put a comma and start to type again, say choice to another
comma.
Choice three, choice four.
Obviously I can do as many as I want and then as soon as I hit enter, it's going to give us this cool
little effect and it's going to stop on a random choice.
It's also going to clear the text area.
All right.
So if you just need if you need some little helper to help you make a choice between however many items,
however many objects, I mean, you could do numbers here.
And it's just going to stop on a random one.
OK, so that's what will be creating let's go ahead and get started.