All right, let's get started on a random choice pick, so I have my project starter here, I'm going
to go ahead and just change the title here to Random Choice Picker.
And let's go down here.
So we're going to have a container.
We can get rid of the H1.
Let's put a class of container here and inside the container will have an H3 and let's say enter all
of.
Enter all of the choices divided by a comma.
Go ahead and just specify what a comma is, Floren and then let's do a line break here and then we'll
say, press enter when you are done.
All right.
So under the H three, let's put a text area.
And this is going to have an I.D., we'll call text area real creative and let's have we don't need
this stuff here because we're going to style of a success and then we don't need a name.
I do want a placeholder, though.
So it's a placeholder.
And we'll go ahead and set that to enter choices here.
Dot, dot, dot.
Now, under the text area, we're going to have an area for the tags, so we'll give this an idea of
tags and the these are going to be span's with the class of tag and obviously with some text of the
different choices.
But this is going to get inserted with the JavaScript.
However, for now, I'm just going to hardcoded just so we can see it in style it.
So we'll just create a tag here.
It's a choice one.
We'll just add three of these civil two to three and save.
OK, so that should do it for the HTML is jump into our success and let's so font family will just keep
our bottle.
That's violence at a background color.
Background color is going to be hexadecimal value to be eight eight F zero, which is a blue color,
and we have display Flex and Flex Direction columns center.
So all this is fine.
So now the H3, let's give that a color of white on that blue background.
And let's also just add a little bit of margin.
We'll do 10 pixels, zero, 20 pixels for the margin.
You know, let's change the font to Molly.
So success questionmark family equals Molly and let's right here in the body and change this.
There we go, so that's a little bit more readable and then for the container.
Also, the a whiff of the container to 500 pixels and actually that should do it, so have 500 pixel
container,
let's do the text area.
So that has a class of text area and I want to get rid of the border.
So say border none.
And let's make this a block level element.
So display block and we're going to set the width to 100 percent of its container.
Which is not working, and that's because I gave it an idea of text area, so we'll just sort of style
the text area.
So just take away that dot.
There's no class.
The height of this is going to be 100 hundred pixels.
And let's inherit the family of Molly and then let's add some padding, do 10 pixels padding.
And as far as margin goes, we'll do zero zero 20 pixels, and then let's make the font size a little
bigger, 16 pixels.
And then that should be good for the text area.
Now for the tags.
So we have span's with the class of tag and we're going to add a background color.
So background color is going to be F zero nine three to be it's going to be the background and the color
of the text is going to be white and we're going to add a border radius of three pixels and I'm sorry,
not three pixels, 50 pixels.
And patting will do 10 top and bottom, 20 left and right.
And let's spread them out a bit so we'll add margin to zero, top five, 10 and zero and the font size,
I'm going to make 14 pixels.
Make that a little smaller.
Let's display as in line block.
And yes, that should do it now when it selects, you know, when it selects something at random, it's
going to have a background color.
So we'll have in addition to tag, it will have a class of highlight.
And I just want to change the background color to hexadecimal value, 273, C 75.
And just to see what that looks like at, say, the second one here, we add highlights and the highlighted
one will look like that.
OK, so that's it for the user interface here.
So in the next video, we'll go ahead and we'll start to add our JavaScript.