All right, so in this video, we want to create our tags, we want to be able to type in here and split
by a comma and create tags below.
So one thing I want to do in this case, though, is on the H3, I'm just going to add a text, a line
of center.
And just to center that, I think that looks a little better.
And then in our script file, we want to get the tags element, which is this right here, this div
with the idea of tags.
So let's call this tags Al and set that document get element by D and we want the idea of tags.
And then I also want the text area.
So we have an I.D. of text area and let's call this text area and those are the only two things you
want to bring in.
So then I want to automatically focus on the text area.
So we're going to call the focus method, which if we go to the page, it'll automatically put the cursor
in there and we can start typing.
Now we want an event listener on the text area.
So add event listener and we want to listen for a key up.
So you've key down and key up.
We're listening when when you press down and then you let go, that's going to fire this off.
And when that happens, it's passed in our event parameter here.
When that happens, we're going to call a function called create tags and we want to pass in each target
dot value, which is going to be whatever we type in.
So if we create a function called create tags, say input and we console log the input we got down here
and we open up our console and I start to type, you should see what we type down here.
All right.
Now, the way we're going to do this is we want to take whatever, whatever we type in.
And then we put a comma.
We want to split at that comma and create an array of, you know, whatever is on either side of these
comments.
So this would create an array with this as the first value.
This is the second we can do that using split.
So let's say const tags and let's set that to input, which is a string.
We want to split it by the comma and turn it into an array.
So now if a console log here tags and I go and I say, let's just put a one in here, oops.
What happens?
Split is not a function.
So split I put a one.
You can see we have an array with one value of one, which is a string.
If I put a two it's going to just be an array with a 12.
But if I put a comma and then a two, then we have of an array with two values, one and two.
So it's going to split it by the comma.
Now, I don't want to be able to have space like that.
So what we'll do is add on to this dot filter and filter is also a high order array method that allows
you to return certain things based on a conditional.
So we'll say for each tag, let's say tag, dot, trem, which will just trim off any white space,
if that is not equal to an empty string, then will return that.
And then we just want a map which will just manipulate the array.
So for each tag we want to return an array with the tag, but we want to trim.
So we're just saying it can't be an empty string.
Also, we're going to trim any white space.
Now, if I save that and I do one space, you can see that it's not actually added the spaces.
And in there I can put comma to space and the space is not added in there.
And if I just do like comma and then another comma, it doesn't add another, it doesn't do anything
because of our filter.
All right.
So now that we've established that, let's get these tags put into our HTML, so we'll get rid of that
and let's take the tags element and clear it.
Otherwise they're just going to pile up.
So before we do anything, we'll just clear that and then we'll take our tags, which is an array.
And we want to loop through loops with for each.
For each.
So for each tag, let's create a tag element with document dot create element.
And we want to create a span.
We also want to add a class to that.
So let's take the tag element and let's classless dot add.
Class of tag, and then we want to set the entire text of that, so we'll take the tag element and set
the entire text to whatever the tag is, because we're looping through it here.
We get each one and we're going to put that as the inner text.
And then finally, we want to take the tags element.
So make sure you have the S here.
This is the the idea of, you know, the div with the idea of tags and we want to append child and we're
going to add each of those tag elements in.
So if I go ahead and I do.
Hello.
So it starts to type down.
There is a tag, if I do a comma and I put in a world, that's going to be the second tag.
So it's going to separate it by the commas.
All right.
So we have the ability to create these tags.
What we want to do next is have the ability to hit, enter and then have it randomly select.
And it's going to highlight and it'll give that cool little animation as well.
So we'll do that in the next video.