OK, so we're able to create our tags here with commas.
Now we want the random select functionality.
So in our event listener, let's check to see if we hit enter.
So we'll say if and then on this event object, we have a key property and we're going to say if the
key is equal to enter.
All right.
Now, if we hit enter, we're going to call a function called Random Select, which we haven't created
yet.
I also want to clear the input.
So we're actually just going to wait a couple milliseconds before we do that.
So in the set, time will pass in an arrow function and we just want to wait 10 milliseconds and then
clear the input value with e dot target dot value, and we're just going to set that to nothing.
All right.
So let's create random select down here, function, random, select, and for now we'll just console
log one, two, three.
And if I open up my console and you know, I can type stuff down here and then enter, then you see
it fires off that function.
And it also clears this up here now in the random select, we're going to go ahead and set a value of
times and I'm going to set that to 30.
And what this represents is the number of times it's going to highlight each one before it stops.
So, you know, the one, two, three, four, and it'll go to thirty or whatever you put this to.
And then we're going to have we're going to have to set an interval, because this is going to repeat
this highlight of each one, the highlight and the remove of highlight of each one.
So let's create a variable called interval and we want to use the set interval function.
So for the for the time here, we want this to happen, let's say, every 100 milliseconds.
And what we want to happen is we want to pick a random tag.
So let's say conse random tag and set that to a function called pick random tag.
And before we move on, we'll create that so it's a function pick random tag and we want to take all
the tags so we can use document, dot, query, selector, all, and we want to get all the elements
of the class of tag, which would be all these, all of these, all the spans.
And then to get a random one, let's return.
And we're going to return tags, so tags when we use query selector all, it's a node list that we bring
in.
So all of these will be put into the node list, which is similar to an array with an index.
So the index is going to be random and we'll use math dot floor to round down math dot random, which
will give us a random decimal.
We just want to multiply that by the length of the tags array or not array, but no lists, which is
similar to an array.
So that'll give us a random tag.
I'm also going to create two more functions down here just to highlight and highlight.
So we'll call this highlight tag and it's going to take in a specific tag element and then we're going
to take that tag element and we're going to just add a out of class with classless dot ad and we're
going to add the highlight class and then we want one to remove the highlights.
So we'll call this on highlight tag and we're just going to remove instead of add.
Base.
Now back up to here, so we have this intervale, it's going to fire off every 100 milliseconds, it's
going to pick a random tag, and then we want to highlight that random tag.
So highlight tag pass in our random tag and then we want to highlight.
So I'm going to have a set time out here, which is going to take in a function and we're just going
to wait 100 milliseconds here to highlight.
OK, so in here we'll say on highlight tag and want to pass in our random tags.
So with this, if I were to create my tags and then hit enter, you can see what's happening every 100
milliseconds.
It's highlight's picking a random tag to start at and then it's highlighting a random tag and then 100
milliseconds after it's on highlighting.
So that's just going to keep going forever right now.
All right.
I'm just going to reload to stop that.
And now what we can do is go under.
So function, we still want to be within our random select, but we want to go down here and I'm going
to have a set time out with a function and I want this to run after whatever the Times is.
I want to multiply that by 100 milliseconds.
So the 30 here, multiply that by whatever the time this is, which is 100 milliseconds.
OK, we could even put that we could put that in a separate variable if we wanted to, but anyway,
we want to clear our individual.
So you have an interval that runs.
There's a function called clear interval to stop it.
So we want to pass in our interval.
Then we want to pick a random tag to stop on.
So let's create let's do a set time.
And this is going to be 100 milliseconds and inside the set time out, I want to get a random tag.
So once again, we'll create a random tag and set that to pick random tag and then we want to highlight
it.
So it's a highlight tag and pass in our random tag.
OK, so this up here is is causing that, you know, shifting it to each one, highlighting and highlighting
after a certain amount of time.
And then this takes care of stopping it and just picking a random tag to land on and highlight.
Hopefully that makes sense.
So let's do one, two, three, four, five.
These can be numbers or strings or whatever you want to put in here.
Let's do up to ten and then I'm going to hit enter.
So it should run 30 times and then it's going to stop on a random tag or in this case number.
But of course it can be anything.
And let's try that again.
Same thing which we did one through ten and hit enter.
So it landed on three last time.
Now it lands on one.
All right, so you have choice, one choice to choice, three, enter, and it's just a cool little
application to pick a random choice.
All right, so that's it.