OK, welcome to your next project.
So this one, this is a pretty simple project, at least in terms of the JavaScript, it's only like
five lines or so.
Basically, we just need to add an event listener to this icon right here.
And once we click it, we're going to we're going to toggle an act of class.
And it's active right now.
But when I click it, you'll see what happens is a couple of things, really.
This container here, the nav shrinks, the links start to rotate, and then they ultimately disappear,
setting the opacity to zero.
And then the ex does a rotation and then turns into two lines.
OK, so it's a pretty cool effect.
And you could use this on any website or application.
We're going to be doing mostly CSFs here.
As you can see, we have quite a few transitions that are going to come into play when we toggle the
active class, which is what we're doing when we click this.
All right.
So let's go ahead and get into it.