All right, guys, we're going to get started on our animated navigation project, so I just have my
BOLER boilerplate here, a project starter, and I just included the dribble link to the graphic in
case you're interested.
I also wanted to give them credit.
So we'll start off here with the title Animated Navigation and the time I was going to be pretty simple.
So we want to get rid of that and have a NAV tag that's going to wrap everything.
Now, the way that this animation is going to work is when we click this.
This is in the state of active.
So basically we'll have a class of active on the NAV when we click that in the JavaScript, it's going
to remove that class and we have a bunch of transitions to give that effect.
OK, we have this stretching, we have this go disappears the opacity.
Also, you can see the links are rotating as well.
And the X the lines turn are the X turns into lines.
So we're going to add a bunch of transitions for those.
But this nav tag is going to start with a class of active because we want it to be open when it starts.
And we'll give this an idea of NAV as well to grab on to it in the JavaScript.
So and here let's add our fuel and then our ally with an attack that just goes nowhere, stay home and
then we'll have four links.
This next one will be works.
And then we'll do abouts and then we'll do contact, OK, underneath the U.S., we're going to have
a button.
So this button is going to have a class of icon and give it an idea of toggle.
OK, so this this button is this right here, the ax.
But inside here, you see that we have two lines, right?
So we want these two lines.
So we're going to do a class of line and we want two of these.
So we'll add that now we need a way to differentiate these because they're going to be rotating differently
in the transition.
So let's call this one, line one and this one, line two.
And that should be it for the TML, so this is what it's going to look like, very ugly.
So let's jump into our styling and we're going to use a different font here.
We just want success and then replace this with Muli Molly Mieuli.
I don't know how to pronounce it.
And then we'll add that here.
OK, now for the background we're going to use we're going to put a solid color here, but then under
it we'll do a linear gradient.
And I'm putting both just in case linear gradient isn't isn't supported.
So this will be hexadecimal and it'll be a F bsf.
OK, so like a very light blue and then we'll have a background image.
And for this we're going to use a linear gradient and we'll do the direction will be to bottom and then
we'll use this color here.
So I'm going to paste in that color.
We want that at zero percent and then we'll put a comma here.
We'll have more paste in that color again, and we want it to go to 50.
So from zero percent to 50 percent will have that color.
And then we want it that we want this color, this blue, which is five five two nine zero F nine.
And we want that to be from 50 percent to 100 percent.
So let's just grab this.
And right here, we want this to go to 100 percent.
If I save that, we get that split color.
Look, now, let's see, what else do we have here?
Do we want display flaks?
We don't need Collum display column and get rid of that.
We can also get rid of the overflow hidden items over for hidden.
And I'm just going to add margin zero.
I probably should have put that in the boilerplate.
So that's it for the body.
Now let's start on the nav here, so let's take the NAV tag and let's add a background, a lot of background
color of white, OK?
And I'm just going to add 20 pixels padding all the way around.
And the width of this is going to be 80 percent.
But that's in I'm sorry, 80 pixels.
But that's in the non-active state.
So basically this when it's active, it's going to be 350 pixels and it's active to begin with.
OK, we have the class active here.
So let's just jump down here real quick and say if it has the active class on it, then let's set the
width to 350 pixels like that.
All right.
And then I just want to center everything here so the NAV will go ahead and display flex.
We want to line items to the center and we want to justify content to the center.
And let's actually add a border radius of three pixels.
And we're also going to have a box shadow.
So for the X offset, we'll do zero, the Y will do two pixels, the ball will do five pixels and the
color will be a black with a zero point three transparency.
So it just looks like it's slightly coming off the page.
Now, when we remove the active class, I just manually get rid of this.
Here you can see it goes shrinks down.
Now, I want to add a transition on that.
I don't want to just flick right to, you know, smaller or bigger.
I want to have a nice, smooth transition.
So let's add a transition.
So this will take whatever property we want to add the transition to, which in this case is the with
the duration I want it to last, which is point six seconds and the effect which is linear, it's going
to be the same speed throughout.
All right.
So now let's start to do the the you know, the unordered list.
So Sanabel and for this, I'm going to display Flex, which makes it a flex container, makes all the
list items, flex items that will turn into a row.
We want to get rid of any bullets.
So less style type, we're going to set that to none.
And then let's go ahead and just remove any default margin and padding.
Oops.
OK, and then what else do we want to do here, so the with the with for this the initial with is going
to be zero.
And the reason for that is when when it's not active, we want the width of it to be zero.
All right.
Now we want to add a transition for the width here, too.
So it's a transition on the width and it's going to be zero point six seconds linear.
Now, when it's active, let's say when the NAV tag has a class of active, which it does now, we want
the width of the U.S. to be 100 percent.
OK, sorry, I'm going to put you out here.
OK, so have the with that 100 percent and then I think that's all we want there.
So let's do the list items.
So we have our NAV.
You will list items and remember, we want we want them to have that rotate effect.
So what we'll do is we'll use transform and we can use rotates on the Y axis and start here with zero
degrees.
And I'm going to change that for the act, for the active state.
We'll go ahead and add that.
And by default, the opacity is going to be zero, which is going to make it just disappear.
And that's fine because we only want it to show when it has the active state.
And then I want to add a transform of sorry, a transition for the transform property, for the rotate,
because we wanted to have that smooth rotation.
You can see the the allies have that rotate.
And also for the opacity, you can see how they fade in and out, nice and smooth.
So what we'll do is add transition on transform
and let's do zero point six seconds linear and then also added onto the opacity property, which will
be zero point six seconds duration and linear.
All right, and then let's see, so when it's active, we should see it.
So let's say now NAV active and we want to target the ally when the NAV is active and set the opacity
to one so we can see it.
And then we also want to set the transform to rotate.
Why?
And we're going to do 360 degrees.
We just want to do a full 360 spin.
You can see when I save it actually shows us the transition or the rotation, I should say.
All right.
Now the links don't look too good, so let's make those look a little better.
So we'll see now VLA and we want to position these to be relative and the color of the lengths I'm going
to set to black and I'm going to get rid of any underlying subtext decoration.
What is this text decoration?
We want that to be none.
And then I'm just going to separate them with a margin on the right and left of ten pixels looks much
better.
All right.
So I think what we'll do is stop here.
And then in the next video, we'll go ahead and style the icon or the button.
The button with the class of icon.
Put the lines in there and we're going to add the rotation, transform for that, and then we'll add
the JavaScript with the event listener.
All right.
So we'll get to that next.