All right, in the last video, we went ahead and created most of the styling, we have our background
gradient, we have our little nav bar here.
And now we want to do the icon, which is a button with the class of icon.
So let's go ahead and do that or add an icon and we're going to set the background color to whites,
which is the same as it's as it's a container there.
And then we want to get rid of that border as well.
So we'll set that border at zero.
So now we essentially can't see anything and then we're going to set the cursor to a pointer so that
when we hover over it, we get that cursor.
We want to set any padding to zero.
We're going to position this relative because the lines inside are going to be positioned absolute and
we're going to set the height and the width both to 30 pixels.
All right.
We can't see anything just yet.
One thing that I want to get rid of is this outline on the focus state.
So we'll say icon Cole and focus, and we want to set the outline to zero.
OK, now we want to style the lines.
Remember this to Divs inside the button with the class of line.
So we want to style that.
So let's say icon line and we'll set the background color and we'll set that to hexadecimal five to
nine zero F nine.
And we want to set the height.
So the gist is going to be two lines or set two pixels to the height.
So we have two two pixel lines.
Now we want to position this to be absolute.
And actually it's put our width as well.
So the width is going to be 20 pixels and we position absolute.
Now, we want to move this from, let's say, from the top 10 pixels and from the left five pixels.
So this is the top line.
Now, both of them are in the same exact spot right now because they both have the line, the class
of line, which we just put in the same position.
So what we're going to do is right underneath, let's say, icon, and then we want to take line two
and we want to move it down so we can actually use auto for the top and from the let's say from the
bottom 10 pixels.
OK, so now we have two separate lines now up here, see what else do we want?
And we want to add a transition, actual weight.
What do the transition after?
Let's do the rotate.
So remember, when we click it, when it goes from an X to the two lines, we want them to rotate.
So we're going to go down here and they need to rotate in different directions.
So we want to say NAV and when it's active, we want to take icon and we want line one first.
So let's take line one and let's add a transform so that we can rotate.
And the degrees is we're going to do a negative seven sixty five degree rotation.
And we also need to add translate y for the positioning and that's going to be 5.5 pixels.
All right.
And then what I'll do is just copy this whole thing.
And this is going to be for line two and this is going to be positive, seven, six, five degrees.
And then this will be negative because we want them to go in a different way.
So save that and now we have an X now when they when it changes, we need to have a transition.
So let's go back up to here to the line class and let's add a transition.
We want to put it on the transform property.
Everything is zero point six seconds.
Of course, you can change that if you like linear and you can see when I save and that's applied,
you can see the rotation.
So the last thing we have to do now is the JavaScript, which is very, very it's only, I think like
five, five, six lines.
Basically, we just need an event listener on this button so that when we click at the active class
is toggled.
So let's go to our script and let's say const toggle and set that to document it.
And we're going to use get element by D to pull in the idea of toggle, which is the button.
Right.
So we have this idea of toggle, so we're grabbing that.
We also want to grab the nav by this side.
So let's say const nav document gets element by D and we want the NAV back and then what we're going
to do is take the toggle and we're going to add an event listener on to it because we want to listen
for a click.
So pass and click.
And then we have a function which you can write out like this, or you can use an arrow function, which
is what I prefer, so we can get rid of that and then just add an arrow, OK?
And then we're going to take the nav and we're simply going to toggle the active class, meaning that
if it's applied, it'll remove it.
If it's not applied, it will add it.
So let's take a class list and class list.
You can do add if you want to add a class, you can do remove to remove one or you can do toggle, which
is what we want and we want to toggle the active class.
All right.
Now, with arrow functions, if we only have one single line like this in the function body, we don't
even need these curly braces.
We can just do that.
I mean, you don't have to, but I don't know.
So it's shorter.
It's cleaner.
So let's try this out.
I'm going to go over here and I'm going to click this.
And there we go.
So all the transitions are applied, including the rotation of of the icon, the rotation of the rotation
and the capacity of the links.
You can see they spin and they fade in and out the width of the the container here.
So all these transitions are applied when that class is added and removed.
All right.
So that's pretty much a pretty simple project.
You could integrate this into your website or your app, your mobile app, whatever it is that that
you want to use it with.
But that's it.
Thanks for watching and I'll see you in the next project.