All right, so in this project, we're going to create an increment counter and I'm sure you've seen
this on websites somewhere.
Basically, we have these numbers.
I'm just using Twitter, YouTube, Facebook fans.
But this could be any number.
And when we come to the site, initially, you can see that it counts from zero up and we can set the
whatever the increment is, we can set that to whatever we'd like to make it faster or slower.
So we're going to first just create created style it we're going to make it responsive.
So when it's on a small screen, you know, it goes vertical and then we'll add the JavaScript to make
it increment like this.
All right.
So let's get started.