All right, let's get started on our increment counter so I have my project.
I also have a link to font.
Awesome, because we will be adding the social media icons, which, of course, is optional and let's
say increment counter.
And in the body here, we're going to have three divs at the class of counter dash container.
OK, so in this kind of container, we're going to have the icon.
So let's do an eye tag now.
When you use social media icons with font, awesome, it's fab class instead of fax and then F.A.A.
dash and this one is going to be Twitter.
And I'm going to make it a little bigger with font.
Awesome.
You can also add the class of a dash.
Let's do three x, so three times the normal size and then we're going to have a class of counter and
this is where the number is going to go.
However, right now I'm just going to hardcoded, but it's ultimately going to come from a an attribute,
a data attribute that we're going to call data target and we're going to set that to twelve twelve thousand
instead of two, whatever you want.
And then we're going to have a span with just the text that this is the Twitter followers, OK?
And we're going to have two more of these and you can have as many counters as you want.
So the second one here is going to be YouTube.
And this lets say this will be 5000.
And the date of Target 5000 and let's change Twitter followers to YouTube
subscribers and then this one down here, let's make this Facebook and then four followers or fans,
whatever will do.
Seventy five hundred and seventy five hundred will change this text here to Facebook fans.
All right.
So that's what it's going to look like now.
Let's go ahead and style this stuff.
So the font I want to use is Raboteau mono.
So up here, I would say success question mark and then let's change.
We'll get rid of this.
So the family is going to be Rebadow plus mono like that, and then we'll change the font family here
to Raboteau mono.
OK, is it kind of that typewriter look and then let's add a background color here.
So background color is going to be a purplish color.
So h e for for add it will make the text white.
And then let's see if Filloux Direction column, I'm going to get rid of that, I actually want it to
be I want it to look like this, except on you know, when it's on small screens, it'll go this way.
So we'll just add a media query at the end.
So let's set a line item.
That's good.
All right.
So the counter container counter dash container, I'm going to display flex.
And this I want to display as a column.
Remember, the counter container is each one of these which we're making a flex box and we don't want
to go this way.
We want them to be stacked on top of each other.
So let's set the flex direction there to column and let's justify content center and let's add a margin.
So just to add some spacing, we'll do 30 pixels, top and bottom, 50 left and right.
And then let's see for the counter, class or counter, I'm going to set the font size.
This is the you know, the text that's going to increment.
I'm going to set that to 60 pixels are going to make that quite big.
And then let's add a margin, top of ten pixels.
And it's also a line in the in the container here.
Count a container.
Let's do a text, a line of text dash line to the center.
Good.
Now, when it's on small screens like this, I want it to go the other way.
So let's create a media query here by saying at media and a max width of, let's say five eighty.
So meaning anything under five eighty pixels, then I want the body flex direction to be a column instead
of a row.
All right.
So there we go.
Now, we don't need to have these these hard coded numbers in here.
We can get rid of these because that's going to be input by the JavaScript.
So in the next video, we'll jump into our script JS and we'll continue with that.