OK, so now we're going to make this function by having it count up to whatever this data target is
and we want to put it in here.
So basically the entire text of counter.
So we have multiple counters.
That means that we need to bring it in with query selector all.
So let's say CONSED counters, set that to document Dods query selector all all the classes of counter
and that's going to give us a node list which is similar to an array.
So we want to then loop through that with a for each, for each takes in a function.
So we'll say for each counter then let's first of all take the counter so that that specific element
and let's set the entire text to zero and I'm going to set it to a string of zero.
So now it's going to just show zero in, you know, inside of the div right here.
So that's in our text.
Will either you can either put something in there like we are now or you can get something from it with
inter text.
So I'm going to have a function in here called update counter and this is going to be an arrow function
and then we want to get the target.
So let's say const target, which is in the data target attributes so we can take the counter and we
can call doGet get attribute and the attribute we want to get is going to be data Dasch target.
Now this is going to be a string.
In fact, I'll go ahead and console log and I'm going to use the type of operator and show you what
data type target is.
Also the value of target.
If I go down here and I open up my console, actually nothing's going to show because we haven't called
this.
We want to call it so outside of update counter call update counter.
And it's going to just call it once and we're going to see the type, which is a string.
And then whatever the data target is now the changes to a number, which is what I want to do, because
we're going to want to do some math on it.
We could either wrap it in a number constructor or we could use pass int or we can just add a plus sign.
So if we save that now, you can see down here that turns it into a number.
So let's get rid of this and let's create another variable called C, and this is going to be whatever
is in the inner text.
We set it to zero here, but now we want to get it.
So let's say counter dot, enter text and we want that to be a number as well.
So I'm just going to add a plus sign here and then we're going to create the increment.
So we need to decide how how much do we want to increment this by?
And depending on that number, that'll depend on how fast or slow it is.
So we want the target.
Let's take the target and let's divide by.
And this could be anything you want.
If we divide it by if we just use target, it's just going to it's going to increment by itself.
So twelve 5000 and it'll just basically just flick right on the screen.
We want it to count upwards.
So I'm going to divide it by two hundred.
And you can experiment with this if you want.
Now I'm going to console log increment here.
So the first one remember that is twelve hundred and that divided by 200 will be sixty five thousand
by two hundred twenty five.
Seventy five hundred three seventy three thirty seven point five.
So let's go ahead and add an if statement here.
We want to make sure that that c no, we want to make sure that that is less than the target because
we don't want to go past the target.
So if it is, then let's take the counter and let's set the entire text and I'm going to set that to
a set of tactics.
And we want to take that C and we want to add whatever that increment is.
OK, but I also want to round this up.
So let's let's do math.
Dot, seal.
So math dot seal is going to round this number up, OK?
Now if I save that, you can see we get sixty 25, 38, which we just saw in the console, it was thirty
seven point five, but we're rounding it up now.
We want this not to just stop on the first increment.
We wanted to keep going until, you know, until it reaches this, this right here.
So we need to keep calling update counter.
Now, if we just call it like this, it's not going to work it.
I mean, it's going to go up, but it's not going to do that, you know, the count up, the animation
type effect.
So what we want to do is just pass this in a set time out and we want to run it, let's say.
Every hour, not every, but we want to wait one millisecond before we run it that way, it waits that
millisecond, which gives it time, and then it will go ahead and, you know, keep running and it's
incrementing by, you know, 60, 25, 38, whatever it was.
And if you want it to go slower, you could do.
You can make this a bigger number, like a thousand.
And you can see that takes longer if we do, let's say ten, very quick.
So it's up to you on how fast you want to make this.
I think 200 is good.
And then I just want to put an elsea.
So else then let's just set the counter dot in our text and set it directly to whatever the target is,
because we obviously we don't want it to go above these numbers which are in the target, and that's
pretty much it.
So obviously, if you wanted to change changes, if you wanted to do, you know, 500000 and save,
it's going to it's even though this is this number is way higher than these, it's still going to take
the same amount of time.
It's not like these will finish first and then this is going to finish after because we took whatever
the target is and we divide it by a specific number, OK?
And then it's going to increment by that so you can set these to absolutely anything.
All right.
So I hope that made sense.
And of course, you could add this to your website, just a little widget, and it doesn't have to be
follower's or it can be any number at all.
And it's pretty easy to to implement.
So no query or anything like that.
But that's it.
I hope you enjoyed it.
Let's move on to the next project.