All right, so this is kind of a cool little project, basically we're going to just track glasses of
water or cups of water and basically we have a goal of two leaders and we have this big cup here and
this is just all success.
So we're going to style this and then add some JavaScript functionality.
So if I click on this first one here, you can see that we have twelve point five percent of our two
leaders.
We have one point seventy five liters remaining.
And if I click on, like the fourth one here, it's going to not only highlight this one or fill this
cup, but all the way up to that cup.
And now you can see I have 50 percent and one leader remaining.
And then here, you know, zero point seven five remaining, sixty two point five I go to 100 percent
fills up the whole thing.
So I think it's a cool little project to kind of manipulate the dom, do a little bit of calculation
in the JavaScript.
So let's go ahead and get started.