All right, guys, so we're going to bring out the timeline access for this drink water project, so
let's jump right into our next TML and for the title here, I'm going to change that to drink water
and then in the body, let's get rid of this one and we're going to have an one for the heading here
and just say drink water.
And underneath that will have an H3 with our goal.
And our goal is going to be to leaders.
And then underneath that, let's have a class of cup.
Now, this class of cup is going to be basically just like the shape of the cup, the the flat top and
then the rounded kind of shape.
And this is going to be used on the big cup and all the small cups, the eight small cups.
So this first one we're doing, though, is going to be the big cup.
And inside here, we're going to have a class of remained.
And this is basically going to have, you know, the the amount that is remaining for your goal.
So inside remained actually want to add an I.D. to this as well, because I'm going to use an ID to
grab onto it in the JavaScript.
So let's just say remained.
And then in here we'll have a span and let's give this an I.D. of leaders.
And for now, we'll put it in here one point five L and then we want a small tag with just kind of a
label that's just going to say remained.
Obviously, this span, this is going to change.
This small tag is not it's just static.
So underneath the remains div, but still within the cup, we're also going to have a percentage.
So this will be like the percentage that has been, you know, that you've drank and this will be an
I.D. also of percentage.
And then inside here I'm just going to do it's going to put 20 percent, but that's going to be dynamic
now underneath this last div so that this is the the cup div.
We're going to have paragraph with the class of text and in here we'll just say select how many glasses
of water that you have.
Drink.
OK, and then underneath the paragraph let's have a class of cups because this is where all the little
cups are going to go, which are also going to have a class of cup but also a class of cup dash small.
OK, and then here we'll say 250 ml and we want eight of these splits.
We'll put a space here.
So let's do it's one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
And I'm just going to add the class of full to a couple of these because the full class is going to
give you know, it's going to look like there's like there's water in it.
It's going to be have a blue background.
So we'll say full on the first two.
And that should do it for the TML.
It's going to look like this and jump into our success.
I'm going to use the Monserrat font, so I'm going to grab from here, delete that and say success.
Family and family is going to be Munt what is amont Sirat to ours.
And for the wait, let's do Colen 400, karma 600 like that and then we'll change your boto to Monserrat
Montserrat.
I have trouble spelling that for some reason.
OK, and then for the body here, let's give this a background color and we're going to use hexadecimal
value three four nine for e for OK and then we'll give it a color.
Text color will be white, it's more readable.
And then let's see as far as the body here we can get rid of.
And see, we don't actually need justify content or hype or overflow hidden and then margin, I'm going
to set just margin bottom of 40 pixels like that.
And then we have some general styles like one for the one I'm going to set margin to do 10 pixels,
zero zero, and then the H3, which is the goal when to set the font weight, let's set the font weight
to 400 and let's set the margin to 10 on the top and bottom.
All right.
Now we have our cup.
So the class of cup, this is for the the one big cup that's going to be up here and for the eight small
ones.
So it's just going to kind of give it that shape.
So let's start with giving them a background color of white, OK?
It's going to look like that.
And the border here is going to be let's do four pixels solid.
Now, this color I'm going to use as the water color as well as the the font color.
So I'm just going to put some of these colors in custom properties.
So up at the top, you don't have to do this.
But since we're going to be repeating some of these colors on the root scope, I'm going to say border
dash color and we're going to set that to the value of hexadecimal one for for FC six, OK, which is
going to be like that darker blue and then for the border here will pass in VA.
And I will say VA will pass in the border color like that.
And then the color is also going to be the same color as the border.
So the text color and then let's set a border radius.
I want the top to be straight edged.
So zero zero and the bottom left and right will be 40 pixels.
OK, now let's give this these a height.
I'm going to use three hundred and thirty pixels for the height and then the width is going to be 150
pixels.
Now at the moment, all of these are big cups, right?
So they're all this height and with.
But later on, we're going to have to remember we have this small class, so we're going to make these
smaller later.
But the initial the initial Highton width will be this.
And then we also want to add, let's say, margin 30 pixels on the top and bottom.
And I'm going to display.
Flex and let's set the flex direction to column, so we want that want the flex items to be on top of
each other and I think that should be let's set overflow to hidden as well.
So nothing comes out of the container and we should be good now for the small cups, let's say wherever
there's a cup, a glass of cup and also a cup small.
Then let's set the width of that.
So instead of instead of, you know, 330 pixels, let's set the the width to 50 pixels and let's set
a height of ninety five pixels.
So you can see now these are smaller.
Now, the the way that the bottom looks, this looks way more rounded because it's smaller.
So we want to set instead of having a border radius of, you know, 40 pixels on the bottom, let's
set these to 15 on the bottom and it'll look more, you know, more similar to how this looks.
OK, and then let's set let's do a background color of our GBA.
Not RGB Q or RGB A and white, so 255 for red, green, blue, and then the alpha value will be zero
point nine and then let's set the set a cursor to a pointer because we're going to be clicking on these
to fill them up.
So we want that cursor to be a pointer and I'm going to set the font size on this to 14 pixels.
And let's set
I'm also going to do a line items to the center because we already have display flex.
Remember, the class has display flex.
So I want to line items to the center.
I also want to justify content to the center and text a line whoops and also text a line to the center.
OK, so I can see that the this text is in the middle and let's add a margin of five pixels.
And I want to transition on this as well because when we click on it to fill, we want that like transition
effect.
So it's two zero point three seconds and we use the EZ effect.
OK, and I think we should be good as far as as far as the small cups, now, we do have a class of
cups, plural, wrapped around this, and we want to set that to Aflex block.
So these are in a row.
So let's add the class of cups and set that to display flex.
And as soon as I do that, it's going to display them all in a row.
I do want them to knock on to the next line.
So what we'll do is set a flex wrap value of rap and it's not going to go on the next line yet because
we need to add a whip here.
So the width I'm going to set on cups is going to be two hundred and eighty pixels and that should just
be enough to wrap, you know, after the fourth one, it's going to knock the next one on to the next
line.
All right.
I'm just going to line items center and justify content center as well.
Good.
Now for the full cups from the first to have a class of full.
So I'll say any class of cup that has cup small and fall, I'm going to set the background color to
actually I'm going to set this as the as a variable and we'll call this fill color.
And then up here, let's set on the root scope fill color.
And this is going to be hexadecimal value six so six A B three F eight.
And now you can see that the first two have this background color because they have that class of fall
now the full class.
We also want to have the color of the text to be white.
So that's a little more readable and that should do it.
Now for the four up here, we have the remained remember, a divide with the class of remained and the
did with the class of percentage.
So four remained.
Let's see, so remained, I'm going to add display flex, I want to center everything so we'll say a
line item center, justify content center and text a line center.
And actually, let's set the flex direction, set that to column.
OK, and then I want this to take up, you know, most of this right here, so we'll set the Fleck's
value to one and then let's add a transition here as well, because when it fills, we want to have
that kind of like, you know, transition animation effects.
So zero point three seconds is now the span.
So inside the member inside remained.
We have this span which has the, you know, wraps around the one point five L so let's say remained
span.
And I just want to set the font size on that to twenty pixels and let's set the font weight to bold.
OK, and then we have the small tag, so say remained small, which is just the text right here remained
and I just want to set that font size to 12 pixels.
All right, now for the percentage part, which is down here.
So percentage I'm going to set the background color and I'm going to use the the full color here, so
let's take the variable of full color and set that and then make the font size to 30 pixels.
And we want to center this.
So let's add display flex and we're going to set a line items to center and justify content to center
that will put that in the middle.
Let's make the font weight bold as well.
So what we will do bold work and then let's set the height to zero, so we'll have an initial height
of zero and then transition.
We're also going to add here to zero point three seconds, EE's.
All right, I think that should do it and then for the techs down here.
So that's a paragraph with a class of text and all I want to do here is just make sure we text a line
to the center and let's also add margin to zero zero five pixels.
All right, cool.
So that should be good for the CSFs.
Now, in the index HTML, we can get rid of the full class here on both of these.
I just wanted to test it out, make sure it looks right.
Also, the data like the 20 percent, we don't need that.
That looks kind of weird because this is empty, but we can still see the top of the 20 percent.
I mean, you could leave it there.
It's going to get overwritten by what we have in our JavaScript, but we'll just get rid of that.
And then also the one point five L that's going to come from the JavaScript as well.
OK, so in the next video, we'll go ahead and we'll start on our script JS file.