OK, so now we're going to get into the JavaScript here of the fun part of this project, and first
thing we want to do, like with most of these projects, is bring in what we want from the DOM.
So we want all these small cups.
So let's say document dot and we're going to use query selector all because there's there's eight small
cups, right?
There's not just one element we're selecting and we want all the cup Dasch small classes.
So that'll put put them all into a no list of elements with the, you know, the class of cups small.
Next we want the leaders.
So leaders is it's the number above remained so right here.
So I mean, there's nothing there right now, but that's what we're grabbing and we need to insert something
in that.
So we want to grab that element.
We're going to use gets element by D has an idea of leaders and then we want two more things.
We want the percentage.
OK, so percentages is down here, it's going to be the percentage fall for the big cup and then the
remaining is the opposite, so remained.
All right, so remained is this right here, this whole divide with the leaders in the remained?
All right.
Now, the way that I'm going to handle this is we're going to take all the small cups and we're going
to loop through with a foreach.
So for each takes in an arrow function and first is going to be whatever we want to call each item,
which I'll call cop, and then we can have the index, which is going to be, you know, zero through
however many cups, so zero through seven, basically.
And in fact, I can just console log the index and if I open up my console.
Yeah.
So it's just logging.
It was just showing the index of each one.
Now what I would what I want to do is add an event listener on each of the cups.
So let's say cup dot, add event listener and we want to listen for a click event on each cup.
And when that happens we're going to call a function.
So we're going to add an arrow function here that calls a function called highlight cups.
And we're then going to pass in that index so we know which one we're clicking on.
So down here, we'll create a function called Highlight Cups, which takes in an index, and then here
lets console log index and now whatever.
When I click on, it's going to show that index.
So what I want to check here is when I click on one of these, basically, I want to add the full class
because remember, when it has a class of full, it gets colored blue.
So I'm going to take all the small cups and there's a few different ways you could do this.
This is probably the easiest way.
So if we take all the small cups and loop through number for each takes in an arrow function and we
want to say for each cup now, I don't want to use IDEX here because I'm using it here, I'm passing
it in.
This is the index of the cup or clicked on.
This is the index of, you know, each one in this loop.
So let's call this one, index two, and then here we'll do a check and we're going to see because what
I want to do is not just fill the one that I click on, but also all the ones before it.
If I click on this fourth one, all the ones before, it should also fill up.
So we can do that by checking if index two basically looping through the small, all the small cups
and seeing if this particular iteration, this index is less than or equal to the index that we click
on.
OK, now if that's true, we'll take the cup and we'll add a class to it.
So we'll say class list, dot add and we'll add the full class or else then we want to remove the class.
So I'll just go ahead and copy that and then we'll just set instead of add we want to remove.
So I'll save that and and let's go over here.
And if I click on one of these, you see that fills up.
If I click on the fourth one, it's going to fill up up to that cup.
OK, so no matter which one I click on, it's going to fill up to that.
But one thing I want to do is if let's say I click on the fourth one here, if I click on it again,
I want this one to empty.
I want to be able to toggle the last one here.
So before we actually do this in highlight cups, I just want to run a check and basically say if the
if the one that we're clicking on is full and the next one is not, then we want to decrease the index
by one and, you know, get rid of this so we can toggle it.
So the way we can do that is by checking small cups, which remember is a node list which is similar
to an array.
So I want to get the current index, meaning the current when we click on and I want to check the class
list and see if it contains a method called contains, we check for a specific class.
I want to see if it contains full and I want to see if it if the next one doesn't contain false.
So I'm going to say, if not small cups, the current index and then I'm going to use the property called
Next Element Sibling and check the class list of that.
So now I'm checking the next one to see if the class list contains full or I should say doesn't contain
because we have this, you know, this exclamation here, which means not if this is true, then let's
take the current index and decrement by one.
So now if I click on, you know, the third and this is full, but this is not and I click again, it's
going to decrease the index and make that go away by click again.
It's going to fill it so I can now toggle the last one.
OK, so that should be good.
Now that's pretty much it for the small cups.
This highlight cups function.
Next, we want to add a function called update big cup where depending on how many cups are filled down
here, this is going to be filled to a specific point.
We also want to show the percentage number.
We also want to show what's remained.
So we'll get into that next.