OK, so now that we were able to fill and empty these small cups down here, we want to work on the
big ones.
So we're going to actually call the function we're going to create in two places.
One is going to be right when the the application loads.
So let's call update big cup.
And then we also want to call it when we click on one of these.
So at the end of highlight cups.
So right under the loop here, let's say update big cup and let's go down here and let's create function
update big cup.
So the first thing I want to do is get the amount, the number of full glasses.
So that's pretty easy.
We can just create a variable called full glasses or let's call it four cups, not four glasses.
So full cups is going to be document dots.
So document dot, query selector all because we want to select all the full cups.
So in here, let's pass in the rest of the class of cups small and also have the class of fall in the
inquiry.
Select our inquiry, select are all we can pass in next selector.
So this is just going to get all the full ones and we want to get the length, so let's say at length.
And then just to show you that we can console log the full cups.
And we'll go down here and we see zero because it calls it right away, but then I'm going to click
on this one here we see that there's two, three, four and so on.
So we have the full cops.
Let's also get the total cops.
So consed total cops, which is just going to be all the small cops.
So Langguth, no small cops we brought in up here, which gives us a no list which we can call lengthen
so we can see the total cops here, which is always going to be eight right now.
I want to hide the percentage which we don't have an actual percentage in there right now anyways.
But let's just say we did like 20 percent.
We want that to hide if if it's empty.
So if there's no full cops.
So let's say if.
If full cops is equal to zero, that means that it should be empty.
So we want the percentage, we want the style and I'm going to set the visibility equal to hidden.
And let's also set the height.
So percentage of percentage style height.
I'm going to set that to zero.
OK, now you can see that kind of flashes for a second there, but it is actually setting it to hidden
and setting it the height zero.
So I'm just going to get rid of that hardcoded 20 percent there.
Now let's have an L.
So basically, if if it has something in it, then we want that percentage.
We want it to show.
So let's set this style dot visibility.
We want to set that now to visible and let's set percentage dot style.
And we want to set the height, style, height and the height we're going to actually get by doing let's
put some back ticks in here, but we can get the height by taking the full glass are full cups and divide
it by the total cups and then multiply it by the height of this large cup here, which if you remember
is three hundred and thirty pixels.
So whatever, whatever the height is, that's what we want to multiply it by and then pass in here.
Just pixels.
It's going to save that.
Close this up.
If I hit this first one here it's going to fill it up to their, their.
OK, now we want the text to say the percentage as well, right now we're only filling the height,
so let's set the percentage in our text and we're going to set that to a set of tactics.
And and here once again, we're going to get the full cups and we want to divide that by the total cups.
And let's multiply that by 100 because we want to get like, you know, 25 percent whatever.
So I'll save that.
If I click this first one, we get twelve point five.
Actually, let's just add a percentage sign right here.
So we get twelve point five percent, 25 percent, 37.
That's half.
That's fifty sixty two seventy five.
Eighty seven point five.
One hundred.
Now we still have this up here.
This remained, which we don't want to show if this is fall.
So underneath this if statement here, let's create another one and we're going to deal with the remain
now.
So we want to check to see if full cups is equal to the total cups, meaning it's fall.
So if it's full, we're going to take remained and we're going to set the style dot visibility to hidden
because we don't want to show that.
And then let's also set the height to zero.
So remained dot style, dot height.
We're going to set that to zero.
So save and we're going to see this remained until it's completely full, then it goes away.
Even if it's here we can see it now.
It's we we don't see the remain text anymore because we've removed it from the DOM.
We've set the visibility to hidden and we've never set it back or the height.
So here we want to have an LS.
Then we'll set remained dot style dot visibility and we want to set that back to visible if it's not
full.
Right.
So set that to visible.
And we also want to set the text of remained.
So if I just save this right now, fill it up and disappears, if it's not totally full we do see remain
but we don't see the leaders.
Remember up here we have a span with the idea of leaders.
So we want to show the leaders that are remaining.
So to do that, let's say remained and we want to set I'm sorry, not remain.
We want to set leaders.
We brought that in up at the beginning.
At the beginning at the top.
Want to set the entire text of that and let's put some back ticks here.
And what I'm going to do is take two fifty, because that's the number down here of milliliters.
And we want to divide that, not divide.
Multiply that by the full cups and then we want to divide that by a thousand because we wanted to say,
you know, zero point two five or zero point five, whatever.
And then I'm going to just let's just see what this does, actually.
So I click on that.
It says zero point two five remain.
That's not true.
It's actually zero point two five full of four of two leaders.
If I click on this one here, it says one remained click here, one point two, five remain, which
is not correct.
Right.
If I click on this one, one point seventy five remain is not correct.
It should be zero point two five remained on the spot.
So what we'll do is let's wrap this in parentheses, what we just put here and let's go to the beginning
here and say two, which is the total number of leaders and minus that from it.
Now, if I click on the first one, we have one seven five remained by click on this one here we only
have point to five remained.
OK, so, I mean, obviously, if I click here, it's 100 percent we have zero remained.
So.
So that should do it good.
Actually, I want to put an L there for leaders, so right after the curly brace, we'll just put an
L.
So two leaders remained here, one point five, seven remained.
And it's twelve point five percent full, 25 percent full, one point five leader remaining.
All right.
So seems to be working.
So that's it.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next project.