So in this project, we're going to be building a movie app and we're going to be using a third party
API from the movie DB Dog, which gives you, you know, a giant database of movies with the title and
ratings and images and just a whole bunch of data that we can work with.
So we're going to, first of all, create the UI, you know, add the e-mail access that we're going
to register an API key with the the TMD DB service.
We're going to add the JavaScript to make a request to get the data to show the most popular movies
at the time, which is what you can see here.
We're going to have this hover effect where it shows you the overview of each movie, shows you the
rating.
We're going to have special colours depending on what the rating is.
So if it's like above eight, it'll be green.
If it's between five and eight, it'll be orange.
If it's below five, it'll be red.
OK, and we're also going to add the search functionality.
If I search for the word hard and enter, it's going to get me all the movies with the title, with
the word hard, or at least the first 20 or 30.
If I search for, let's say, over, see, I'll get movies with over.
So it's it's not a giant application, but it gives you a good idea on, you know, using the fetch
API, working with a third party data service or data API and also putting that stuff into the DOM,
adding the data to the DOM to the page.
So that's it.
Let's go ahead and get started.