OK, so in this project, we're going to build an image slider, but we're also going to have the background
image change as well.
And you can see the background is basically in line with this image here.
So we're going to have some event listeners on these arrows and these buttons.
So when I click, it's going to change this image but also change the background image and position
it into the right place.
So you'll see that these are basically connected, this foreground image in the background.
All right.
So with the both background images, just one is on this, the slide element and then one is on the
body element.
And we're going to add some JavaScript to to add these event listeners and have everything lined up
nicely.
All right.
So let's get started.