So we're going to get started here in our TML, let's say, for the title Thene Clock and get rid of
the H1 and I'm just going to paste in the the dribble link for what you know, what this project was
inspired from just to give them credit.
And we're going to have a clock, but we're also going to have a way to toggle the light mode and the
dark mode.
So that's going to be a button.
So we'll have a button with the class of toggle.
And in here for now, it's a dark mode.
And then underneath that, we'll have our clock dash container and this is going to include the clock
itself.
So I'm going to have a class of clock and the clock will have three needles.
So let's say class needle and let's create three of those.
And then each one will have its have a separate class so we can tell which one is the hour, which one
is the minute and which one is the second.
OK, and then underneath that we just want to live with Center Point.
That's going to be the center of the clock and then outside of the clock div but still within the container
we're going to have a class of time and this is going to come from the JavaScript.
But for now I'm just going to hard code twelve o'clock and then we also want the date and the format
of this is going to be like Monday, Monday, November, and then the day will be in a span.
So let's say span with a class of circle.
And then here I'll just put it to some Monday, November 2nd.
All right.
So if I save that, that's what this is going to look like.
So let's jump into our stylesheet and I don't know if we'll get the whole all the CIA.
We should be able to do all the success.
So I'm going to bring in and see.
We're actually going to use a font called Habbo.
So let's get from here over to success and success.
Questionmark family and sit there to HCB.
Oh, so it's going to be our main fun.
Let's say Colen three hundred and then we're going to add that down here.
Hebel save.
You could see the font.
The fun has now changed.
And then let's see for the body here its display flex.
We want to align center.
We can get rid of flex direction.
And know the rest should be OK now as far as the colors go.
I'm actually going to use some custom properties, so I'm going to go up here and let's say on the route
scope, I want to have a primary color of black and then a secondary
color of white.
Basically, this is going to be for for regular mode or light mode, I should say, and then if the
HTML has a class of dark, because we're actually going to change that within the JavaScript to enable
mode, then let's actually set the primary color, because you can have different scopes for different
variables.
So if it's on this primary dark scope, then the primary color I'm sorry, Teladoc scope and the primary
color will be white and the primary colors like the hands of the clock and stuff like that, the text
and then the secondary.
Color will be let's do three, three three, so real dark gray and then we'll say HTML dyed dark and
we're going to set the background color here to let's do one one one which is almost black and then
the color.
So the text is going to be the primary color.
So var dash dash primary color and it's going to be white because on that scope the primary colors white
everywhere else, the primary color will be black and obviously you don't have to use custom properties.
But I figured I'd make it so that we could easily, you know, change these up here rather than going
through and changing each one later on.
So when we click Doc Mode and this changes, you know, the background goes dark and everything else
goes white, I want it to have a transition so that it kind of has a fading effect rather than just,
you know, flicking to a different color.
So I'm going to add scoresheet here on HTML on the H2O element, let's transition, say transition all
zero point five seconds with an ease in effect.
OK, so that way when the background color changes, it'll fade in.
Now for the let's start on the the stuff in here for the toggle.
So the toggle button, let's do background color and we're going to set that to a cost to our one of
our custom properties of primary color, which is going to be black by default.
And then let's set the color to the secondary color.
OK, so of secondary color and let's get rid of the border, let's set a border radius of four pixels,
let's set the padding to eight pixels, top and bottom, 12 pixels left and right.
And what else, let's position this, so I'm going to position this to be absolute and I want it up
at the top, so let's say one hundred pixels down from the top.
And then this has this outline when it's when we focus on it.
So let's say toggle when it's in its focus state, we want to set the outline to none.
OK, so now let's start on actually, let's give it a curse, curse or appointers as well.
OK, so let's start on the clock container, which wraps around the the needles and wraps around the
the centerpoint, so clock dash container and I'm going to display that as a flex box.
And then let's set the flex direction from RO.
Let's set it to a column and I'm going to justify the content to this space.
Let's do space between and then line items to center.
Now we can't really see much within this container because everything is just an empty div.
So we'll go ahead and start to style the stuff inside.
So we do have a clock class that's going to be positioned relative so we can position stuff inside of
it.
Absolute.
And I'm going to set the width and the height both to two hundred pixels.
OK, and then we're going to do the needles now every needle, hour, minute and second has this needle
class and I'm going to give this clock a temporary background color, just a light gray.
I'm not going to keep this here.
It's just so we can see the outline of the clock and we can position the needles.
So we're going to have like a base needle class and we have the the hour, the minute and second needle.
But this is the base class and we want the background color of this to be whatever the primary color
is.
And then we're going to position this absolute within the clock class and the clock classes relative.
So position absolute.
And let's put it from the top, let's say 50 percent and from the left.
Fifty percent and let's give it an initial height of sixty five pixels, obviously each needle, you
know, the hour is going to be shorter than the minute, but will make the the the hour 65 or the base
needle 65 and then the width of the needles will be three pixels.
All right.
So you can see it's positioned right here.
Now, one thing I want to add to this is a transform origin because we are going to rotate these needles
or these hands.
I see needle or hand.
I mean, the same thing.
So we're going to use, transform, rotate, but I don't want it to rotate like from the middle.
I want it to rotate from the bottom center, you know, so it goes like this.
I mean, I can't really show you with my mouse, but you know what I mean.
I don't want it to spin on the middle.
I want to spin on the bottom center.
So we're going to set the transform origin to bottom center.
OK, and then let's take, let's say, a needle and then hours so far as the our class.
It's set to transform
and we're going to translate because we want to move this up, right?
We want we want the bottom of this to be up here because this is basically the clock.
That's the square.
So let's translate on actually going to use translate because we want it to be directly in the middle
on the X axis, because right now, I mean, it looks like it's in the middle, but it's the beginning
that's in the middle.
So let's say negative 50 percent on X and then we want to move it up negative 100 percent.
Now, this right here is the our needle, right.
These down here, this is still the other two because we have three.
We have the hour, minute and second.
So all we moved right now is the hour.
Now, we also want to add a rotate because that's how we're going to have this thing move.
So let's set it's going to be set to zero degrees initially, which if I say if it's the same thing,
if I set it to, let's say, 30 degrees, you'll see that it rotates like a clock.
So, I mean, we'll get into that later.
But that's how we're going to make this thing move is with transform rotate now for the minute.
Let's see.
We're just going to copy this because we want it in the same position, let's say eight minutes.
And this is going to be the same.
It's going to start at zero degrees.
But I want the height instead of sixty five pixels.
I want it to be 100 pixels.
So if I save that now, you can see that we have the minute placed here as well.
But it's longer.
In fact, if I rotate this 30 and save, you'll see that now the longer hand is rotated 30 degrees.
But we wanted to start at zero now for the second, let's.
Just take this and let's change this to our second hand or second Neidl, and then this can stay the
same, let's the hike and stay the same as well.
What I want to change is the background color, and I want it to be reddish color.
So it's going to be hexadecimal E seven four, C, three C, so it's like a reddish orange kind of color.
And you see if I rotate that, so that's going to be our second hand.
Now, the center point, which is right here where we have a dive for that did with the class of Centerpoint,
we're going to want to style that to be like a circle with a border.
So I think that we can stop here and we'll continue on with this in the next video, because there's
still quite a bit of success left.
And I don't want the video to take up too much time.
All right.
I'll see you in the next one and we'll finish this up.