All right, so in the last video, we created our e-mail, which is pretty simple and a lot of the styling,
so we set the positions of the needles and so on in this square right here, we can actually get rid
of that.
Now, I just wanted you to see kind of the outline of the clock.
So this background color on the clock class, we can get rid of that.
And then let's start on the center point.
So we have a class of center point and we're going to use the Centerpoint class, but we're also going
to use the after pseudo selector because we want it to be basically two circles.
So we need to style both.
So it's going to be a circle within a circle.
So for this, let's set the background color and we're going to set that to, let's say E seven, E
seven four, C, three C, so it's the same color as the second needle.
We could put that in a variable, but these are the only two places we're using it in the right next
to each other.
So this should be fine.
And then I'm going to set the width to ten pixels and also the height to ten pixels.
So you can see it's just a square and it's positioned static right now, which is the default positioning.
So we want to position absolute and as far as where we want to put it, we want to top 50 percent.
And this is within the clock class where that's that gray square was and let's say from the left, 50
percent.
Now, that's not directly in the middle.
So we need to use transform and we want to translate on both axes.
So let's say translate and then just negative 50.
So we want to pull it back negative 50 on Xanthi.
So that'll put it directly in the middle.
And we want this to be a circle.
So let's set the border radius.
We're going to set that to 50 percent, which will make it a circle.
OK, and then I think and I think that's all we want to do here.
Now, we also want to add a like a black dot in the middle.
So I'm going to copy let's actually just copy this whole thing and say center point and then we're going
to use colon, colon after.
And since we're using after, we need to add a content property here, which will just be an empty string.
And I'm going to set the background color to the primary color, whatever that is.
So let's say var dash, dash, primary color and the width and the height.
We want this to be smaller because this is going to be in the middle of the other in the middle of the
red circle.
So we'll set that to five pixels position.
Absolute this this is all good.
That's all the same.
So if I save that now we have a little black dot in the middle of our center point, OK, now it's style
like the text.
So we have the class of time.
I'm to set the font size here to 60 pixels.
So nice and big and then the class of date.
So date I'm going to make the color triple A and then let's set the font size to 14 pixels.
Let's set the letter spacing.
I'm going to do the zero point three pixels and let's make it uppercase.
So text transform will set that to uppercase.
Now the the the date, like the two here, has a span around it with the class of circle.
So let's say for date circle, let's make the background color, the primary color
and let's make the color the secondary color.
And we want it to be a circle, so border radius is going to be 50 percent at that.
All right.
And then let's add a Hitner with so we'll do 18 pixels.
And let's set I'm actually going to display this as in line Fleck's.
OK, and then we want to obviously you want the number in the middle, so let's do a line items center
and let's do justify content center seats that are put in the middle.
And then I'm just going to change the line height to the same as the font size 18 pixels.
And then that when it changes, I want to have a transition.
So at a transition, let's say zero point five seconds is in.
OK, so I think that that looks pretty good.
Actually, the font size, let's say, font size 12 pixels.
All right, so now we have basically our UI done here.
And in the next video, we want to make this function OK.
We want to make the clock work, want to show the date and time.
We want to be able to change to light mode or change to dark mode and back.
So we'll get into all of that in the next video.