All right, so now comes the fun part and, well, I guess it depends on who you are.
Some people do like the UI, the CSI stuff, but I like to make things actually function.
So we're going to jump into the JavaScript and let's bring in everything we need.
So we'll say the our element document dots and I'm going to use query selector and we want to grab the
class of our.
So it's going to be the needled class of our and let's just copy this down a bunch of times.
So we want the our we want the minute and the second and let's change these variable names.
So this will be minute elements and second element and then this is going to be for the time.
So that has a class of time and we want the date so date and we also want the toggle switch or toggle
button.
So this over here will be the date element and then this will be the toggle.
All right.
So that's all the stuff we need to bring in.
So we want to create a couple arrays, one for days and one for months.
And and you'll see why in a little bit.
But I'm just going to season because there's no reason for you to watch me type this out.
It's just two arrays, one call days, Sunday through Saturday, one called months, January through
December.
So very simple.
And before we do anything with the date, the time or the clock, I want to handle the dark mode, which
is going to be pretty simple.
Basically, we just need to change the R add, add or remove the class of dark to to the HTML element.
And we also want to change the text of this.
Right now we're in regular or light mode, so it says dark mode.
If you change the dark mode, it should then say light mode.
So this isn't going to be too hard at all.
We just want to take our toggle button.
If you guys want to pause the video and figure this out, you know, I'm sure that a lot of you can
do can do this without watching.
So I'm going to continue here and just add an event listener.
So we want to listen for a click and let's pass in a function here with our event object and create
a variable here called HTML.
And then we're just going to use document dot, query selector and we're going to select the HTML element.
So basically the root element and we're going to check to see if it has the class of dark.
So let's say if html dot class list dot and then there's contains method.
If it contains dark then let's take HTML and let's take our class list object and call the remove method.
Here we want to remove dark and let's also set e dot target, which means the element we click on,
which is the toggle button.
We're going to set the HTML.
I do in here in our HTML.
We're going to set that to dark mode because we're in light mode, right.
If it contains dark and then we remove, it means red light mode.
So we want the button to say dark mode or else then let's just copy this.
And instead of remove, we want to add the class of dark and we want to change the text here to light
mode.
All right.
So let's go over here and let's click it.
And you can see it fades into dark mode.
The button is now light and the text in all that is all the correct colour because of, you know, the
primary and secondary colours, which we defined up here basically on the root scope.
It's it's the light mode colours.
But if the if HTML has a class of dark, then it's going to be reversed.
OK, so and we have that transition because we did add a success transition.
So that's that's the easy part.
Now we want to do the the clock.
So we're going to have let's go under the event listener here and let's create a function called Set
Time.
So first thing I'm going to do is set a variable of time and set it to new date and just to show you
what that gives us or console long time here and I open up my console.
Actually, we have to call this set time.
And it gives me this, all right, now, with this time variable, I can get specific things like the
month, the day, the hours, all that stuff.
So I'm going to put those into separate variables.
So for the month, we can set we can get it from time, dot, and then there's a get month method that
we can call to get that.
Let's do the day so we can do time, dot get day.
And if you want to console log these to see exactly what it gives you, you can do that.
Let's get the hours.
So time to get ours and then we want the hours for the clock.
Because remember the clock is is what.
It's 12 hours.
Right.
It's not a 24 hour clock.
I mean you could do that if you want, but I'm going to make it a 12 hour clock.
So let's say hours for a clock.
We're going to set that to whatever the hours is with Modulus.
We can use the modulus operator from twelve.
So whatever the remainder is basically.
And then for the minutes, say, koans minutes, we can use time to get minutes.
Make sure you put parentheses on these gets and then seconds.
So consed seconds equals time, doget seconds.
All right.
So that will give us a whole bunch of stuff.
Now as far as.
Making the clock work, let's just close that up, because that ruins the UI here and of course, you
could put the button somewhere else if you want, but basically we want to take each of the needles.
So like the our element and we want to set the on the style.
We want to set the transform, OK.
And set it to some back text.
Now, in our success, you can see for like the hour we have transform translate negative 50, negative
100.
And then the rotate is what we really want to focus on here.
The rotate is going to depend on the time.
So let's just copy this and we'll just just put that right in there like that so that if I say if it's
not going to look any different, if I change this to, you know, 30 degrees.
Why isn't that working?
Transform.
Oh, I copied this, too.
There we go.
So you can see that now the our hand is rotated 30 degrees.
So this obviously needs to be dynamic and it needs to pertain to whatever the time is.
Now, the way we're going to do this is by using very helpful utility function that I've actually used
in quite a few projects in this course.
And that's the scale function.
So I'm going to paste this in.
I'm using an arrow function and it needs to be above set time where we actually use it.
And this is the link to the stack overflow page.
And this comes in handy because what we need to do is, is map, as it says right here, map a range
of numbers to another range of numbers.
So we want to map the hours, which is, you know, 12.
So it's essentially zero to eleven.
We want to map that to zero to 360 because there's 360 degrees in our clock in our circle.
So four rotate.
Let's go ahead and pass in our variable syntax and we're going to set that call scale.
And the numbers of the first argument we want to pass in is going to be hours for clock.
OK, so the hours, 4:00 right now for me, it's one thirty eight p.m. so this should be one and then
the inmind.
So the minimum end is going to be zero, the maximum 11.
So it's zero to eleven, which which is a 12 hour format.
And then we want to map that to zero to 360, OK, because it's 360 degrees and then we want to just
add the digits here, just like we have here.
It has to have that.
So if I save that now, you can see that the hour hand is placed in a specific position.
And if we look at it, let's look at the div here for our and it has a rotate value of thirty two point
seven to seven three degrees.
So it basically took the time, the hours for clock and mapped that to a position in the 360 degree
clock.
OK, we want to do the same thing, four minutes and seconds.
So let's grab that and paste that in and let's do the minutes.
So we'll take the minute element and and then rotate here.
We're going to use scale, but we don't want to use ours for clock because now we're dealing with minutes.
So we want minutes, which we got from here.
And then instead of zero to 11, we want zero to 59.
OK, so 60 Minutes in an hour and then we want to map that to zero to 360.
So if I save that now, the minute hand is over here and then the same thing, four seconds.
So second element, we want to scale seconds and that's also zero to fifty nine to three 360 degrees.
Now, right now, it's just clock that's kind of frozen in time.
We want it to to operate.
We want it to tick.
So the set time, we need to keep calling this.
So will you set interval, which takes in a function which in our case is set time and we want to call
that every second.
So every 1000 milliseconds and they'll save.
And now you can see that the second hand is going to tick every second and you should move along as
well.
All right.
So we have that working.
Let's just try out a transition to the needle.
Yeah, let's do a transition here, so set transition to transition all to zero point five seconds and
ease in just so it kind of when these move, I mean, you're going to barely see them move just like
on a regular clock.
But when they do, we want to transition now.
We want to handle this part here, which is the time and the date.
So let's go into set time below, you know, where we set all the the hands or needles, whatever you
want to call them.
And every time it reaches the end, you know, it's going to do that spin, but it should be accurate.
So what do we want to do here?
Let's take our time element.
All right.
So our time element, we want to set the inner HTML.
So there's two ways we can do this.
We can use ours, which will give us, you know, military time.
It'll be when it's one o'clock, it'll say 13 and then 14, 15, so on.
Or we can do the 12 hour clock.
I'm going to go with the 12 hour clock.
So I'm going to set it to its back ticks here.
And we want to use if you want to do the twenty four hour clock, you can use ours.
I'm going to use ours for clock.
All right.
And then we'll have a colon and then we want the minutes.
Now, we do want to have a zero in front of the minute.
Right?
So if it's if it's twelve or five.
Right.
We don't want it to just say twelve colon five, which is what minutes gives us.
So we want to check to see if it's less than ten.
If it is then we'll add a zero.
So here, let's open up another, you know, variable syntax and let's say if minutes I'm going to use
a ternary here.
So if minutes is less than ten then let's add a zero.
So we'll put in a set of tactics and say zero and then whatever the whatever the minutes is.
And then we'll go outside of the back ticks here and say else then just put in whatever the minutes
is.
So let's save that.
And you can see I get one forty three.
Now at the moment there's no way to tell if this is a.m. or p.m. I mean you're probably going to know,
but we should put that somewhere.
So what we'll do is add let's add a variable up here, call it AMPM.
And the way that we can get this is by checking the hours.
So I'll use a ternary here.
I'll say if ours is greater than or equal to twelve, then let's set PMB else.
Let's set this string to an OK and then we'll go down here and right after five minutes let's put in
ampm.
So now I get one forty four p.m..
So for the date let's do that, let's go right here and say date element and I'm going to set that equal
to some tactics.
And in here this is where we're going to use our days in Monterrey.
So I'll say day or days and I want to use the day that I got from here as an index for the days, OK,
because it's going to be, you know, zero one, two, three and so on.
So that'll give us the day.
And then for the month, let's put a comma here and oops, not there here, because we want like this
Monday and then comma and then November or whatever the whatever the month is.
So let's take the months away and for the index we're going to use the month that we got from up here.
All right.
And then let's see.
So we have that, then we have a span.
So let's put a spanner in here, give it a class, let's use a circle
span.
And then in here is where we want the day so we can actually just put in here the date variable, which
wait a minute, we not put this.
We didn't do this.
All right.
So let's copy this down another day and let's say date and set that to get date.
So I saved that and now I should be able to get rid of everything that we have inside this div with
the class of date, and if I save should get rid of this to.
And that's see, that's not showing up.
Oh, I need to set in our HTML and then we go so we get the same thing Monday, November 2nd.
OK, so now this works.
This is dynamic.
We can change to dark motor light mode.
And hopefully this just gives you a better understanding of how to deal with, like, success and changing
specific styles and stuff like that.
All right.
So that's going to be it for this project.
Guys, I hope you enjoyed this and I will see you in the next one.