So in this project, we're going to create a button ripple effect, basically will be able to have buttons
and just give it a specific class of ripple.
And when we do that, if we click on those buttons, we'll get this effect.
And it's not just a ripple effect in the center.
It's wherever we click on the button.
And we're going to obviously add the animation, the styling with access.
But we need JavaScript to be able to pinpoint where exactly we're clicking so that we can change some
of the CSFs values of the positioning to give it that effect in that exact position.
All right.
So that's what we'll be doing.
Let's go ahead and get started.