All right, so let's get started with our button ripple effect.
So the idea is we want to have a button and then we click on it.
We're going to basically have our JavaScript create a specific span that will have a class of circle.
And we're going to style that to basically be like a round white circle with an animation.
So it scales up and we want to set the the position of it.
So the top and left position, we want to set to where we click.
So we don't want to just always ripple in the center.
We want it to ripple wherever we click.
So we're going to have to do that within, you know, with a combination of CSR and JavaScript.
So let's call this button ripple effect.
And all we're going to have here is a button, we'll say click me, and then for now, I'm going to
hard code the span in here just so that we can style it.
But ultimately, like I said, this will come from JavaScript, so this will have a class of circle.
Then I'm going to just put some inline style in here for the position of it, so for this will just
say top, I'll say twenty seven pixel semicolon and then from the left, I'll do like 82 pixels.
OK, so we just have our button, and that's all we need for the HTML, very, very simple.
Stylesheet is is pretty easy as well.
I'm going to add a background comes out of background color of black.
And then let's see that that's fine for the body, we can leave those styles and then button what style
that I'm going to give it a background color of purple and let's give it a color of white, OK?
And then for the border, we'll do one pixel purple solid.
And then for the font size, let's set that to 14 pixels and make it uppercase, so text, not text,
uppercase, text transform, we're going to set to uppercase and let's set the letter spacing.
Set that to two pixels, not 20 pixels, two pixels, spread it apart just a little bit, and then for
padding on the button, lets to do 20 pixels top and bottom, 30 pixels left and right, and then let's
set the overflow to hidden so that nothing comes out of the button and then just margin 10 pixels on
the top and bottom.
So obviously you could use this, you know, you could use this in any of your websites or applications.
So now let's do the circle that we just hardcoded inside.
So we'll save button, dot, circle, and we want to position this to be absolute.
And remember, we have in here, we have the inline styles of top and left.
This is going to just be basically random, not random, but based on where we click.
And we're going to do that through the JavaScript, but we're just setting it hardcoded for now.
So position absolute.
Let's give it a background color of white.
And of course, we could change some of these values to make it look a little different.
We'll give it a whiff of 100 pixels and also a height of 100 pixels.
And the reason that it's up there right now is because I positioned it.
Absolutely.
But I forgot to position the button relative.
So right now it's being positioned absolute in the browser window instead of the button.
So let's just add here position.
We want to do position relative.
So now it's going to be relative to the button.
So basically this is put wherever we you know, wherever we put this here.
If I if I say top zero, that's going to move it up.
So it's just a random position.
And then let's see, we want to we want it to be a circle.
So so at the border radius to 50 percent and then.
It's on the on the X and Y axis, so translate, I'm sorry, transform.
Translated, We want to position this to be basically in the middle of where we put that point.
So to do that, let's do negative 50 percent and negative 50 percent on the X and Y axis.
OK, so now you can see where it's positioned.
Let's see, what else do we want to do here?
That's pretty much it for the styling.
Oh, one thing I want to do is take that focus or take that outline off the focus of the button.
So button, when it's in its focus, they set the outline to.
Right now, this we want this to have an animation where it scales up and disappears.
So let's start this off.
With a scale, so I'm adding another transform value, we already have translate, but we can add more
than one transform value.
I want to start this off with a scale of zero, and then we're going to have an animation called Scale
and it will last point five seconds for the duration and we'll use these out.
OK, now the animation, we need to create that, so let's say keyframes.
And we called it scale, and we're just going to use a two here because we want it to go from its original
scale of zero and we want to change the trend.
Actually, I'm just going to copy this.
And paste that in, and we wanted to scale up to three.
You can see when I save with live servery, you can see the animation now that that's, you know, it
just takes up the entire thing.
We also want it to disappear within that time.
So we'll set the capacity to zero.
So now you can see as it scales up, it just disappears.
OK, or it has that has that fading out effect, really.
So that's pretty much it for for the success and the next video, we're going to make it so that when
we click, we want to target where we click and then have that effect come from, you know, wherever
we click.