All right, so we're going to start on a JavaScript, but there's just a couple of things I want to
do here in the HTML.
One, I want to put a class on the button because I don't want to automatically add the ripple to all
buttons.
So we'll just add a class of ripple here and then we can get rid of the span because we're going to
be, you know, adding that through the JavaScript and will leave the styling for the button here.
But if we want it to have the ripple effect, then we'll add that class of ripple.
So let's say const buttons and we're going to use document dot, query selector all because we want
to be able to do this on multiple buttons as long as they have the class of Ripple.
OK, and then we'll take those buttons and let's add a foreach here and we'll say for each button,
let's take that button and let's add an event listener on them and it's going to listen for a click.
And when we click, we're going to run a function past in our of an attribute here, our event object
in the first.
We want to get a couple different values.
The first is going to be where we click in the viewport, but it's only going to fire off if we click
the button because that's where this event listener is.
So I'm going to call this value X and set it to that event object and then client X and then I'm going
to do the same for client client.
Why put that into a Y value?
And then just so you understand what we're getting here, let's consider log X and Y.
So I mean, if I click out here, nothing happens because the event listeners on the button.
But if I click like up in the top here, you'll notice it's not like, you know, two, three or something
like that because it's not getting where we click in the button, it's getting where we click in the
entire viewport.
So this is saying it's 160, 160 pixels over from the left because this is the X and then one ninety
nine is, you know, where we click down from the top because that's the Y axis.
So now that we have that, there's another thing that I want to get, which is the position of the the
button itself.
Where does it start on the X?
Where does it start on the Y?
So to get that, let's create a variable called button top and we'll set that to target, which is always
the element that that the event fires off of, in this case, the button.
And then there's a property called Offset Top, which is going to give us where it starts at the top.
We also want to get where it starts from the left.
So offset left will set that to button in the left.
So now, just to show you what that gives us, say, button, top and button left.
If I click it, it's always going to be the same no matter where I click, because what it's getting
is the position of the button itself, not where we click.
Now we want to calculate where in the button we click.
Like if I click up in the corner, it should be something like one one.
Right.
So the way that we can do that, let's say CONSE will call this X inside because it's the opposite position
inside the button.
And then we take the X value, which is the, you know, the where we click in the entire viewport and
then we just subtract from that the the top, the button top the offset from the element itself.
So button.
Top, and then we'll do the same for, say, button left.
This is going to be the Y value and this is going to be why inside and then will console log here X.
Inside and why inside, so now if I click over in the corner here, it should be some very low number.
Actually, that's not right.
Why is it negative?
Oh, I got these I did these wrong.
This should be button left.
Yeah, because this is the x axis and then this should be button top.
All right, now, if I click over in the corner, we get like four, three, five, three.
So it's getting from where the button starts over, that's going to be the X inside.
And then from where it starts on the top down is going to be the Y inside.
So we'll get rid of that.
And then we want to create a circle element.
So the span that we excuse me, the span we had in here before, we want to construct that from within
our JavaScript.
So let's say document create elements and we want to create a span.
We want to add a class to it.
So let's take our circle and say class list, dot add.
And we want to add the class of circle and then those positions where we have the top and left in the
inline style, well, we want to get that from these values right where wherever we're clicking.
So let's take the circle and style and we can set any excess property we want here.
We want to set the top value to whatever y inside is because why is the, you know, the Y axis.
But we want to just add on to that p x because we need to that's the format and access.
It'll be, you know, 10 pixels, whatever, whatever it has to be.
And I'm just going to copy that down.
And let's change this to X inside and change this to the left value.
And then down here, let's use the this key word pertaining to this this element.
And we want to append child.
So we're putting in the circle element.
All right.
So if I save that and I click, oh, you know what, since I use this, this isn't going to work with
an arrow function is has to be a regular formatted function.
So let's just get rid of the arrow here like that.
And then if I click now, you can see that the circle is is basically just showing up wherever I click.
Now, we do have one issue here that you can't really see from here.
But if I go down, look at all these circles.
So every time I click, it does add the circle, but it doesn't just remove it from the DOM.
That's the thing with vanilla JavaScript is you have to handle everything.
If you put something into the DOM, you have to handle handle taking it out.
Stuff like that is a lot easier if you're using something like react because you get a bunch of tools
to do to deal with the DOM.
So what we're going to have to do here is remove it from the DOM after, but we just want to wait a
certain amount of time.
So we're going to set time out, which takes in a function.
And what I want to do here is take the circle.
So the current the circle that we just appended into the DOM, we want to remove it.
So I'm going to call circle dot remove.
All right.
And then this takes time.
It takes a second argument of the time we want to wait, which is going to be 500 milliseconds.
So now when I click, you can see right down here, the arrow will show when the when the circle is
put in and then it's automatically taken out a half a second later.
OK, so you want to make sure that when you're using vanilla JavaScript and here you're adding stuff
to the DOM, you want to make sure that you clean up afterwards.
You don't want just a, you know, a shitload of circles in the in the button.
All right.
So that's it.
Hopefully you guys enjoyed this.
I know it's a very simple thing to just have a ripple, but if you're pretty new to JavaScript, this
should help you out, you know, finding out where you're clicking, finding out the position of a specific
element, adding an element, manipulating the style.
So there's quite a bit and just this tiny little project, if you're just learning JavaScript or you
don't know much about the Dom in general.
All right.
So that's it.
Let's go ahead and start on our next project.