All right, so in this project, I want to get into a little bit of drag and drop functionality, so
we're going to just create these boxes style, these boxes.
We're going to have one div inside one of these boxes that has a background image coming from one splash,
just a random image.
And you see, if I grab it, a couple of things happen.
The the image I'm holding has a class of hold, which gives it a gray border, which you can't really
see.
It's very faint, but it has a border.
And then each one of these boxes I hover over gets a class of Harvard, which gets a back of a background,
a dark background and a white dashboard.
And then if I drop, it'll actually go in whichever of these hovering over.
All right.
So it's a very simple project, but it gives you a basic understanding of how drag and drop works.
And you can then go on to build some really cool interfaces or even games and stuff like that.
So let's go ahead and jump in and get started.