All right, so we're going to get started on a drag and drop project, so I have my project starter
open.
I'm going to just change this to drag and drop.
And the HTML is going to be really, really simple.
We're basically just going to have a bunch of boxes with the class of empty.
So let's say class empty and we want five of these.
So we'll say times five.
And the first one here, I want to have the the image that we can drag and drop.
So inside this div, I'm going to have a class of fill.
And we also want to add an attribute here of Dragonball, OK, because we want this to be Dragonball
within the browser.
So we want to set Dragonball equal to true.
And that's it.
That's all we need for our HTML.
So now let's jump into our stylesheet and we'll start to create this.
So we actually don't need any font because there's no text.
So we're just going to get rid of that for the flex direction.
I'm not going to use a column unless it's on smaller screen.
So what I'll do is get rid of the Flex Direction column, but just create a media query down here.
So say if it's a max width of 800 pixels, so if it's under 800 pixels, then on the body, we want
the flex direction to be a column.
OK, and then in the body, the only other thing I'm going to do here is add a background color of steel
blue.
All right.
So now we want to style the boxes with the class of empty.
So let's say class empty.
And I'm going to actually we don't need a display here.
Let's do a height of 150 pixels and a width of 150 pixels and we'll do a margin of 10 pixels.
And I'm going to have a border solid three pixels and.
Black, and let's give it a background of white, OK, so there's our boxes, those are empty boxes.
Now, when we when we have our image here, actually, let's just do the fill class.
So under empty, we'll have our fill class and we're going to have a background image here.
And I'm going to use an unspoiled random image.
So it'll be a different image every time.
So for the Earth, it's a mess and it's going to be source dot on splash dot com and then slash random
and then you can do a size.
So I'm going to do one 50 x 150 will be 150 by 150.
I'm going to set the height of that to one forty five pixels.
And let's set up from a semicolon.
And let's set the width to one forty five pixels and let's look the cursor to a pointer, and if I save
that, you'll see we have a random image and it's going to be a different image every time.
And I'm able to drag this and see that if I don't have this, if I set this to false.
And now you see, I can't actually pick it up and drag it, so you want to make sure that that attribute
is always set to true if you're using drag and drop.
Now, we want to have some specific styles when we're dragging it.
So, for instance, when I'm when I click and I hold and I'm dragging it, I want it to have a border
like a grayish white border around it.
So I'm going to have a class here of hold and I'll say border so that the solid let's do five pixels
C.C.C..
Now, that's not going to be applied.
But when we get to our JavaScript, when we have that event where we're holding it, we wanted to add
the border.
I can add it manually.
If I go over here and I say hold now you can see there's that gray border around it, but I only want
it when I'm actually holding it.
And then I also want to style these boxes if we hover over.
So if I take this and I hover over a box, I want it to have a dark background and also have a dashboard
around it.
So let's have a class called Harvard.
So you just need to figure out the styles of the different states of the drag events, because there's
there's multiple drag events that we can use.
So we're going to set the background color of this to three, three, three, if it if it has the class
of Harvard and let's also say border color, we'll set that to white and we'll set the border style.
We'll set that to dashed
hopes.
Keep forgetting my semicolons border white.
You don't need that.
OK, so this isn't going to show just yet because we need to apply that with the JavaScript, so in
the next video jumped, it will jump into our script.
Yes.
And we'll start to add all of our different drag events.