OK, so now we want to fire off specific events at certain times during the whole drag process, so
first thing I want to do is create our drag functions.
I'm going to do that down here.
So the first one is drag start, and that does exactly what it says.
As soon as you pick something up and he starts to drag it, this will fire off.
And for now, I'm just going to do a console log for all of these and just say what they do.
So that's drag start.
And then I guess we'll just you we'll just copy this down a few times.
So we have drag start.
We also have drag end.
And you can check out these events in the Murdochs, too, but you'll see exactly when they fire off
the drag and we have drag over.
So when we drag over something, drag enter
and drag leave so we can enter and leave and we also have drag drop for when we drop.
All right.
And then we'll just change the this text here say drag drop.
This one is leave.
This one is enter and this one over and end.
All right.
So when do we want to fire these off while we need to bring in.
Or, you know what, we need to drag, which is the film class, and then all of these empty boxes,
which there's multiple of.
Right.
So we need to use query, select, they're all for those.
So let's first grab our fill, which is only one of so we'll say document dot, query selector, and
that has a class of fill.
And then we also want all the class of empty as more than one.
So we want to do query selector all.
We'll call this MTIs and let's do four fill.
We have to two events that we want to fire off and two of these functions drag's start in drag end.
So that applies to the fill to this image that I'm actually dragging.
So let's add an event listener on to this.
And I named the functions the same as the events.
Only the events are all lowercase.
So you want to do drag, start all lowercase.
That's the event name.
And then we're going to fall call drag star like that and we're going to do the same with drag.
And so make sure the second one has the camel case because that's the function and this is going to
be drag and all lowercase.
All right.
So let's go ahead and open up the console here.
I'm going to put this at the bottom.
And this kind of messes up the sizing of this, but I don't know, that's fine, I guess, because it'll
still pop in there.
So I'm going to click this and notice as soon as I pick it up, we get dragster.
And then when I let go, I get drag and drag, start drag.
And so we know that that's firing off.
So we know these functions are running.
Now, the rest of the functions here are going to go on the empty boxes.
All right.
So I'm going to there's a couple of ways we could do this.
We could use foreach we've been doing that quite a bit throughout the course.
So we're going to use a for loop here that we can do this as well.
And we'll say for const empty of empty.
So this is a form of loop the slot.
This should be MTIs because remember this is a node list which is basically an array.
And we're just saying for each empty of the MTIs array, then what we want to do, we want to use that
empty variable and we want to add an event listener.
So this is going to be for drag over and that's going to call the function drag over.
And we want four of these.
So this next one here is going to be drag, enter, drag, enter.
We have drag leave, drag leave.
Now, the last one is is a little different than the rest because all the other events start with drag.
This one is just drop.
So we don't want drag drop here.
We just want drop.
But I did call the function drag drop so they drag drop.
All right.
So now let's save that and I'm going to grab this.
You can see drag over is just keeps firing off.
And as long as we're moving over something, it just keeps firing off.
And you can see drag enter, drag leave.
OK, so so enter and leave just will run once like you enter when we enter this box here and then when
I leave it calls drag leave, but when I'm going anywhere over it, it calls drag over.
So hopefully you can see what exactly what the when these events are firing off.
Now, as far as these events down here, we'll start with Drag's Star, which is on the the Phil element.
Right.
It's on this right here, which is the as the has the background image.
So what I want to do with that first is add the class name of hold.
So I'm going to say this class name and this we can just assign a class or we can append a class.
In this case, we want to upend the class of hold.
We still want it to have the class of Phil.
So plus equal will append and then we just want to put space and then hold.
All right.
As soon as I do that, when I grab this, you'll see it has the the border around it, both the one
I'm holding and that image.
Now, as soon as I pull it out of the box, I want the box to clear up.
So what I'll do is I will say this class name and we want to just reassign it.
We can leave it empty or we can just put a class of invisible.
I know we don't have many styles for that, but we can set it to invisible.
And but if I go over here and I click, what happens is I don't even have time to grab it and to add
hold it just this happens like at the same time and invisible gets applied fact.
If I look down here, you see that has a class of invisible.
Phil is gone, hold is gone.
If I do it real quick, it's just open this up so you can see it has a class of fill.
And as soon as I click, I don't have any time to to basically grab it so we can just add a set time
out which takes in a function.
And what I want to add is this right here
and we can even put zero.
We don't have to put anything above zero here.
It'll just make it so that this happens first.
Right.
So if I go over here now, I can grab it and pull it out, OK?
And then that box then turns white.
Now, as far as our event listeners down here are functions, I'm going to start with drag start.
I'm going to get rid of this.
And I want to add the class name of hold when we start to drag and that whole class will put that border
on the fill.
Did for the div that has the background image.
Now we can use the this keyword, which is going to pertain to whichever element that the events fired
on in this case it's going to be fill, which is the div with the background image.
So I want to take that specific element and I want to add class name.
Now, this class name will just set the class.
I could set it equal to something which would replace any other class that's already there.
But I actually don't want to replace, I want to append.
So I'm going to say plus equals and then add space hold.
OK, so it's going to still have the fill class, but it will also have the old class.
So now let's go ahead and drag this and hold.
And you can see the border, the c the the gray border around the picture.
It's kind of faint because of the picture, but it's on this one and it's on the one that's still there.
Now, another thing I want to do is when I pull it off the box, I want this box to go white.
So we want to do that by getting rid of the fill class on that.
So let's say this dot class name and we could set it to nothing, but I'm going to set it to a class
of invisible.
It doesn't this class doesn't do any thing.
There's no styling for it, but it'll get rid of the whole class.
So if I open up my tools down here so you can see it has a class of fill now, as soon as I click,
it goes to invisible.
It doesn't even give me time to to drag it and to add the class of hold.
So what we'll do is add a set timeout, which just, you know, sets a time out for something to happen,
for a function to run.
So we want to add in a function here, our function, and I want this to run in here.
And I don't even have to put a time.
I can just put zero here and that well, that's enough for this to happen first so that it just doesn't
disappear when I click on it.
So now if I save, I'll go ahead and click and hold and I'm able to pull it out and then this goes white.
OK, so we have that done.
Now, when I draw up, it's just it's still gone because it has the class of invisible.
So we also have drag and on the fill element.
So if we go down actually drag and is right here, we want to then add the class name of Phil.
So let's say this dot class name and just set that to fill.
Because right now we're only dealing with the one we're clicking and dragging, we're only dealing with
this because those both of those have dragged start and drag end.
So right now, if I pull it off, you'll see this goes white.
I'm able to add the whole class when I let go, it goes back to the same place because this specific
element still it still has the fill, right.
This this isn't being added anywhere else.
What we want to happen is when we drop on one of these boxes, we want this div to go in, whichever
one we drop.
So we just close access.
So what we'll do is go down to drag drop and let's get rid of this.
And I want to say this dot class name set that to empty.
We always want to make sure that it has a class of empty right before we drop or when we drop it.
Then we also want to add the class or not the class, but the element of fill inside of whichever one,
you know, we drop on.
And we do that with the append method.
So I can say this, meaning the class of empty that did with the class of empty.
And then I want to append into that the fill of element.
Now, if I save this and I try to drop it here, you notice it's not working.
And the reason for that, I'm just going to bring this browser window over for a second.
So both the drag over and the drag enter events have a default action.
You can see drag over resets the current drag operation to none, which we don't want to happen.
Drag enter will reject the immediate user selection as the potential target element.
So we don't want either of those to happen.
So all we have to do is for drag over and drag enter is past in our event objects and call each dot
prevent default.
That'll stop the default behavior of these two events.
Just like if you submit a form and you don't want to actually submit it's am doing, you don't want
to actually submit it to the page.
You want to, you know, use JavaScript, you would prevent the default behavior.
So now let's go ahead and try it.
So I'll just go down here and let go and notice I'm able to now drop it wherever I want.
OK, so that's the drag and drop functionality.
But I also want to have an effect when I hover over these as well to make the the box I'm hovering over
docker.
So on drag enter.
After we prevent the default, we're going to take that element and we want to append the class name.
So plus I want to do plus equals and we want to add the class of covered.
So now if I take this, you can see every time I enter it adds that class.
So we actually want to clear that when we leave.
So on drag leave, we'll just go ahead and set the class name, we'll set it equals we don't want to
append, we just want to basically reset it.
So we'll set it to empty again.
So now if I go over here and I enter, it gets that dark background.
That's the class of hover, also the dashboard here.
But when I leave, it goes back to empty.
OK, so whatever I hover over, we get that effect and then I can drop it.
All right.
So, I mean, that's that's pretty much the basics of drag and drop with HTML, HTML5 and JavaScript.
So I mean, you can be more creative with this and you can create games and really cool interfaces.
But this should give you an idea of just how to you know, how to add these different events and do
certain things when they fire off.
So that's it.
Thanks for watching.
I'll see you in the next project.