All right, so this is actually one of my favorite projects in this course, this is a little drawing
app that we're going to create using HTML5 canvas.
So we're going to use the canvas element.
That's what this big square is.
And there's a JavaScript API that we can use to draw shapes.
We can draw, you know, circles, rectangles, images, whatever lines.
And we're going to implement that with mouse events so that we can actually click and we can draw,
OK, so we can draw.
And then we're going to add these controls down here where we can actually change the color.
So change it to red start to draw and we can change the the width of the the pen or the line here.
So if I go down to five and see it's a little smaller, I'll change the color to like a greenish color
and bring this to 20.
OK, and the highest we can go is 50.
So that's the thickness we can go and the lowest we can go is five and we can clear it with this button
here.
So I think it's a cool little canvas app and I think you'll enjoy it.
So let's go ahead and start on the interface and then we'll we'll talk a little bit about creating shapes,
creating circles and lines with canvas, and then we'll move into the mouse events and drawing and then
these two box controls down here.