OK, so we're going to get started on our drawing app and I'm just going to leave the browser a little
wider than usual just so we can fit the whole canvas in there because we wanted to be quite big since
it's a drawing area.
So for the title here, let's say drawing app, and we want to add our canvas element.
So it's a canvas.
I'm going to give it an idea of canvas as well.
And basically this just allows us to have an area that we can use the canvas API on.
So in JavaScript we can draw shapes and lines and do all types of cool stuff.
Now I do want to give this a width and give it a width of 800 and height.
So we have 800 height.
I might make that a little smaller later, but if I save that, we're not going to see anything.
The canvas is there.
If we open up our elements tab and the dev tools, you can see if I highlight over canvas, we can see
the outline of it and you can add access to this, like we could say style.
You don't have to write, have to do this.
But just to show you, we could say like background red and save and now you can see the outline of
our canvas.
All right.
I'm just going to get rid of that.
Nothing is going to go inside those inside the canvas tags.
But what we do want is an area under the canvas to have our toolbox, which is going to be like where
we can increase and decrease the size of the pen and so on and change the color and clear it.
So let's create a divide with the class of toolbox here and in here will have a button.
So this button will have an idea of decrease.
And I'm just going to put a minus sign inside the entire text here and then under that will have a span.
And this is going to have an idea of size.
So the initial size, I'm going to say 20 and then under that will have another button.
And this is going to have an idea of increase.
And inside here, we'll have a plus sign.
OK, we also want the color.
So let's say inputs.
And this is actually going to be a color input.
So each HTML5 has color inputs, so the type will be color.
We don't need the name.
The ID will also be color.
And then finally we want a button to clear it.
So say Button will give an idea of clear and I'm going to put an X inside of that.
All right.
So if I say that it's going to look like this, OK, now we're going to style and you can see the color
picker here, which is pretty cool.
It's just an HTML five input of color.
But let's jump into the stylesheet.
And surprisingly, we're not going to have to do too much here.
I'm going to keep the Roboto font.
Let's give the body a background color of light gray.
We'll do five, three times.
And then I want to get rid of overflow hidden case.
We have to scroll.
And that should do it for the body, for the canvas, so the canvas, I'm going to give a border, so
it's a border.
Let's do two pixels solid and I'm going to use steel blue.
Of course, you can use whatever color you want.
And then we have our toolbox, which has all the controls.
So for the toolbox, I'm going to set a background color of steel blue and I'm going to set a water.
Let's do border one pixel and solid and we'll use Slate Blue for that.
You can see that down here.
Now, I'm going to display this as a flex box so that everything inside of it are lined up as flex items.
And let's set a width of this.
I'm going to do a with of eight 04 pixels.
So that should just, you know, fill up the same with as the canvas and then padding.
Let's do one room padding like that.
Now, I want all of these controls here to have a just I want them to be in a big white box, everything.
So I want to take all of the direct children of Tool Box so we can target that with class toolbox and
we want the direct children.
Doesn't matter what the element is, button input, whatever span.
And let's set the background color to white and I'll just make this smaller so I can actually see.
So make the background color white.
Let's remove any border so border none.
And let's set them to display.
I'm going to use in my inline flex for the display and then we can a line item center and justify content
center.
OK, so they're all in the same level and let's make the font size much bigger.
We're going to use two REM units.
OK, let's give it a fixed height and width of 50 pixels.
So height and with.
All right, let's add some margin will do points to five REM spaced him out a little bit.
Let's do padding and padding will be same thing.
Point to five REM.
And I think I think that's it, yeah, so we have all these boxes now, the last one to clear, I want
that to be set over here.
So what I can do to target that is, say, the direct children of Tool Box.
But I only want the last ones when you use the pseudo selector of the last Dasch child.
OK, so it's the last child element in the toolbox and I'm just going to set margin dash left to auto.
And if I do that now, it gets pushed over to the side.
All right, cool.
Let's actually add a pointer as well.
OK, so that's pretty much it for the interface.
And I mean, of course, you can make this is as big or small as you want, but we're going to go with
this.
And in the next video, we'll start on our JavaScript will get into canvas so that we can actually draw
on this and control the pen and all that.