All right, so we're going to start on our JavaScript and we're using the canvas API, which is a way
to draw graphics or draw shapes on the canvas using JavaScript, and we're using the small five canvas
element.
So basic example here, we can bring in our canvas and then we create a context using get context created
to add context.
And then we can call certain we can set certain properties and methods like the film style set the green
Phil RACT will create a rectangle.
The first two are the positioning.
So it's ten over from on the x axis of the canvas and then ten down on the y axis.
The width is 150.
The height of this is 100.
All right.
So I'm just going to grab that.
So we're bringing in canvas.
It does have an I.D. of canvas.
So bring that in and then we create a context.
Now, I actually want to draw a circle, so I'm going to have a function called Draw Circle and we are
going to be using this function in the in the final version draw.
A circle is going to take in an X value in a Y value.
That's going to be the positioning on the canvas where we want to draw the circle.
Now, if we go, I think there's a link down here.
Yeah.
Drawing shapes and see paths.
And right here, so to draw a circle, we need to begin a path and then create an arc and the arc takes
in the positioning where you want to put it, the radius of the circle.
I think this is the start angle and the end angle is right here.
And then if you want it clockwise or counterclockwise.
So I'm actually going to.
Grab this.
So we're going to begin a path now, the values here, I don't want this is just this is 75 over 75
down.
I want this to be wherever X is that's passed in in Y and then the size I'm going to have in a variable
called size, and that's going to be a global variable.
So up here, I'll say let size and set that to 20.
OK, so that will get passed and then zero for the start and then the end will be yeah.
Math dot pi times two and then you don't need to pass anything in here.
So just doing that, if we take a look it doesn't do anything because we haven't filled the circle yet.
So what I'm going to do is set a color on the circle first through dot and then fill style.
And I'm going to set that to a variable called color, which I'm also going to set up here, because
we want we want this to be accessible outside of this function.
So the color initially all set to black and then let's fill the circle.
So take our context.
And there's a method called fill.
Now, if I save that, OK, we have to call the function.
Let's call, draw, circle.
And let's say we want to start at one hundred over and 200 down.
So save that.
And now it's going to plot a circle or draw a circle.
One hundred over on the x axis and 200 down on the Y and that's within the canvas, not the page.
All right.
Now, we also want to be able to draw lines, so let's say function, draw a line.
And this is going to take in the move to positions X and Y positions like where we want to move to and
also where we want to draw the line from in two.
So what will pass in is X1 and Y one.
So that's going to be the move to X1 and why one.
And then the line to which draws the line will be X to and Y two.
All right.
So in here we need to again begin a path, so begin path and then let's do X dot move two and that's
going to be x1 y one.
So that's going to move to a specific position.
It's not going to plot anything or draw anything.
It's just going to move to it.
Then let's say it's line two and that's going to go to X two and Y two.
All right.
Now we need to want to apply a color so we do that with X dots and stroke style.
So stroke is like like a a border kind of.
So when we use a line, we're using a stroke.
So the strokes style is going to be the same color as the circle.
So the basically the global color, which is going to start off as black, we're going to be able to
ultimately choose our color here, but it's going to start as black and then the line width.
So let's say it's a line with and we're going to set that to a variable of size, which is this, you
know, twenty to start with.
And then finally to actually draw the line we need to call stroke.
So dot stroke.
And then let's go down here and let's say draw a line and we'll say, let's start 300 over on the x
axis.
Three hundred down on the Y axis.
So that's basically the move to which you can think of as having your pen off the paper.
You're moving to a certain spot.
The second two arguments we're passing in is the line two.
So that's what the pen down.
So we'll say we'll go from 300 to 500 by save that.
And I can see you have a line starts.
We move to three hundred three hundred and then we draw down from 300 to 500.
All right.
So and of course, you know, we can change if we want to do like a diagonal line.
We could change this to two hundred, something like that.
Now, we're not actually going to call these like this.
We want to call those when we have our most move event because it's going to be dynamic.
All right.
One of the thing that I want to do here is the X values and Y values.
I want those to be global as well, because we're going to be, you know, using those in multiple places
and reassigning them.
So I'm just going to initialize X.
We'll just say let X and we'll say let Y.
So they're undefined right now.
All right.
And I think that's good.
So in the next video, what we'll do is start to deal with our most events, like on the mouse move.
We want to be able to.
We want to create our circle and lines and we want to know if the button is pressed or not, too, for
moving because we only want to drive our moses' down.
So we'll get into that stuff in the next video.