OK, so we have a couple of functions here to draw a circle, draw a line, and I'm not calling them
anywhere just yet, but we want to start to deal with our most events.
So ultimately, we want to be able to hold up our most buttoned down and drag and draw based on the
color selected based on the, you know, the line selected or the with whatever you want to call that
the size.
So let's go above our functions here and let's take our canvas.
So we're going to take our canvas and add an event listener and I'm going to listen for a most down
event.
So basically when I click and I hold it down, that'll be a down and we're going to pass in our event
object here.
And I'm going to have another global variable up here and undersize.
And we're going to call this is Prest because we want to know if the mouse is being pressed and that's
going to be false to begin with.
But once we have mouse down, we'll say is pressed is then going to equal.
True.
I also want to get the position of where the mouse is, and that's what these X and Y values are.
So let's set X here to dot offset X and then we'll set Y to idot offset Y, OK?
And that will give us the positioning of where the mouse is.
In fact, I'll go ahead and console log.
Let's log is pressed and let's log X and Y so I'll go over here and I'll open up my console.
Just reload that and you'll see we get true because when I most down it's true.
And then the position where I clicked.
All right, so if I go, if I go up here, I can see it's a very low number.
The top is cut off because of my console.
But you can see if I click all the way over here, it's like one, right?
If I click outside of the canvas, nothing happens.
But if I click right on the edge that said negative zero.
So one, as they go over, you can see that first number climb.
As they go down, you can see the second number climb.
OK, so that's our X and Y positioning and is pressed is true.
Now when we release I want is to be false and I want to clear these values.
So I'm just going to copy this and I want to change this now to mouse up.
So that's on release.
We're going to set is press to false and then we're going to set X and Y just equal to undefined.
So sets that to undefined and will console Lorgat there as well.
So if I go, I'm going to click and hold true and that gives me the positioning I'm going to let go.
I get false and the positioning is undefined.
OK, so that's what I want.
I'm just going to get rid of the console logs because we don't need those anymore.
But now it knows if we're if we're holding it down or if the mouse isn't being pressed.
Now, we want an event for mouse move.
So just copy this real quick and let's set this to mouse move right now.
Mouse move.
We can get the positioning, but we only want any of this to happen if the mouse is being pressed.
So let's do an F here and let's say if is pressed.
Hey, so if that's true, it means we're holding it down, then let's create a variable here called
X2 and set it to the positioning.
So E dot offset X and then do the same thing for Y.
This will be called Y two.
All right.
And we can go ahead and console log this X to and Y to.
And now if I go and I click and hold, you can see the position of wherever my mouse is now instead
of console logging, I actually want to draw.
So I'm going to call, draw circle.
And what's going to go in here is that the position, the X two and the Y two.
Now if we save that, we come over here.
I'm just going to close up the console.
Now, if I click and I hold, what's going to happen is it keeps drawing circles, OK?
So every time I move the mouse, it we get the values of the position.
We passman to draw a circle and it draws a circle.
Now the problem we have is if I go really fast, you can see that there's, you know, spaces in between
the circles and we don't want that.
We want just a straight line no matter what.
So in addition to draw a circle, we're going to draw a line or just copy that down and say draw a line.
Now, this is going to be where we draw the line, but we need that.
We need to add the move to positions as well.
So this move to is the first two arguments passed in which is going to be X and Y.
OK, now if we check it out now, we have this weird effect going on.
And that's because after we do this, we want to set the X value to whatever the current position is
and the Y values and the Y value to whatever, you know, y to is.
So now if I come over and draw.
Hmm.
So what's happening now is the line with is not as wide as the circle because I actually forgot down
here I set line with to the size, so line within the radius of a circle that, you know, there are
two different things.
So if I multiply this by two, it should end up working and being the same.
So now it's just a straight line, OK?
The width of the the radius of the circle or the size of the circle is the same now as the line width
of the line.
So they're both being drawn.
We don't have any of that skipping going on or anything like that.
All right.
So pretty cool.
Cool.
All right.
So in the next video, I want to have these controls work.
I want to be able to change the colour, change the line, the width of the size, I guess, and also
be able to clear it out with this button rather than having to reload.
So we'll do that next.