OK, so this is going to be probably one of the shortest, if not the shortest project in this course,
but we're going to do a couple of cool things with success.
So let's change the title here in our project starter to Connecticut, Connecticut loader, and we're
going to have in our HTML.
Here is a class of kinetic div with a class of like and that's it.
So in our stylesheet here, we don't need to bring in a font because we have no text so we can get rid
of this font family here.
I am going to add a background color.
Let's say background color and we're going to set that to hexadecimal value of two three three five
zero, which will give us this blue background.
And we want to display Fleck's the correct the direction.
I'm going to get rid of the column direction and justify and align to the center.
And then let's do the kinetic class, which I'm going to position this.
I want to position this relative because we're actually going to use the before and after pseudo selectors
to create our triangles and we want to position those absolute within this class.
So this has to be relative.
When you position something absolute and you want an inside of a specific container like this, the
container needs to be relative and then we're going to set the height and the width to 80 pixels.
OK, that's all we need for the kinetic class.
Now we want to do the before and after pseudo selector.
So let's say kinetic coal and coal and after and also kinetic colon colon before.
And we're using both because we're going to have two triangles.
So when you use before and after or before or after, you have to add this content property, which
we're just going to set to an empty string.
We're not actually inserting anything here.
And then we want this to be positioned absolute inside of this relative container.
And then for the position we'll do top zero left zero.
And we want to create a triangle now.
And CSFs, what you can do is create a basically a box with a height and a width of zero, which will
set here.
And then you can set a border to and set whatever with you want.
The bigger the width, the bigger the triangle.
Let's do 50 pixels solid and we want to make this transparent.
OK, so we're not going to be able to see anything just yet.
But what we'll do is on the bottom.
So we'll say border bottom dash color and we're going to set that to white.
As soon as I do that, I see we get a triangle because essentially we have our border bottom, which
is white, but the left one, the left, right and top are transparent.
They're they're they're just transparent.
So if I wanted this to be facing down, I could set this to top color white or I could set top and bottom
to white and give it kind of an hourglass effect.
So it's just just something cool you can do with access.
I just want this to be bottom, though.
All right.
And there's two triangles here on both of these on on before and after.
They're just positioned in the same place.
So we can it just seems like there's one.
Now we want to add an animation, a rotation animation.
So let's set.
Actually, before we do that, let's grab just the before, because the styles of bovver for both before
and after, we want to rotate before so that it's on over here on this side so we can rotate with the
transform property.
So let's say transform and then rotate.
And I want to rotate this 90 degrees.
And that's just the before one, which now is over here.
OK, so we have the before and after triangles.
Now for the animation, we're going to use keyframes.
So let's say keyframes will call this rotate a and for the I guess the time frames here will say zero
percent, 25 percent.
I just want to change.
I want to add the transform here for the rotate and set that to zero.
So it's going to start zero zero degrees.
All right.
So we can start there.
And then for 50 percent and 75 percent, let's set the transform rotates and we're going to set this
to 180 degrees.
And then for one hundred percent are up to 100 percent.
We're going to rotate all the way.
We don't want to do that.
We want to do transform and then rotate.
And this is going to be 360 degrees.
All right, let's put our semicolons here.
All right, so I want to apply this to this here to the before and after, so we apply a keyframe animation
with the animation property and let's say rotate a we want the duration to be two seconds.
It's going to be in a linear fashion.
It's going to be infinite.
So it's going to keep going and then a delay of zero point five seconds.
So that's what it's going to do for now.
And we also want to add a different rotation on the before.
So I'm going to copy this whole thing here.
OK, and basically what's happening is, you know, it starts at zero four, rotate A and then it goes
to 180, so goes from here to here and then 360.
So just does a complete circle.
And then for this one, this is going to be rotate B and I just want to add different values as far
as, you know, how far we're rotating.
So let's do 90 degrees for the first one and then this one is going to be to 70 degrees and then this
one is going to be 450 degrees.
And we want to apply rotate be to this before selecter.
So let's say animation and we want to apply rotate B and make it two seconds, linear and infinite.
All right.
And you might have to reload to because since we're using live server and it should look like this.
So basically one triangle follows the other and you can experiment with it if you want, change up the
rotations and stuff like that.
But that's going to be it for this project.
I know this was a short one, but you could use this as a loader for your website or whatever.
I think it looks pretty cool and it gives you a little bit of experience with some animation and how
to create triangles and sixths or arrows, whatever you want to call them.
All right, that's it.
Let's move on to the next project.