All right, so in this project, we're going to build a content placeholder and you can see this just
looks like an ordinary card, has an image, some text, a user image or an author image and and some
data.
So if I reload or we come to this page, you're going to see this cool gradient animation that loads
in about two and a half seconds and then the content comes in.
So the way that we're going to approach this is we're first going to build out just the card with HTML
access.
Then we're going to create this animation with access using basically just modifying the background
position of a linear gradient.
And then we're going to have JavaScript insert the content and the content will just be hardcoded in
the JavaScript.
But of course you could fetch the data from some kind of API.
All right.
And of course, you could have multiple cards and stuff like that.
So that's it.
Let's go ahead and get into it.