All right, let's get started on our content placeholder project, sort of content placeholder.
Now, the plan here is to just do the HTML and access, have our card, our image card content, and
then create our our animation, like the wave type animation as it loads.
We're going to do that within the access.
And then ultimately the content is going to come from the JavaScript, like the images, the text that's
going to get input from the JavaScript after that little animation.
But for now, we're just going to hardcourt all the content directly in the HTML just so we can get
the card set up.
So let's give this a class of card that will be our wrapper class, no bootstrap or anything like that.
We're going to style the card from scratch.
So we have a card dash header.
And then anywhere where we want to add that the little wave animation, we have this animated dash B.G.
class.
And if it's text, it's also going to have an animated big text class because the text doesn't always
go all the way across the card.
But we want that animation to go all the way across the header.
Isn't just text.
That class will go on like paragraphs, headings and stuff like that.
So this is fine for the for the header.
But I also want to add an idea of header because I'm going to use IDs to grab on to it from the JavaScript.
So we'll have an image in here.
And I'm going to grab just a link to an unsafe image.
So we'll save that.
You see, it's just a laptop.
And for now, this is just going to take up the whole screen.
But we'll fix that when we get into the CSFs now under the header.
So the header ends here.
We want to have our card content and in the card content will have a card dash title.
And I'm going to add the animated animated dash B.G. class here and also the animated dash BGU dash
text, because this is actually going to be an H3.
So let's add H3 right here.
And fix that spelling, animated, big animated big text and also an idea of title and let's just say
Lorem five enter, which just give me five, you know, five dummy text words.
So under the age three, we're going to have a paragraph with the class of Kadesh excerpt.
And I'm also going to give it an idea of excerpt.
And for the paragraph, I'll do Lorem 10.
And still within the paragraph, I want to have three of those animated lines.
So I'm going to have three spans.
So let's say spane class, animated dash B.G. also animated dash BGI dash text and that should do it.
So inside the span, I'm just going to have a non breaking space.
So let's say ampersands nbsp semicolon and then I just want three of these.
I want to copy that down three times.
Good.
And then under the paragraphs these spans I'll be within the paragraph because basically you're going
to see these which are going to be the animated lines before this text loads.
So under the paragraph will have the author class, which is going to be where we have the profile image
and the name and the date.
So first we'll have a class of profile dash img and let's also add animated dash B.G. and it's given
an idea of profile underscore IMG.
So for the image, let's throw this in here and I'm going to use http s random user dot mi slash api
slash
portrait's slash men slash forty five dot jpeg.
Slash.
All right, now, this image here, that's good under the d'Hiv, so we have the profile image Divx,
we're going to go under that still within the author class and let's say author Dasch Info and and here
will have some strong tags.
I'm going to give this the animated class.
So animated B.G. also animated BGU dash text and also an idea of name.
And we'll just say John Doe for the name.
OK, underneath the strong tags will have some small tags with the same animated B.G. animated PG dash
text.
And so let's do an I.D. of dates.
And for the date, I'll say October 8th.
Twenty twenty.
All right.
So that should do it for the HTML.
I just want to make sure I have these classes.
Correct.
So animated big text.
All right, so if I missed something up, we'll come back to it, but I think we're going to stop here
and in the next video, we'll go ahead and start to style the card.