All right, so we're going to get started on the case for this project, so I guess we'll just keep
the Roboto font.
That's fine.
And the body, we're going to add a background.
All right.
Let's do a background color and it's going to be a light gray.
So hexadecimal e, c, f zero, F one.
It's going to be our background and we don't need Flex Direction column.
And this other stuff should be fine.
Now, let's just say for the image, we want that to have a max width of one hundred percent of its
container.
So that's going to shrink up that image.
And then let's start to add the styles for our card.
So the card, I want to give it a box shadow.
So we have our horizontal offsets to zero vertical, two pixels blur 10 pixels and color will be a black
with an opacity of zero point to you see the the outline here.
All right.
Now we want to have some rounded corners on the card.
So I'm going to set the border radius to 10 pixels and let's add overflow and set that to hidden so
nothing comes out of its container.
And then I'm going to have a width of 350 pixels on the card and let's set the card header height.
I want to set that to 200 pixels.
And right now, the text is kind of over the image a little bit.
So let's styled the card header image.
So I'm going to just make sure Object Fit is set to cover and let's set the height to 100 percent of
its container and the width to 100 percent.
So now you can see that the text is no longer over the image.
Now the card content here say card contents.
So I'm going to set the background of that to white sheet.
We'll use background color.
And then I want to just set some padding to move everything away from the sides or do 30 pixels padding.
All right.
Now, the stuff that's in the card card content like the title, let's do that.
So card dash title, I'm going to give that a height of twenty pixels and a margin of zero.
And then the excerpt.
So the excerpt, I'm going to give a color of hexadecimal 777, which is a great color, and then for
the margin, let's do 10 pixels, zero, 20 pixels.
So that's the excerpt now for the author of the wraps around all of this.
So author, I just want to display Fleck's, which automatically puts it into a flex row and then for
the profile image.
So profile dash image, remember, that's the div around the image.
So I am going to set the border radius to 50 percent because I want it to be rounded, although right
now that's on the div and the image is basically popping out of the div.
So we want to make sure we set overflow, we want to set overflow to hidden.
OK, so that'll make it rounded.
We also want to make it much smaller.
So let's set the height to 40 pixels and also the width to 40 pixels.
So now the last thing is the author info, which is around the name and the date.
So let's say author info, which I want to display as a flex box, but I want them to be on top of each
other.
So the flex direction is going to be a column instead of a row.
And then let's take any remaining content.
So justify content to be around each element of space around and let's add a margin left to move it
away from the image.
So 10 pixels that will move the text away.
And let's add a width of, let's say, one hundred pixels.
OK, and then for the small tag, we have author info small.
I just want to change the color to triple J, which is a grey and then add a little margin top.
So five pixels and then we go.
So now our card is styled.
So in the next video I want to create the animation effects and then ultimately this content, the images
in the text are going to come from the JavaScript.