Hey, guys, this project, we're going to create something that's pretty simple, but also something
that's very useful that you see quite a bit, and that's a sticky nav.
So we have this over at the top of our little website here.
We're going to create this hero image with an overlay.
So we're going to style, you know, a little bit of this Web site here.
But the main point is the Navar that sticks to the top.
And when I scroll down and I hit a certain point, you can see that it does a few things.
It changes its color, it changes the text color and it lessens the padding and makes it smaller.
If I go back up to the top, it turns back black and adds that padding.
So we get that nice little effect.
And you see this a lot on different websites.
So we figured that it would be a nice addition to the course and to the projects.
So let's go ahead and get started.