All right, so we're going to start on our sticky nav, and the way I'm going to do this is we'll do
all the e-mail now and then we're going to style the whole rest of the page, including the hero image,
the hero area with the overlay, and then in the next video will style the navigation and add a little
bit of JavaScript that we need in order to give it that effect where it's it's making it active and
not active, depending where we're scrolling on the page.
All right.
So let's start off in our HTML here.
We'll just say sticky navigation for the title.
And down here, first thing we're going to have here is the navigation.
So I'm going to use an HTML5 nav tag and I'm just going to give a class of NAV as well.
And inside there, we want a container class because we don't want all we don't want the logo on this
side and the links on this side to stick to the edges if the browser is too long or too wide.
So we'll settle with a max width of like twelve hundred on the container.
And then inside here we want two things.
One is going to be the one.
I'm just going to give that a class of logo.
Usually you'll have a link around the logo.
Just go to the, you know, this page here and inside here.
I'll just say my Web site, OK, and then under the one we want to have our unordered list with our
list items and our links.
And these aren't actually going to go anywhere.
Let's say home will have for these.
So we'll do home about services.
These are kind of the default pages that we use.
And then I'm going to add a class of active onto home.
So basically we just want a different color link for whatever page you're on.
So if I save that, it's going to look really weird just because of the default styles we have, putting
everything in the middle and so on.
So let's move on under the nav now and we're going to have our hero area.
So let's have a class of hero.
And we also want the container in here because we want to contain the content and let's do an H1.
We'll say welcome to my Web site and then a paragraph and we'll just do Lorem 10 enter to give us ten
words of text.
All right.
Now, under the hero will have a section and the section is going to also use the container class and
also give it a class of content and we'll do an H.
Let's do an H2 here and say content one paragraph.
We'll do Lorem one hundred.
And then under the that paragraph will do, say, an H3 will say contents to obviously this would be
whatever you want on your site.
So we just need something.
So a couple of paragraphs and headings.
Good.
So now what I'm going to do is just comment out the now for now, because I want to style the rest of
the page.
That way we can do everything that we need to with the nav bar in the next video.
So in our stylesheet here, let's go ahead and change in the body.
We don't actually need flaks or anything like that.
So we're going to get rid of all of this, actually.
And then let's just set a color of two, two, two for the text and let's use open sans is a find.
It looks a little nicer.
So success questionmark family set that to open plus Sande's and we'll add that here open sans.
And then I want to add a reset.
So we want to take the margin and padding off of everything that includes the body.
OK, so now there's no margin and padding and then in the body I'm going to add just padding bottom
of 50 pixels just to give some room at the bottom.
All right, now the container.
I'm going to set a max width of twelve hundred pixels and then for the margin, we want zero top and
bottom and then auto on the left and right, which will put it in the middle.
So now if I stretch this so you can see anywhere we use the container, it's going to end right here,
including the NAV, which I just have commented out right now.
All right.
We can make this a little smaller here and here.
Now, the NAV stuff will go here.
But let's just let's just put a to do here, so to do now.
All right.
Now I want to work on the hero area, which is this here.
I want this to take up the full screen right here, all the viewport heights with a background image,
with an overlay.
So let's take the class of hero and let's do a actually let's add let's add the background.
Image first, so the background image is going to be a neutral and I'm just going to grab it.
It's from the pixels dotcom Web site and of course, you could use any image you want here.
And if I say we're only going to see it up to the height of the content so we can't even, you know,
make out the image.
But let's add a height.
Actually, I'm going to make this a little wider.
So let's make the height of this, take up the whole viewport.
So one hundred viewport heights like that right now.
I do want to add some background properties because that doesn't look how I want.
So let's set first of all, we'll do background repeat, set that to no repeat, then we'll do background
size and we'll set that to cover.
OK, as soon as I do that, we can see the whole image and then I'm going to position it.
So background position, we're going to set that to the bottom center.
All right.
And then, yeah, that should do it for the background image.
OK, now the content inside, we want to deal with that, so let's go under the height here.
Let's set the color of this to white and let's display blacks so that we can justify content center
and also we want to align items center.
So it's going to put it right in the middle.
We also want to text a line to the center like that.
And let's add.
Let's see, let's add a position relative, because we're going to be adding an overlay inside of it,
which will be positioned absolute, I also want to just add some margin bottom to push the content below
it down.
So the 20 pixels, so that takes up one hundred viewport heights.
And then when we scroll, we can see the rest of the content.
Now for the overlay, we want to add an overlay because this this image is way too bright.
This is the contrast is not right here.
This is unreadable.
I mean, it's readable, but it's it's not readable enough.
So we could add an extra element in the HTML to add the overlay to.
But what we'll do is use the DB for pseudo selector.
So if we say hero, colon, colon before it, basically kind of you can think of it as adding like a
ghost element to style.
So before and when we use before or after, we have to add content and you can actually store something.
There you can add content like hello, which is right here, so that's getting inserted with the.
Now, we don't want to add any text, so we're going to leave that blank.
And then we want this to be just placed over this entire thing, over the hero.
So we'll position it absolute within the hero, which we positioned relative.
And then once we do that, we want to set the top.
So basically say we're going to start it at the top zero and left zero position and we want it to cover
the entire thing.
So the with hundred percent height, 100 percent.
All right.
And then we could add a background or as background color.
So background color.
Now if I say background, color red, you can see that it adds an entire overlay to that area because
we positioned it relative.
We started it at the top left corner and we had to go total with total height.
Now, obviously, we don't want a solid color like this.
So what we'll do is use our GBA red, green, blue, alpha, and we'll make it black and alpha.
The last value is the transparency or the opacity.
So let's set that to zero point six.
And now you can see we have this overlay.
If I make it higher, like zero point nine, if it's darker, if I do zero point two, it's lighter.
I think six is and I think that looks good.
Or maybe five.
Now, the problem here is that the text is actually behind the overlay.
So the text is darkened, which we don't want.
So I'm going to set a Z index, which is basically how close to you how close to the screen an element
is.
We're going to push this back.
So let's do negative two, which didn't work because I want to set that to negative one and set this
the hero to negative two.
So this is the index.
We'll set that to negative two.
And now you can see it goes the image, the overlay and then the text.
All right.
Now I just want to kind of like make this each one a little bigger and position it better.
So let's do hero H1 and set the font size to forty six pixels and we're going to add the same margin.
So margin.
I want to move it up a bit.
So negative 20 pixels zero and then 20 pixels on the bottom and then for the paragraph.
So hero P let's make the font size twenty pixels and let's make the letter spacing.
Will do.
We'll do one pixel for that.
Pace that looks a little better, and then for the content, we need to separate some of this stuff
out.
So let's say content age two and we also have an H3 in there and let's say font size for this will do
we'll do a percentage.
So hundred and fifty percent for those.
And let's also do margin 10 pixels on the top and bottom.
Separate that out from the paragraph's.
And then for the paragraph's, let's say content P, let's say color five five five.
And the line height can see how the lines are very close together.
So we'll do a line height of 30 pixels and let's do letter spacing of one point five pixels.
So if we take a look at that actuals to one point, that's kind of it's kind of much.
Let's do one point two for that.
All right, and actually, let's do 20 pixels on the headings.
All right, so that's good.
Now for the Navar and let me just show you if I make this bigger.
OK, so that sort of looks like so not much, but it's the start of, you know, 90 percent of the websites
out there, just hero and then some content.
So I'm going to uncommented the NAV.
And as soon as I do that, you'll see that we have it up here completely unstyled.
So in the next video, we're going to go ahead and style the NAV and add a little bit of JavaScript
to dynamically add and remove a class to basically give it that effect that I showed you in the intro.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next video.