OK, so now we want to start on the Navar and I wanted to separate this out because, you know, the
website you're going to use this on in the future will be completely different.
So I want the Navar will be the same.
So I wanted to do that all in one video.
So let's go ahead and grab the nav tag.
OK, so that surrounds everything.
And I'm going to add a position to this, because right now you can see if I scroll it just you know,
it's just in the regular position and I can scroll out, you know, out of it.
So I want to position that fixed to the top as soon as I do that.
Now, no matter where I scroll, it's always going to be up at the top.
Now I'm going to set a background, let's do a background color and I'm going to do two, two, two
for the background color and I'm going to set the top.
So it's going to be zero from the top and zero from both the left and the right, which is going to
make it go all the way across like that, OK?
And then we're going to want to add a transition here, because when we start to scroll, it's going
to change color and it's going to it's going to lessen the padding.
It's going to have that effect.
So we don't want that to just flicker in.
We want that to, you know, to add a smooth transition.
So we'll transition all elements or I'm sorry, all properties that can be transitioned in point three
seconds with an ease in our effect.
All right.
And then let's start to style some of this other stuff.
The container, basically, I want to put, you know, the logo on this side and the well on this side.
So the container is going to be the flex box because the H1 in the U.S. will be the flex items inside
of it.
So if we look at our HTML, if I put the flex on now, then that's going to make the container the flex
item, which I don't want.
So I want this to be the flex box in these two to be the flex item.
So let's go right under that and do now have a container and set that to display flex, which automatically
is going to put the H1 in the U.S. side by side in a row.
And I want to basically take this space here and put it in between these so we can use justify content
space between and that will push that over to the side.
OK, I also want to align some or let's do a line items center which will center it, you know, this
way.
And then let's also add some padding.
Let's do 20 pixels top and bottom for the padding and we'll take care of this these list items in a
minute.
OK, so we have that.
We're also going to add this transition onto the container because we're going to change the padding
value when we scroll and we add the active class.
Now for the U.S., you say NAV, you well, we want these items, the list items to be in a row.
So we'll display flex.
That'll automatically put them into a row.
We want to get rid of any bullet points.
So that's going to be set to none.
And let's line items to the center.
And that should be it will justify the center as well.
And then for the links.
So we have our actually, I, I just use NAV here.
We want to use the class of NAV because you might have a nav somewhere else, you know.
So next is the link.
So let's say class nav Maytag's.
I'm going to set the color to whites and let's get rid of that underline with text decoration none.
And let's spread these out so we'll do a padding of seven pixels, top and bottom, fifteen pixels left
and right that'll, you know, separate them out a bit.
And then I'm also going to add the transition.
I'm going to copy this and put that here as well.
All right, so, I mean, we have a sticky now, nav, pretty much all you have to do is is position
at fixed like this and it'll stick.
But we want to have that effect where when we hit a certain point, it turns white.
And it also has a little bit less padding.
OK, so when you scroll up and down and we'll give it that effect, so we're going to have a class of
active.
All right.
So let's say class now have class active.
So when it's active, I want the background color to be white and we can go ahead and add that right
here manually.
Let's just add active and now you can see it's white so we can at least see it in style it.
And then I'm also going to add let's make the links, the active links black.
So now active a set the color to black.
All right.
And then let's do let's add a box shadow when it's active as well.
So box shadow do for the offsets zero and two pixels, 10 pixel blur, Rajiva Black and zero point three
is just a little bit of box shadow.
Now the container, when it's active, I want to have less padding.
It has 20 to begin with.
So what I'll do is grab that.
And right here, let's say nav
active.
So the active nav container, I'm going to change it from twenty to ten pixels, right?
Now, if I say we can see it's skinnier and then I just want to have the hover, I want it to be ratified,
hover or if or if the link has a class of active.
In fact, maybe we should call it something different because we call this active so we can call it
current.
And then what we'll do is say NAV, if the A tag has a class of current or the nav a is being covered,
then let's make the color of this hexadecimal see zero three nine to be, which is a red color and we'll
make the font weight make that bold.
All right.
If I say we can see the current link, is that red color and if I hover, it's that red color and that's
going to be whether the Navar is white or black, active or not.
So I'm going to remove the active class on the NAV now goes back to being black.
So what the JavaScript is going to be used for is when we hit a certain point, when we scroll, we
want it to turn into the active nav bar.
Right.
So let's go to our JavaScript here.
And this isn't going to be difficult.
We're going to bring in our NAV.
So let's say Korn's now equals document dot query selector and will select it by the class of NAV.
And then we want to add on the window in event listener and we want to listen for a scroll.
And when we scroll, we're going to call a function called fixed nav.
OK, so down here, let's say function Fixx NAV loops no space.
So function fixed nav.
And we want to check the the scroll points.
So I'm just going to do a console log here of window dots and then scroll y because we're using we're
talking about the Y axis which is vertical.
So I'm going to open this up and as I scroll you can see it's going to give me that value.
And I also want to see the NAV element and check its offset height.
So if I scroll, you can see that the nav bars offset high.
It's seventy three and it's always going to it's going to stay seventy three.
But what we'll do, I want to figure out a point where we want to actually turn this into the active,
the active nav bar.
So what I'll do is actually do an if statement here.
So let's say if and we'll say if the scroll y position is greater than the nav offset height and we'll
just add one fifty to that.
So that's going to bring it down, you know, to to this area.
So if that's true, then let's take the nav and add the class.
So classless dot ad of active.
Right.
So we want to add active and else.
So if it's not if it's less than that then we want to remove the class.
So we'll just copy.
That and instead of ad, we're going to remove, all right, so I'll save that and now I'll start to
scroll.
And as soon as I hit this point where this is true, where it's the scroll, why value is greater than
the offset height plus one 150, then it turns to active.
OK, so it's going to take this height plus one, you know, 150.
So right around this point right here, OK, it's going to turn and if we go back up, it goes back
to normal.
So you see this effect a lot on Web sites and there's no need for Junqueira.
There's no need for any extra library.
It's very, very simple.
So you can use this for, you know, your Web sites and user interfaces from now on.
So that's it.
Hopefully this helps you out and, you know, gives you something you can use in the future.
And that's it.
Thanks for watching.
I'll see you in the next project.