All right, welcome to your next project.
So in this one, we're going to build a vertical slider.
Basically, we have an image on the side and we have some text on this side.
And this could be any kind of content you want.
And then these two arrows here, if I click the up, what's going to happen is one side goes up, one
side goes down, but it brings into place the correct text area and the correct image.
So go up again.
Up again.
So we have four different sides.
If I click up again, it just goes back to the beginning.
Same with down.
So then it just goes the opposite way, so I think it's a it's a really cool looking slider.
It's not really responsive if we make this smaller, you can see it doesn't really look good on smaller
screens just because of the orientation of it.
But that's not really the point here.
This is this is made for, you know, a desktop, laptop, et cetera.
If you wanted to, you could go on and try to maybe switch the orientation on smaller screens.
But we're going to go ahead and build this out.
I think it's a really cool looking project.
So let's get started.