We're going to get started on our vertical slide.
And I have my browser window quite wide because this isn't really responsive just because of the orientation
of the how the slider is.
So it's not going to look good on like a smartphone or anything like that.
That's not really what this is geared for.
So I'm going to just keep this a little wider and just click back and forth for now in our HTML, we
just have a product project starter and I have a link to the font awesome CDN because we will be using
icons for the buttons.
So let's start off here and change this to vertical slider and then we're going to have a container
that wraps around everything.
So let's give this div a class of slider dash container and there's basically three three separate parts.
First we have the left dash slide.
So this is going to be the text area.
So we'll have an H1 and a paragraph and then the right slide and I'll fill this fill this in in a little
bit.
But the right slide is going to be the images.
Right?
So they're just basically it's going to be digits background images.
And then underneath that, we want our buttons.
So let's say action dash buttons.
And our first button here is going to have a class of down dash button and I'm going to use font awesome
icon.
So Fayaz And we want a dash arrow dash down.
OK, so go ahead and save that weight.
Is that right now Faez space.
Narrowed down and then for the up arrow, we'll just take this button, copy it down, and we'll change
this to up and change this icon to up.
And now we have our buttons.
So for the left side, let's go into that div and we're just going to have a bunch of divs with in each
one.
So for this one will say nature flower and a paragraph will say all in pink.
And then each div is going to have an inline style with a background color.
So that way when you want to add new slides or new divs, you just throw the background color in here
rather than creating a whole separate class for it.
So let's say background color and we'll make it F.D. three five five five.
So I save it.
We're going to see that now.
We're going to have three more of these, which I'm just going to paste in because it's the same thing.
It's just different colors and content.
So if I save that, you can see what we have here now for the right slide is going to be just a bunch
of background images.
So I'm going to grab that.
And I'm just using links to splash images, just to stock images.
So you can see we have a div with a background image, you URL and we have for these.
Now, if I save, we're not going to see these right now because we don't have any content within the
div and there's no height or with applied to to the element.
So we're not going to see the images just yet.
Now one thing I want to mention is because of the way the slides, one side goes up, one side goes
down, we have this first div, this nature flower is actually going to go with the last image div here.
All right.
So if I look at this last image, I'm just going to copy that you URL and paste that and you can see
that's the pink flower.
So the way you would do this, if you want to add more, is if you add one on to the end here, you're
going to add one on to the beginning here.
OK, see the beat.
The last one here is Flying Eagle.
And if we take a look at this, we get the Flying Eagle.
So that's the order of the elements.
So now let's jump into our success and let's get started here.
So as far as the font goes, I'm going to use open sans.
So let's say family equals open plus sans and we're going to change this to open Sans, OK, and I can
make this smaller here, so make that smaller and make this a little smaller for now.
Now the body we actually don't need all this stuff like display flex.
I just want the, the font family and I want the height to be 100 viewport heights.
So it's going to go like that right now.
And I want to just set a reset on the margin and padding.
So for the universal selector will set margin padding to zero.
That's going to remove the margin and padding from everything.
Now, as far as the slider container goes, which is wrapped around everything.
So the slider container, I'm going to set the position to relative, because we're going to be setting
everything inside of it as absolute within that container and then just set in the overflow to hidden
and set the width to 100 viewport widths.
So VW, which will take the hole with and same with the height.
This is going to be vague.
Report heights.
All right.
And then we'll go ahead and start on the left slide.
So for the left side, I want to set the height to 100 percent and let's set the clock.
Let's do the width first.
So the width is going to be 35 percent of the container.
OK, the image part is going to be a little bigger, it's the image power will be 65 percent and we're
going to position this absolute and from the top zero, from the left zero.
And then what we want to do is target the immediate division side, which are each of these here.
So let's say left slide, immediate div.
And I want to set for that the height, for I want the height to be the entire thing, so one of these
should take up the entire height.
So there will be 100 to 100 percent and then width will be 100 percent.
But it's 100 percent of its container, which is 35 percent.
So if I save that now, we can see this nature flower and it takes up the entire height here.
And when we add the slide functionality, it'll show the next one.
Now, we want to style this a little better.
So let's display flex so each div will be display flex.
Now it's in a row right now.
That's why it's it's it's horizontal.
So we want to change the flex direction to a column and then we can align both horizontally and vertically.
So align center line item center and then let's justify content center and that'll align it that way.
And then let's also make the color white.
OK, and then let's grab the H1, so left slide H1 and let's set the font size to be a little bigger.
We're going to set that to 40 pixels and we'll add a little bit of margin bottom because remember,
we took the margin off of everything, 10 pixels to separate it from the paragraph part.
And then I just want to move it up a little bit.
So margin top offset a negative margin, 30 pixels, which will pull it up a little bit.
All right, so that's the left slide now, the right slide, right slide and the set, the height to
100 percent on that position, absolute from the top zero and then from the left, I'm going to go thirty
five percent because this with this thirty five percent.
So for the right slide, I'm positioning an absolute within the container.
So I want to start it here, which would be 35 percent over from the left.
All right.
And then we want to set the width of it to sixty five percent.
OK, and then.
To actually show the image, let's target the device, so Rightside directive and I just want to set
some background properties like background repeat so that no repeat, we already have the background
image set in line.
Right.
That's already set right here.
So I just want to add some other background properties like the size.
So what's the background?
Size is going to be cover.
I want to show the whole image and then background position is going to be centered on the X and Y axis.
We still can't see it because we need to apply a height to it.
So height and width are going to both be 100 percent.
So it takes up the whole part there.
And now we can see the image.
Now, this isn't the image that we actually want to show with this nature flower.
But like I said, since the way that we're sliding them in, when we get to our JavaScript, we're going
to set it so that this is the right text or the right left slide for this image.
But for now, let's go ahead and style our buttons.
So we're going to have some general button styles.
But before we do that, I just want to target the slider container action, what I call it action,
dash, Fortin's and Button.
And I mean, we could put the general styling in here as well.
But just in case you wanted to add other buttons somewhere.
So this is going to be positioned absolutes.
And as soon as I do that, you can see up here now there's there's two buttons here, but they're both
in the same exact spot right now.
I'm going to move both to a position of left 35 percent.
OK, so it's going to push them over and then let's go from the top will go down about halfway, we'll
say 50 percent down.
So now both buttons are right here and we want to make sure they're always on top.
So let's do a Z index of one.
All right.
And then for the down button.
So let's grab this here and say class down dash button.
I'm going to set a border, actually, let's let's position it first so we can use, transform and then
translate on the x axis, because what I want to do is move this button over this way to the left.
So if we put a positive number in here, I'm going to just do 100 percent of the element.
It's going to move it over to the left, which I don't want.
I want it over to the right.
So that's going to be I'm sorry.
That's going to move it to the right.
I want it to the left.
So that's going to be negative.
So now it's on either side of this line right here.
All right.
And then as far as the borders go.
Actually, you know what, we'll do that in a second, let's first do the up button, so this one is
going to be a button and we want to actually move this one down.
So we're going to do translate.
Why?
I'm sorry.
Now move it down.
Move it up.
This one here, I want to move up one hundred percent, so we'll do negative one hundred percent.
So now you can see the positioning of these arrows now for the styling.
So the general button styling.
Let's go up here to button and let's set a background color of white and let's get rid of the border.
So border none and let's make the color a gray will do triple J and let's make the cursor a pointer.
Let's make the font size a little bigger.
We'll do sixteen pixels, let's do padding fifteen pixels all the way around.
OK, so you can see it looks a little nicer and on hover it's a button however said the color to two
to two just a little darker and we don't want any outline.
So any button in the focus state we want to set the outline to none.
All right.
Now if we hover over, it gets darker.
I do want to have some rounded corners on the bottom for this one and for the top for this one.
So down where we have these down and up buttons, let's just add on the down button.
We'll say border.
We're going to say border.
This is the down button.
So let's do top top left radius and set that to five pixels so you can see that this has the rounded
corners here.
And then we're going to do bottom left radius.
So now this side is rounded.
I want to do the same on this one, but the opposite side.
So I'll just copy that.
And instead of left, let's take this and this.
Change that to right.
I said, now, those buttons look pretty good, OK, and it's obviously this doesn't do anything yet
because we need to add our JavaScript, so that's what we're going to do in the next video.