OK, so now we're going to start on the JavaScript to get this to function and slide.
So in our script, yes, I'm going to go ahead and bring everything that we need in.
So let's bring in our slider container and we're going to use document, dot, query, selector and
select by the class of slider dash container.
And then we're going to bring in a couple other things.
So this is going to be the right slide.
So class of right Dasch slide.
And for the variable here, we'll call this slide.
Right.
And then we're also going to have slide left and that's going to have that has the class of left to
slide.
All right.
Then we also want the buttons.
So we have the up button up dash button and we have the down dash button.
And let's call this one up button.
Down button, and then I also want to get the length of the slides, meaning how many slides do we have?
So let's say slides length and we'll set this to query selecter, all because what we're selecting is
all the divs.
And we actually don't want all the divs in the document.
We want all the divs that are in the slide.
Right.
OK, so basically all those divs with the background images.
So in here we want to query selector all the dishes that will give us all the elements, but we just
need the length.
So we'll use the length property here and that will give us it will give us four in this case if I can.
So log slides length and me go over here and open this up.
You can see that we get four.
OK, so you'll be able to add more or less slides if you want.
Now we want to have an active slide index because basically these are positioned to be like on top of
each other.
We need to know which index is basically in view.
So let's say active slide index.
Make sure use let here and we'll set that to zero to start with.
And let's take the slide left, OK?
And then we're going to add a style and we want to apply the top and set that to a set of tactics.
And we want to do negative because this is actually going to go up and the initial top value is going
to be negative and then put in our our expression syntax here and then some parentheses.
And we want to take the slide length and subtract by one because the length is going to be for.
However, the index is zero based, so the index will be like zero one to three, even though this four
total, it starts at zero.
So we want to get the last index, which in this case would be three, which would be the fourth slide,
OK, because arrays are no lists, they're zero based.
And then we want to multiply that by 100 because it takes up one hundred percent or 100 viewport heights.
So let's add here, vich.
All right.
Now, if I save that and I go back, I noticed that this has moved to the correct position.
So Flying Eagle actually goes with this image here.
Now we just want to add functionality so we can, you know, flick these up and down.
One side will go up, one side will go down, and it should bring the correct slides into place.
So let's take the up button and let's call an add an event listener for a click.
And when that happens, we're going to run.
We'll call this function change slide and we will pass in an argument of OP, OK, and then I'm going
to copy this down and then this one is going to call down and this is going to be on the down button.
So let's change this here to down button.
So they're both going to call the same function.
They're just going to get passed in a different argument.
So let's create our function.
We'll use an arrow.
So we'll say change slide equals and it's going to take in a direction as a parameter.
And then let's get the slider height.
So we'll say conse slider height, and that's going to be the slider container.
And then there's a property called client height, OK, which will give us just that.
In fact, we can console log so you can see what that gives us slider height.
And if I go over here and I click the button we get six, six, six.
Is that a bad sign.
Let's click up again.
Five seven seven.
So it's based on whatever, you know, whatever the height is here and it's it's going to be completely
dynamic.
Doesn't matter how, you know, high or small it is.
So that will give us the slope, whatever the slider height is.
Now, let's check for the direction that's being passed in.
If the direction is, let's say, equal to up, then what we're going to want to do is take the active
index, active slide index and increment that by one.
So plus plus and then we want to know what happens if we hit the end.
So let's say if the active slide index happens to be greater than the last the last index in the slide,
which we can get with slide length oops, slide slide length.
But we want to take away one.
From that, so if that's true, then we'll set the active slide index to zero to back to the beginning.
So basically, if we get to the end, we're going to go back to the beginning.
All right.
Now, if I click on up, you can see nothing is happening yet because we need to add a transform.
We need to translate it on the Y axis, basically move it up and down.
So down here, after the if I'm going to take the slide, we're going to have to move both slide left
and slide right.
So let's take the right slide right.
And set the style dot transform and we want to translate the Y on the Y axis.
So translate why.
And what we want to pass in here is negative because we want the right side to go up and then our expression
syntax, we want the active slide index multiplied, whatever the slider height is, because remember
the slider height is variable and then we just want to add pixels on to it.
So if I save that, I go over here and I click up.
Nothing happens.
Let's see, slide length is not defined.
Slide length is not defined.
Oh, it slides length, plural.
All right, so let's try that and then we go so you can see that it switches.
Now, if I do it and it's at a certain height and then the height changes, you can see it kind of bleeds
over.
If I click it again, it's going to then recalculate the height based on this right here, OK, which
we put in to this variable which we're using down here.
Now, I want it to actually have a smooth transition rather than just flicking over.
So let's go back to our style sheet and let's see.
We want to go on both the left and right slides.
So let's go up to the left slide here and let's add a transition.
So we want to transition the transform property, which is what we're changing in our JavaScript.
And we'll do a point five seconds and ease in out.
And then I want to do the same thing for.
Right.
So right here, we'll add that as well.
And let's see what happens here.
All right.
So now you can see it has that transition.
And when we get to the end, it just goes back to the beginning.
OK, so now we want the same for this side, because right now we're just switching the images.
This is staying the same.
So let's grab this here and paste that.
And then we want to say slide left and change the the transform value translate why?
And we just want to make this positive because we want it to go the other way.
Right.
So active slide index times slide or height pixels.
So now if I click up.
There we go.
All right, so it just goes the opposite way now, the down button doesn't do anything.
So up here where we have this, if direction is up, let's go right now.
Let's put an elsea.
Actually, let's do an else.
If so else, if the direction is equal to down, then we're basically going to do something similar
to what we did here.
So we can copy that, but we want to decrement that.
So minus minus will take away one and we want to check to see if we're at the beginning.
So if this is going to be less than zero, so if that's going to be less than zero, then we're going
to set it to the last slide in the index, which is going to be whatever the slides length is, minus
one, because the length for us at least is four.
But the last index would be three because it's zero.
One, two, three is the indexes.
So let's save that.
And now if we click down.
There you go, and it should always match up with the correct you know, the correct text with the correct
image.
All right, so that's it.
Hopefully you enjoyed this project.
I think it's a pretty cool looking slider.
So that's it.
I'll see you in the next project.