All right, so this is going to be a pretty simple project, but I think it's useful because there's
a lot of times when you need to notify a user of something, whether it's an error or just like a little
info block, and you'll often see these tost notifications.
So something that will pop up in sometimes it's up in the corner here, sometimes it's down here.
Or you could put it in the middle wherever you want, really.
And you can see that it actually disappears after a few seconds because you don't want him to just stay
there.
And we can have multiple notifications because maybe multiple things happened and then they all just
go away after a certain amount of time.
Now we're going to make it fun and just randomize the messages and the types.
You'll see that some of them have different colors.
So like green is success, red is ever purple is info.
So we're going to randomize those.
But I'm also going to show you how you can add a specific message and a specific type.
And you could use this in like form validation or something like that.
All right.
So that's it.
Let's go ahead and get into it.