OK, so this is going to be a pretty quick project, we should be able to get it done in one video pretty
quickly.
So let's change the title here to toast notification.
And then down here, the way this is going to work is we'll have an idea with the idea of toasts.
And I want to be able to have multiple toasts.
So basically, you know, one can show up and then another can show on top of it, another on top of
it, and then they'll just disappear after whatever, three seconds.
So we'll have an idea of toasts, which we'll put right in the HTML.
And then the divs with the class of toast like this will actually get inserted via JavaScript.
But just for now, we'll go ahead and, you know, put some in here.
So we'll say hello world and we'll say toast number two.
And then I want to button give it a class of B10 and then let's give us an idea of button and just say
show notification.
All right.
So, I mean, we're just going to have it.
So we click the button.
It shows a random message.
But of course, you could do form validation or any kind of of, you know, any time you want to notify
the user of something, you could use this.
So let's do the styling.
The the font that I that we're going to use is Poppins, Floren Pop's favorite font.
And then wait 200, 400.
Add that here.
And a set of background color.
So background color.
We're going to set that to Rebecca Purple and we can just leave the rest of this stuff in the body and
let's style the button so we have a class of BTN going to give it a background color of white and give
it a color hopes.
That's fine.
Give it a color of Rebecca Purple and then let's give it a font family.
We want to inherit Poppins and then font weight is going to be bold and padding.
I'm going to add one REM and border radius.
Let's do five pixels and get rid of the border.
So border nun and cursor, we want that to be a pointer.
And then for the outline here, let's get rid of that, so the button focus state, we're going to set
the outline to none and then the active state.
So when we click it, I just wanted to scale down a little bit.
So set transform scale from one two point nine, eight cases are button.
And then let's start to let's do the toast.
So we have toast, plural, which is the container, and we want this to display fixed down in the bottom
corner and then we want to style each toast.
So let's start with the idea of Tostes that I give it an ID or class.
Yeah.
And I gave it an idea.
I mean, you could use a class if you if you want if you don't like styling with the ID.
But I'm not going to use the ID here.
And let's display first of all, position it.
So position this to be fixed and I want it in the bottom corner so we'll say from the bottom ten pixels
and from the right ten pixels.
And of course you could put this up but you could put them up at the top over here wherever you want.
But I want to put it in the bottom here and then let's do display flex.
And I don't want it to be a row.
I do want them to be on top of each other.
So we'll do Flex Direction column.
And I want to align to the end so we'll align items to flex and.
And that should be good for the for the container, so now let's style each individual toast.
So for that, let's set the background color to whites and we'll set the color to Rebecca Purple and
the border radius to five pixels and padding.
We're going to do one room, top and bottom to room, left and right, and let's separate them out.
So margin will be zero point five REM.
All right.
And obviously, you can style these however you want, but I think that's all right.
So now let's take these out of the HTML because these will be inserted with JavaScript.
So basically you would have, you know, your Web page or form whatever it is, and then you'd have
this just somewhere on the page so that your toes can display and its display.
I'm sorry.
It's positioned fixed.
So it's always going to be, you know, at the bottom corner or wherever you decide to put it.
So in our script here, let's bring in the button so we can add in the event listener on it.
So Button set that to document dot get element vidi.
And we gave that an idea of button.
Let's also bring in the container or Tostes.
OK, and then I'm just going to have an array of random messages here, so I'm just going to do message
one, two, three and four.
I mean, we don't have to do this, I can't count, we don't have to do this.
We could just have like an argument, a message passed and as an argument.
But this just makes it a little bit more fun.
So we have an array of just random messages.
Now we want to take our button and we want to add an event.
Listener, listen for a click.
And run a function here and let's call a function called create notification, if you want to leave
at any time, pause the video and do this.
Just try to do this yourself without any guidance.
I would invite you to do that.
So let's create create notification.
And inside here, let's just make sure this is working.
So I'm just going to console log one, two, three and see console good.
So that we know that's working now in here.
We want to create the notification div because remember it's going to be a div with the class of toast.
So let's say consed we'll call this note if said it to on the document object, we have a method called
create element to create any kind of HTML element we want, we want this to be a div and then we want
to add a class to that.
So let's say notify DOT class list add and we're going to add tost class of toast.
We also need to decide what we want to put inside the div as the text is the message so we can say notify
DOT in our text and you could set this to anything you want.
He could just put a string here.
Or you could you could have it come in as an argument.
We're going to have a separate function called get random message, which I'll go outside of this function
now and create.
And it's pretty simple.
So we just want to we have our array up here.
So let's just return from this function messages, which is our array with with a random index.
So, you know, we can do zero one, whatever.
So let's do math dot floor to round down math, dot random.
So that'll give us a random decimal.
We want to multiply that by messages at length so that the you know, however many elements or items
are in the messages array.
So it'll give us a random message.
And then to put it into the dorm, we're going to take the container ships, take the container and
let's append why it's doing that.
I bring in the container.
Oh, I called it Tostes.
That's right.
So Tostes, which is basically the toast container we're going to append child and we want to append
into that the notification.
All right.
So if I see that I come over here and I click, I see message to message one, message three.
So it's just going to be random and they just keep adding up.
Now, obviously, you're not going to want that.
You don't want them to stay there.
There's a few things you could do, you could put like an X button so you can close it up, but we're
just going to make it disappear after a certain amount of time.
So after the the toast is put into the dorm, we're going to run a set time out, which takes in a function.
And we just want to remove it from the dorm completely, so we'll take our notification and remove or
just remove it from the dorm now set time out takes a second argument of the time that you want to wait
until you run the function.
So we're going to wait 300 milliseconds, which is three seconds.
So if I save that and I click show notification a few times after three seconds, the first one goes,
you know, then the second, third.
So even if there is a bunch of messages, they're all going to disappear, which is what we want.
Now, in reality, you're probably not going to do like a random message.
You want a specific message when you call this function.
So what we could do is pass in something like this.
This is invalid data or something like that.
And then we could pass in here as an as a parameter, a message.
And what we'll do is set that to null by default so that down here in the inner text, we can say if
message, then show the message or else get a random message.
So now if I click show notification, it's going to give us this is invalid data because that's what
we passed in here.
And you would probably you know, you would only call this once and we could also and I'm just kind
of just winging it here.
I didn't plan on doing this.
But just to give you a better idea of how you would actually do this, because you wouldn't actually
do random messages, I don't think.
But we could do a type as well, like pass in a type which will just set to null by default.
And a type could be like a CSFs class.
So we could actually copy that down.
And let's say add.
So we'll do say if there's a type, then add that type as a class else, then else then I guess set
it to like info and then we could go on our success and we could say tost dot info.
So it should be a class.
So tost info pops and we could take the color up here.
And no, I don't want to duplicate it, I want to bring it down into here.
So that'll be the info and then we'll take that.
Let's do a success class and we'll make that green and we could take those who could take this one here
and call this error and make that red.
So right now, if I see this, it's going to it's going to be purple.
It should have a class of info.
But if I were to add in here a type of, let's say, success.
Now they're green, so we have the ability to do that, another thing we could do is just for fun is
have some random types, just like we did with the messages.
So we'll see CONSE types and we'll set that to an array and let's say info
success.
And it was the other one error.
And we could create a function just like this to get random, get a random type and just take from the
types array of random random item.
Actually, one thing we want to do is make sure that when we get the types we use, the types, the
length here, or else it's going to be because there's more messages and types.
And then where we have this ternary where we're saying, you know, if there is a type and use that,
if not use enfolds change info to get random type.
Now at the moment we have this is invalid data and success.
Pastan, which actually doesn't make sense.
That should probably be error because that's that's an error.
But if we take out both of these and we just call create notification, then everything's random.
So the message is random and the class or the type is also random.
All right, so, I mean, the random stuff is it's just for fun, but you can see what how you would
actually add this in your application.
If you wanted to add these little tost messages, maybe you'd have some kind of form validation.
And, you know, if you're if the name isn't included or whatever, you could go ahead and run create
notification with a specific type and message.
All right.
So that's it, guys.
Hopefully you enjoyed this little project and we'll jump into the next one.