All right, guys, so we're going to do quite a bit in this project.
We're going to use the GitHub API to fetch users.
We're going to able to search for GitHub users to get some of their profile data and display it in a
card.
And we're also going to make a separate request to get the user's latest five repositories, or however,
however many want to add, to add to the card.
So to give you an example here, I can search for a user.
I'll go ahead and search for myself and you'll see that my avatar pops up my name, my bio followers,
following my latest five repost.
If I search for Floren Pop 17, you'll see the pull heads up.
So, of course you can search for your own.
And if I search for just something that isn't going to be a name, it'll say there's no profile with
this username.
So we'll do a little bit of error handling as well.
So these are the docs for the GitHub rest API.
This is the newer version of the docs.
And you can basically see, you know, how you can fetch users and what kind of data you get.
And then the other thing we're going to do is use Axios instead of the fetch API.
So Axios is a library.
It's a promise based HDB client library for the browser and no Ge'ez.
So I prefer Axios personally when I do any kind of larger or medium size to larger projects, I'll use
axios.
It has better features.
In my opinion.
It's easier to use the error handling is better, so I definitely prefer it.
So I did want to add it to at least one of the projects in this course and we'll be using it with a
sink away.
But I'll show you how to use it just with regular, you know, then syntax as well.
So that's what we'll be building.
Guys, hopefully you enjoy this project.
Let's go ahead and get into it.