OK, so it started on our HTML and most of the stuff that we're going to do right now, the card with
the user info inside of it, that's going to ultimately come from JavaScript with the dynamic data from
the API after we fetch it.
But for now, I'm just going to just type out the HTML, just hardcoded so we can at least see it and
style it.
All right.
So for the title here, it's a GitHub profiles and then down here let's create a form.
And this form is going to have a class of user form and it's going to have an idea of form.
We don't need an action.
OK, and then inside this form, we're going to have a single input and give it an idea of search and
let's add a placeholder.
And for the placeholder, we'll say search a GitHub user, save that.
We have an input here and I'm not going to put a submit button.
We're just going to type the user in and enter.
You can add a submit button if you want, and then let's go underneath the form and we're going to use
the HTML five main tag and give us an idea of Maine.
Now, ultimately, this is all we're going to have in our HTML.
Whatever the card, the user profile card is going to get inserted in here by the JavaScript.
But like I said, for now, we're just going to type it out so we can see it in style it.
So we want a class of card and in that class will have a div with an image inside with a class of avatar.
And I'm just going to put up a dummy image from the random user API.
So we'll say random user dot me slash API slash portrait's slash and I'm just going to use men slash
30 dot jpeg.
Now that you just give us a random user of some guy now under the stiv here.
So card we're going to use flex box to align it.
This will be the first flexitime and then we'll have another div with the class of user info with all
the user's info such as the user name which will put in an H2.
For now I'm just going to say John Doe and then a bio which right now just do LAAM 10, some dummy text
in there and then under the paragraph, under the bio we want a little and let's do a list item.
So this will be like the number of followers, we'll say three hundred and then put some strong tags
in and say followers and I'm just going to copy that down twice.
This one here is going to be following the following will say one hundred and then this will be the
number of repos, say thirty three posts and then under the rule will have the actual repositories of
the user.
We're going to get the latest five repositories.
So let's have an idea of repose here.
And then each one is just going to be a link with the class of repos and then the text they'll just
say Rebo one and we'll just do three.
And that's it for the HTML.
So it's going to look like this so far.
So let's start to style this as far as the eye can make this smaller.
Now, as far as the font goes, we're going to use a font called Poppins.
So I'm going to just replace Raboteau with Poppins and the wait, let's do two hundred and four hundred
and change the family down here to Poppins.
OK, and then let's see, we're going to add a background color.
What else do we want to use hexadecimal value to a two and then a seven two, so it's a dark blue and
then we'll make the color of the text white.
All right.
And then let's see for this stuff.
This is all good.
Yeah, we'll just keep the rest of the body stuff here.
So the user form.
For that, I want to just set the set a width of one hundred percent so it goes all the way across its
container and this is the form, not the input.
And then I'm going to set a max width of 700 pixels.
All right.
And then for the input, experts say user form input.
What set the width of that to be 100 percent?
And we want to style this to look a lot better.
I'm going to also display it as a block level elements and then let's set a background color to the
input.
And that's going to be for C two eight eight five.
So like a purplish color, let's take away the border.
So say border none.
And let's set a border radius and we'll do 10 pixels on that.
OK, let's make the color white.
And let's make the let's give it some padding, so I'm just I'm going to use Rhim units here.
So one room, which is just a multiplier of the root HTML element, which by default is 16 pixels.
So we're just saying padding 16 pixels right now.
All right.
And then I just want to add a margin bottom for that I'm going to use to RAM, which in this case will
be 32 pixels.
And let's set the font family to inherit and let's set the font size to be bigger than that.
I'm just going to set it to one ram.
And let's add a box shadow or a couple of box shadows, and I'm just going to pace this in.
OK, so our first shadow here with the offsets, the blur and the color.
And then we have our second shadow here.
All right.
And then if I click inside of it, we get this outline, which I don't want to keep.
So let's use our dash form input and then Colen focus and then we want to set the outline to none.
All right.
And let's also make the placeholder white.
So if you want to change the color of a placeholder, we can say user form input and then Kalanchoe
and placeholder and let's say color and we'll set that to hexadecimal triple B, so make it a little
lighter.
All right, now let's work on the card, which is around all of the rest of this.
So class card.
And for this let's set a max width of 800 pixels and we are going to make this responsive as well.
And then the background color.
Let's set that to four C two eight eight five.
So it's the same as the input background.
And let's set the border radius to 20 pixels.
All right, and then let's add a box shadow for this as well, so I'm actually going to copy this.
OK, we're going to use the same box shadow is that.
Good.
And then after that, let's display everything as a floral display.
This is a flex box.
So the two items inside are the image, the div with the image and then the user info div that has everything
else in it.
So I'm going to set padding on the card to three ram and let's set margin to zero top and bottom.
Let's do one point five ram on the left and right.
So that pushes it in a little bit.
All right.
So it doesn't go any further than that.
And we will add a media query to kind of stack those rows.
I'm sorry, those columns as well.
But let's go ahead and work on the avatar so we have a class of avatar.
I want this to be rounded with a border.
So set the border radius to 50 percent and then let's set the border.
Going to give it a quite thick border, 10 pixels solid, and then the color will be to a to a seven
to and let's give it a height of 150 pixels and we'll do a width of 150 as well.
And now we have the user info, which is all of this over here.
So let's take the user info class and I'm going to set the color of the text to triple E.
And just add a little bit of margin left to bring it away from the image, so I'm going to use to ram
units here, so push that away, the H2.
So user info H2, we're going to get rid of any margin on the top.
So margin top zero and for the U.S. to.
For the URL, I'm going to display flaks, and this is this right here, so I'm going to display Flex
and actually let's take away any bullet points or style type.
We're going to set that to none and then display flex and the we want to justify the content.
So this is the horizontal spacing.
We're going to set the space between the elements like that and just get rid of any padding.
And let's set a max width on this to 400 pixels now for the list item.
So these right here, let's grab this and say for the allies, I'm going to display flaks.
And also I want to just align items to center on the cross access.
And then for the strong tag, the number is right next to the text here.
So let's grab actually, we'll just grab this and save for the strong tags.
I'm going to set the font size to zero point nine REM and then let's also move it over a bit.
So the margin left.
I'll use zero point five REM.
All right, good.
Now, the repos down here, obviously you need to style those.
So let's take the class of repo.
So all all of those links have a class of rebo.
Let's get rid of the underlying subtext decoration.
None.
And let's set the color of these two white.
And I'm also going to set a background color to to a to a seven to oops and what happened there and
why.
Why isn't this working?
Oh yeah.
These should be rebo.
All right.
So we have our background color.
Let's do font size and font size.
I'm going to stick to zero point seven REM.
So make those smaller and then let's add some padding and you don't have to use REM units.
I just we just wanted to kind of change things up a bit.
So we're going to do point to five REM top and bottom and then zero point five REM left and right.
OK, and then let's set the margin or set margin right to zero point five REM and let's do margin bottom
zero point five REM, just in case the Repos go on to the next line and think that's it.
Let's display as an inline block instead of inline and ultimately you'll be able to click on these and
go to the the Repos.
But that's pretty much it.
Now, I do want to make this more responsive because, you know, if it's on really small screens,
it's going to look kind of weird.
So I'm just going to add a media query here so we'll see media with the max width of I'm going to do
500 pixels.
So if it's under 500 pixels, let's take the card.
And it's displayed flex, but it's a flex row, meaning it goes horizontal.
Let's change the flex direction to a column.
If I do that, it's going to put the two elements, the two flex items on top of each other.
And then let's just align to the middle so we can align items to the center.
OK, so that looks pretty good.
And the form let's take the user form.
And initially I think it has a max width of 800 pixels.
So I'm going to set it Max with a four hundred pixels.
OK, so I think that looks pretty good.
So now it is responsive.
So in the next video we obviously want to make this function so we can reach out to the GitHub API and
fetch a user and we're actually going to use axios, which is an HTTP library, as opposed to using
fetch which is built into the browser.