OK, so now we're going to get into the JavaScript and working with the GitHub API and this is the docs
right here, you don't have to go to this page.
But I just want to show you, if we go down to endpoints available for GitHub apps, these are like
the different resources that are available.
We want to deal with users and repos.
So if I click on users, we can make a get request to the API and then slash users, which will give
us a list, an array of users.
We want to get a specific user name based on what we type in the search.
So this is the request we're going to make and it gives us an example of a response that we get, which
includes the login, which is the user name, the ID, the avatar, you URL the if they have a blog,
you URL their name, company email the number of of public repos followers following.
So we have access to all this data.
Now the other thing we want to do is get the users repos so we can do that.
If you look at repos and there's a whole bunch of endpoints here, but if we go down to the very bottom,
you'll see we can do get users the user name and then slash repos.
And then that will give us a response that looks like this.
And it's an array of the users repositories and we can get the name.
All we really need here is the name.
And then we want to get the HTML neutral, which will give us the link to the repository.
All right.
So those are the two endpoints that we're going to deal with, user slash user name and then user slash
user name slash repos.
Now, there is a limit.
If you if you don't use authentication with the GitHub API, you have a limit of a certain amount of
requests per hour or something like that.
So if you are to go into production, you probably want to look at authentication, but we're not going
to get into that in this particular tutorial.
Now, the first thing that I want to do is, is be able to fetch a specific GitHub user from the API.
Now we're going to be using axios.
So I'm going to go to CDN News.com and search for axios so that I can get that CBN link so that we can
use the library.
So you want this Axios mindgames?
I'm going to copy the script tag and put that right above my script.
J.S. in the index HTML.
Now we have access to the Axios object and we can make get requests, we can do Axios Scott post, we
can do put, which is usually like an update and then delete if we want to delete.
And then if you just do axios like this and put the user Ellen here, that's going to be a get request.
It's the same as doing Axios doGet.
I actually have a full crash course on Axios on my YouTube channel, if you're interested in learning
more about it.
So first thing I'll do here is create a constant for the API URLs.
So basically the root GitHub you URL actually is you single quotes, so https and it's going to be api
dot github dot com slash user slash.
That's going to be the root because we're going to make requests to this slash and then the user name
as well as slash user name and then the repos.
All right, so that's our route, your URL.
Now to use axios, let's first just let's create a function called Get User, and this will take in
a user name that we want to get.
And then to make the requests we can take, we can either say Axios doGet or we can just do axios.
And that will default to get.
And in here I'm going to pass in the Aperol, but I also want the user name attached to that.
So in this case, it's going to be this slash and then whatever the user name that's passed in now,
this returns a promise and ultimately I'm going to use a sink away.
But just to show you, without using a sink away, we can say then and we'll get data.
Let's call this data actually.
Let's call this ready for response.
And we don't have to do this.
We don't have to say resident Jason, like we do with fetch, with fetch.
We have to do that and we have to do another promise and get the data.
Axios makes it easier because we don't need to do that.
I just want to console log rez and see what that gives us.
And resident data should be the actual data, but a console log was first.
Now, if something goes wrong, then we want to add dot catch.
When we have a promise, we can use a catch if if there's some kind of error.
So it's past an error here and then we'll just go ahead and console log the error.
All right.
Now, I'm going to just call this function right here.
Let's say get yuzu and I'll pass in my GitHub username, and if we go over here and open the console,
we get an object back which has config with just a whole bunch of stuff here.
But what we're interested in, you also see the headers, the request status, which is 200 status text.
OK, but data is where the actual data is going to be.
And you can see my GitHub data here.
So if I cancel log resource data, that's going to give us just the object that we need.
All right.
So there's no need to add a second dot then with axios, which is one of the reasons why I prefer it.
It also has more features.
Now, if something goes wrong, this catch will fire off, like if we do users w which is not a valid
endpoint.
You'll see that now it's logging the error, which is request failed the status code for for now I want
to use a sink away instead of using this dot, then catch syntax.
So what we'll do is just get rid of that and our function has to be a sink and then we'll be able to
just create a variable here called Redds and set that to that.
And then down here we should be able to just cancel log rez dot data.
If I save that, we want to change this back.
See, we're getting undefined, and that's because I did not await the the axios request here, so we
need to sink a weight.
And now you can see I get my profile data.
We can take this a step further and not use Redd's.
We can D structure because Rez is an object that has property of data, which is another object.
And we can d structure that by just using curly braces and say we just want to take out data.
And then down here I can just log data.
Now what if there's an error?
What's that?
What if something goes wrong?
How do we handle the catch?
Because when we do a regular promise, we can do catch.
Well, there's a bunch of ways we can handle this.
What I usually do is to a try catch so we can just say try and then if something goes wrong, we'll
catch with an error.
And let's take this and let's put this into the tribe block like that, and then if something goes wrong,
then we'll console console, don't log the error or PRR whatever you can put whatever you want here,
error or error.
So if I save that, we get the same result and you'll see if I go up here and I change the URL, we're
going to get the same thing that we would get from the catch from the, you know, dot catch from the
promise we'll get here.
All right.
Hopefully that makes sense.
And you can use this try catch with anything.
You could use it with the fetch API, although error handling is a little more complicated with the
Fetch API, which is another reason that I like axios better.
But yeah.
So you can just try catch in many different situations.
Now at the moment we're just I'm just hard coding my name in here, which I don't want to do.
I want to get it from the form.
And you could initially call a user and show the user.
But we're not we're just going to have the form and then when we submit the form, it'll get the user.
So let's go down here and let's take actually, we need to bring the form in.
So let's go right here and say const form and set that to document dot get element by D and we have
an idea of form and then let's go down here and say form dot add event listener and we're going to listen
for a segment.
You could do this on like a key down as well, but you would be making a request every time you do a
key down.
But yeah, let's do a segment with an arrow function with our event object and we want to prevent the
default behavior.
So we want to do each dot prevent default or it's actually going to try to submit to a file and then
we'll put into a variable called user e dot target dot value.
Actually, you know what, let's bring in search the input, we have an idea of search, so I'm going
to bring that in here like that and then, oops, what I just do.
And then once we bring search in, will set this instead of IDOT Target, let's set it to the search
value.
So search dot value like that.
And then we want to make sure that there's a user.
So say if user then let's call the get user function and let's pass in here the user and then I want
to clear the search value.
So we'll say search dot value and set that to nothing.
So let's save that and let's go over here.
We're not going to see anything happen down here yet.
We haven't done anything with the DOM, but it should at least console log the data that you call this,
get the search input value in here, make the request and console log the data.
So let's look for Floren Pop 17.
And down here, you can see that it's logging the data for Floren Pop.
OK, so now that we're actually able to, you know, search for users data in the next video, we want
to take this data.
We want to insert it into the dorm.
We're also going to have to make a separate request to get these repositories as well.
OK, so we'll start on that in the next video.