OK, so we're able to type in a user, get their profile data and console it, but we don't want to
do that.
We want to add it to this card right here.
So what we'll do is create a new function.
Let's go down here and say function and we're going to call this create let's call it create user card.
And it's going to take in a user.
And we want to take, let's say, const card HTML.
So we're going to create a variable here called card HTML and set it to a set of tactics.
And then I'm going to grab what we have in our HTML, this card.
So this div right here, everything that's in Maine, I'm going to take that and cut that.
We don't actually need anything in here.
We'll save that's going to go away.
And then in our script, in this variable right here in this template, literal, I'm going to just
go ahead and let's go like that and paste that in.
All right.
So create user card right now.
It's just all static, you know, content.
But I'm going to go after the back to here and take mean.
Actually, we need to bring Main in, don't we.
Yeah.
So up here, let's go ahead and bring in, say, Maine, which has an idea of Maine, and then after
the template literal will say Maine dot enter html equals Maine.
I call it a card card html.
So card html.
And let's save that and then once we make the request right here, so we get the data and instead of,
you know, console logging, let's call create user card and let's pass in our data, which is the user
data.
And they get that gets passed in here right now.
It's going to be the same static, you know, content.
But let's just make sure that that works at least.
So if I type in, you know, Brad, enter, OK, so we get a card, but it's still has John Doe in it.
So let's change this stuff up.
We now have access to the user data, and if you want to see exactly what that gives you, we could
take this and you could just go right in your browser here and paste that in and put any GitHub username
and you're going to see what it gives you.
So you can see the avatar.
You Eurail is what we want, that we're going to want the user name right here.
We're going to want the bio.
So all this this data is available to you.
So let's go to the image here.
Let's get rid of that.
And let's put in here the user dot avatar underscore you URL.
And then for the ALZ, we'll go ahead and say user, let's do the user name.
And right here in the H2, we want to use user dot name and then the bios.
So let's get rid of this and let's add user dot bio and then we have down here, like our followers
will get rid of this 300 here and let's put in user dot followers and then we have our following user
dot following.
And our repos is going to be user dot, public, underscore, rebholz.
And this is all coming from the API.
You can see right here, public repose.
You have other stuff like public gists, company blog you could use and then repost here.
We're just going to get rid of these because we're actually going to make another request to get those
and then insert.
But I'm just going to get rid of those for now.
So let's save that.
And let's go back to our application here.
And I'm going to search for my profile and then we go.
So we get my image, my name, my bio number of followers following.
I should follow some more people repos.
Good.
Now, we don't have the the Repos yet, like the you know, because we're going to get to the top five
repos or the latest five.
We're going to do that in the next video.
But what I do want to do is handle the error, because right now, if there's an error, like let's
put something that we know is probably not a name and nothing happens.
Well, something does happen at console logs right here.
So if there's an error, let's then let's get rid of this and let's call a function called create error
card.
All right, now what we could do it this way.
You can also check for specific responses like that would be a 404 because it wouldn't be found.
So we could do an F here.
And we could say if the error dot response DOT status is equal to a 404, then we want to do a create
error card.
And then you can check for other types of of responses as well.
But we'll just go ahead and leave it at this, because if it tries to find a user that doesn't exist,
it's going to be a 404 status.
So this create error card, let's actually you know what?
Let's put a message in here.
So create error card will take a message that says there is no or we'll just say no user.
No profile with this username.
All right, so we'll go down here and let's create that function function, create error card, which
takes in a message and we're just going to do the same thing we did above in the user card will create
a variable.
We'll call this card HTML and set this to template literal and we're going to have a div with the class
of card
and inside this div we're just going to have an H1 with whatever that message is.
OK, and then we'll take the main element and set the inner HTML equal to the card HTML.
So let's save that.
Now I'm going to type something in here that is definitely not a name and that didn't work.
See.
Reference error message is not to oh, I put a message MSG.
All right, let's try that again.
So no problem.
No profile with this username.
And it's going to tell us down here that it got a feel for as well in the console, but good.
That's what I want.
So then we could try, like, you know, Floren Pop 17 and we get Florens.
Beautiful picture and profile.
All right.
So in the next video, we want to work on the repositories.
We want to show the top five, not the top five, the most recent five down here with a link to click
on and visit those repositories.