OK, so now we want to add the repositories to the to the cards here, so I'm going to actually do another
function where we make a request.
So this is to get the username right or I'm sorry, get the user by the username.
Let's create a function right below it and we'll call this one gets repos and that's going to take in
username and we're going to make this async so that we can use a sink, await
and let's do pretty much, you know, the same thing here.
We're going to use try catch.
I'm going to just grab that and paste that in.
Now for the error here.
Let's.
Let's just replace the message here will say problem fetching rooibos, so if for some reason, you
know, the reposts can't be fetched, we'll just we'll just display that we'll actually get rid of the
four or four as well.
Just if anything goes wrong now here, we don't want to get just Aperol username, we also want to get
the repost.
I'm just going to concatenate here and add on to this slash repost.
OK, so it's going to be the API URL, which is defined at the top slash username slash repos.
And I mean, I can show you that over here what that would give us.
So if we do, you know, users slash and then Brad Travis S. slash repos, and that gives me an array
of my repositories with the name, the full name, a bunch of info about the user or the owner, the
HTML, you RL, which is a link to the Rebo.
So that's what we get from that.
Now, over here, once we get that, once we get where are we.
Right here.
So once we get that.
Let's then.
Let's see, let's call instead of create user card.
Let's change that to add, we'll say add repos to card, OK, but we want to call this get repos up
here after we call create user card.
So after that, we'll say get repos.
And we want to pass in the username here that is ultimately coming from here, OK, so it'll create
the user card and then call get repos, which fetches the repos, and then calls this ad repost a card,
which we're going to create right now.
So let's go down below under create our card and let's say function will say function, add repos to
card, which is going to take in repos.
Now we need the repos element.
So let's say const repos element and we're going to set that to document Dotts get element by I.D. and
we should have an idea of repos.
OK, if we look up here in the HTML that gets inserted, we have this div, that's where we want to
insert it.
So I'm grabbing that and then let's take the repos that are passed in here and let's loop through them.
So I'll just say repos dot for each and say for each repo.
We want to then create our links.
Right.
So we're going to say const let's call this repo link and set that to document dot create elements,
because that's what we want to do, is create a new element and it's going to be in a tag.
We want to add the repo class to it because if you remember when we hardcoded, there were links with
the class of repo.
So let's say we'll take.
Repo men actually call this repo element,
so take the repo element and let's say class list dot ad and we're going to add the class of repo for
each one.
Now we want to add an aircraft because we wanted to point to the actual repository.
Strel So we'll take the repo element and say dot HSF.
And that's going to go to Repo, which is the repository object which has a value of HTML.
Underscore RL, which you can see over here, this right here html you URL, which is a link to the
actual repository.
We're going to add that to the address of the link.
I also want to add a target to this because I don't want it to open on the same page.
So we'll take our repo element and let's set the targets and set that to underscore blank so it opens
in a new window.
And then for the the text inside the link, let's say, repo elements and set the inner text.
And that's going to be the repo name, which you can see we can get here.
And then finally we need to inserted into the DOM.
So we want to take our repos, plural element and append child.
And for each one of these, we want to add the repo element.
All right.
So let's save that.
Let's go back here and let's search for Floren Pop 17.
And now you can see all these repos.
Now, I'm not sure if it shows all of them.
No, it doesn't show.
Definitely doesn't show all of them, but it shows too many.
Right.
So I want to cut this down a bit.
Let's get the let's get 10 of them.
So before we do the four each, let's take the repos array and let's slice.
So we're just going to slice it from the first to 10.
So we want the first 10.
And if we save that and I search again.
Oops, I misspelled my own name.
OK, so now we get one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
And of course you can make that anything you want.
All right.
Now, the last thing I want to do is instead of getting you know, it's basically in alphabetical order
here.
And that's not what I want.
I want the latest five.
So there's actually with this API, we can add on a query, a query string to where is it?
So right here where we're fetching our repos, we can add questionmark and we can do sort and set that
to create it.
So now I'm going to save that and.
Search and now this is these are definitely my latest Rebozo Currie Web site, but L.A. rest API react
admon example, which are all YouTube videos, by the way.
You can check my channel out for those, but yeah.
So now it's giving us the latest 10 rebozo and you can change it if you want to change it to five.
I could do that.
And there we go.
So now we get the latest five.
All right.
So that's it.
I mean, I know this is a small project, but there's quite a bit that we did here in terms of learning,
you know, how to use axios, how to use, try, catch and handle errors, you know, inserting things
into the dorm and stuff like that, working with an API.
So hopefully guys enjoy this project and that's it.
I'll see you in the next one.