So in this project, we're going to create this, we're going to have this image here and you can see
it says double click on the image to heart it and it says you liked it zero times.
So when we click anywhere on this image, if I double click, you're going to see a heart pop up.
It's going to have a little CSFs Growe animation and it's going to show wherever we click.
Not only that, it's going to show how many times we clicked.
You can see you've clicked four times.
So the HTML and access for this is really, really easy.
When we get into the JavaScript, we're going to set a double click event and basically insert a heart
in the exact position where we click.
So we're going to be working with, you know, the on the event parameter we have are the event object.
We have the client X and client Y values the the event target offset left offset top so we can tell
exactly where this element comes in from the top and the left, because we need to calculate, calculate
that in in order to find the exact position in the image.
And another thing we'll do is instead of just using DB, I'll click the double click event.
We're going to use just a single click event and basically create our own double click event based on
the time between space, between clicks.
So if I just click once and then I wait, you know, a decent amount of time again, that's not going
to be a double click.
So we're going to test the time between clicks and basically create our own double click event.
All right.
So let's get into it.