So we're going to get started on our double click project and we are going to be using font.
Awesome.
So I noticed that I have the link, the CDN to font.
Awesome here.
So you can get that from font.
Awesome website or CD and Jast dot com.
So let's change the title here in the HTML and we'll call this double double click cart.
And down here we want to have not much.
We're going to have an H3 here and we'll say double click on the image to and then let's put the heart
here.
So we're going to use an eye tag with the class of Fey S and F a dash heart.
And then after that, we're just going to put the word it.
So outside of the icon here.
So it'll be double click on the image to heart it.
OK, there we go.
And then we're also going to count how many times it's been clicked.
So that's going to go into a small tag here and we'll say you liked it.
And then spane here.
And let's give this an idea of times and just start with zero.
And then after the span here, we'll just say time.
So that'll tell us how many times we liked it.
And then the last thing we want is just a div with the class of love me.
And that's basically where the background image is going to go and where, you know, we're going to
we're going to add our event listener to our double click on it and get that heart icon.
All right.
So let's save that.
Let's jump into the stylesheet here and we're going to use a family code called Oswald.
So I'm just going to do Caesar's questionmark family equals Oswald.
And for the background here in the background, for the family here in the body, let's change that
to Oswald.
OK, so that'll change the font.
And then we don't really need Fleck's box here.
So I'm actually going to get rid of all this stuff.
You know, get rid of that and all I'm going to put here is a text, a line center.
And then let's start to style like the three, so let's give a margin bottom here of zero and let's
add text align center here.
And then the small tag I want to display as block as small is inline by default.
And then I want to add margin bottom to that of 20 pixels and also text align center.
So for the heart we want we obviously don't want to Blackheart and we're going to have the heart icon
in the image when we click on it.
So let's style a dash heart and let's just make the color to red like that.
Now we have a red card.
So next we want to do the Love Me class, which is going to be the whole basically the whole image.
So for this, let's add a let's do a height of 440 and let's do a width of 300 and then for the background.
So I'm going to use a background image, actualise background, and then it's going to be a Eurail.
And of course, this could be any image you want.
I'm just going to grab this real quick.
It's just an image of a car from Splash.
OK, so put that in there.
All right, now, I just want to add a couple of background attributes like no repeats position, center,
center and cover, OK?
And then after that, let's just set margin up.
So I want to go.
Yeah, that's right.
So imagine I'm going to set that to auto.
I don't move it to the middle.
And then let's put a cursor point there, because when we hover over it, we want to have a pointer
and I'm just going to set a max with one hundred percent.
And I'm going to position this to be relative because the heart when we click and we have the heart
icon, that's going to be positioned absolute within this.
So this the container needs to be positioned relative.
And then let's also add a little bit of box shadow, which I'm just going to paste in case we have a
little box shadow.
Kind of looks like it's coming off the page and that should do it for Love Me.
So now let's do the the heart that's in the Love Me class.
So F.A.A. Dasch heart.
And like I said, if you want to position this to be absolute.
And we're not going to see this just yet because it's going to get put in through the JavaScript, so
we're just adding the CSFs, which isn't much we want to position absolute.
And then we want to have an animation for it, which I'm going to call Gro and we'll do that over a
period of six seconds and make that linear.
And then let's add a transform
and for the transform set translate.
So it's going to be it's going to start in the middle.
So 50 negative, 50 percent on the x axis, negative, 50 percent on the Y axis.
I also want to scale it.
So in addition to translate will have scale to zero now for the animation that's going to go on a key.
So let's say at keyframes and we called it grow.
And what I want to do is just change the scaling.
OK, so when we double click on it, it's going to look like it's growing, you know, from its regular
size up.
So we want to change this.
The translate will be, oh, actually, I'm sorry, we need to add let's just say two, because it's
only it's only one point.
So two, and then we want to scale it up.
Ten.
OK, so it's going to go from zero to 10.
And let's also make the opacity to zero because we don't want it to stay once we double click.
We just wanted to show scale and then disappear.
OK, so that's pretty much it for the success.
In the next video, we'll jump in and make this function with our JavaScript.