OK, so now we're going to get into the JavaScript and basically we want to be able to double click
on any area on the image and have the heart appear.
We basically want to insert the heart icon into the dorm and we already have the keys for it to grow
and have that effect.
So let's start off by bringing in the Love Me class.
So you just document dot query selector and we're going to bring in the class of love me.
And then we also want the times, which I believe has an idea of time.
So that's going to be this zero right here, because we want to change that when we double click.
All right.
Now we'll take that love me class here that love me variable.
And we want to add an event listener and I want to double click now.
There's an easy way to do this.
We can pass and double click.
And then when we double click, we're going to fire off function.
And let's just do a console log of one, two, three.
So we'll go over here and open up our console.
Sure.
Save this.
And if I double click, we see one, two, three gets logged.
Now, we're going to make this a little more complicated.
And instead of just using double click, I want to use a single click, but create our own double click.
And if you want to pause the video and try to do this yourself, basically we're just going to test
the time between clicks.
And if it's less than a certain amount like let's say eight hundred milliseconds, then that's going
to be considered a double click.
If it's if it's, you know, the time range is wider between clicks, then that's not going to be a
double click.
So if you want to try that yourself, you can.
But I'm going to go ahead and just create a variable up here called click time.
And down here, let's check to see if the time is equal to zero, so quick time is equal to zero, then
we're going to set the clock time to new.
We're going to use the date constructor and the get time method here.
So we're going to set that and then I'll just go ahead and cancel log click time so you can see what
that gives us.
So if I go over here and I just click once, I'm going to see the value of click time, which had the
current time when I clicked.
And it's not going to work again because it's in this if statement.
Time is no longer equal to zero, so that's not going to work.
All right.
So we want to do that.
And then else so if it's not equal to zero, then we want to do another test here and check to see if
the let's actually let's let's put this in parentheses, another set of parentheses and let's say if
the new dates don't get time, so we're just checking the current timestamp.
So if that is or if that minus the click time, I should say, if that is greater than 800 milliseconds,
then for now, let's just console log one, two, three else.
So if it's not less than 800, then we're going to just reset the clock time to zero.
I'm sorry, not zero the current day time.
So new date does get time, OK?
Now, if I go over here and I double click, I see one, two, three by single click.
Nothing happens if I single click and then I wait and single click.
That's not considered a double click because that is, that's greater than 800 milliseconds.
So if I do a quick that's less than 800 milliseconds and that gives me my double click functionality.
OK, so I mean you could use double as an event, but just to make it a little more fun, we just added
a click and then created our own double click event.
All right.
So when this happens, when we actually double click what we want to do, we're going to create our
call, I should say, a function called create heart, and we're going to pass the event parameter into
that.
And then because we need to map where the mouse is in the image, because that's where we want the heart
to appear.
We also want to set the click time.
We want to set that back to zero.
OK, so if I double click, it's going to tell me create heart is not a function or it's not defined.
So let's go ahead and define it down here.
It's a function create heart.
This is going to take in the event value here actually will make this let's make this an arrow function
so const create hearts and set that to an arrow.
So let's build a heart icon so we'll create a variable called heart and set that to document create
element.
So create element does just that.
We can create a div or any kind of html tag or each element I can use and I tag here and I want to add
a couple of classes to it.
So let's say heart dot class list dot add.
So remember with font awesome.
We have the first class and then I also want to add the a dash heart class.
OK, so now we have this heart element but we want to insert this wherever we're clicking now with this
event that's passed in here, ultimately coming from here from the the click event here, we can get
the position.
So let's say CONSED and we'll call this X.
So this is on the X axis.
So on this event object, we have clients client X and then let's do call this Y and let's do client
Y, and then I just want to show you the values for this so we're going to can't type, we're going
to just cancel log X and Y now I'm going to go over here and click somewhere and I get one twenty two,
one thirty three.
If I go up in the corner here I get a ninety nine, I go over here.
So three seventy seven.
So the first value is on the x axis.
I'm way over here so the X value is three seventy seven.
I'm pretty close to the top so it's ninety two here.
It's eighty seven.
And this is just in you know in the viewport here.
So if I go way over here and I click you can see eighty five.
All right.
So it gives me the exact.
Coordinates of where I'm clicking, which is what I want.
Now, another value or two values that I want to get are the offset left in offset right values.
So the this E that is getting passed in here pertains to this element, right?
That the whole image.
So we want to get the offset from the left and we want to get the offset from the right so that we can
basically we can subtract that from whatever these x y values are, because we wanted to show, you
know, within this image here that this is this is our our working space, not the entire viewport.
So we want to subtract this and this from wherever we're clicking.
All right.
And on that event parameter, on that e value, we can use offset left and offset top.
So let's say const and let's set left offsets and set that to E and this is actually on the target property.
So idot target, dot offset or I'm sorry, left offset and then we want the top as well.
So this one is going to be top offset and top offset.
OK, so now we want to basically take our X and Y values, which is in the place in the viewport that
we click and we want to subtract left and top from those.
So let's say const X inside, so inside the image and set that to X what we want to minus the left offset.
OK, we're going to do the same thing with Y and we're going to minus the top offset because X is right
and left wise up and down.
So this is going to be Y inside.
OK, now you can get rid of this console log.
Actually let's console log just to see what we get for X inside and Y inside, so we'll save that.
And now if I click way end up in this corner.
OK, so I'm getting not a number.
OK, so I screwed this up.
This shouldn't be.
It's not left offset.
It's offset left.
So offset left, I must adjust that the autocomplete.
So this is offset top.
All right.
So let's save that now and let's go up into this corner.
And now you'll see that these values are relative to the image rather than the viewport.
Before it was like, what, eighty five or something like that.
But now so that's two one and that's one one.
OK, so that's the start of the corner here.
So that gives us the correct coordinates within the image, not the viewport.
So now that we have those values, what we'll do is take the heart that we created.
We created that element and we want to set the style top property now in the success for the Love Me
heart.
Remember, we positioned that absolu so we can use top left, bottom right CSFs properties, but we
don't want to set them here.
We don't want a hard code them because it's dynamic.
It's going to be wherever it's set here.
So I'm going to set the top value and I'm going to set that to let's actually just put a template literal
in here and we want to set it to Y inside.
Remember, this is the top, so we want the Y axis, which is top and bottom, and then we just want
to add pixels and then we want to do the same here.
This will be X inside and here we're going to set the left property.
OK, so we're going to insert it there.
Now, it's not going to show up just yet.
So if I double click, it's not going to do anything because we need to add it to the love me element
we want to append child.
OK, so we're adding it in the love me element.
The heart.
All right.
So if I go ahead and I click now, there we go.
So we're inserting that heart wherever we click in the image.
So even though this is a very, very simple project in terms of like functionality, if you didn't know
that you can get the positioning of the mouse and stuff and then how to get the exact position within
inner element, this can be very helpful for many other, you know, larger projects.
So we're not done yet.
We want to do this time thing.
And this is going to be pretty easy.
We're just going to initialize another variable up here.
We'll call this times collect and set that to zero by default.
And we already brought the Times element in which is a span right here with the idea of times.
So we'll say times dot in our HTML and set that two times clicked, but that's going to be zero.
So we would just want to increment it and we can do that by just adding a plus plus at the beginning
and that will increment it by one.
So now if we go over here and I double click, you'll see you liked it one times to three.
And obviously it doesn't matter, you know, where we click.
Now, one thing I want to show you is in the elements tab, we see just kind of double click.
So this is going to put in the the eye tag here with the, you know, FASFA heart.
But look how many there are.
So basically, we're just we keep putting them in, but they don't they disappear because of this,
because we're setting the opacity to zero.
But they're all still there.
So to fix this, we want to remove each heart after, let's say, one second.
So we'll use a set time out here and this will just run a function after a certain amount of time.
So the second argument we pass in is that amount of time, which I'm going to do one second, which
is a thousand milliseconds.
And we don't even actually need curly braces because all we're doing is this heart hardcourt remove.
So we're just removing it from the dawn.
So now if we take a look at down here in So Love Me Right Now is empty, I'm going to double click and
now and you can see it gets filled in.
I can't even click it fast enough.
Actually, you know, what I'll do is just change this to five seconds.
So I'll click and you'll see the heart is in there.
After five seconds, it removes.
OK, but I want to set that to one second.
I just just slowed it down to show you.
So now it's not going to fill up with all these hearts.
They get removed after one second.
All right.
So that's pretty much it.
Hopefully you guys enjoyed this project and we'll move on to the next.