Hey, guys, welcome to your next project.
So this is going to be another short one, we can get this done in a single video.
So we're going to have this auto text effect, auto typing effect.
And you've probably seen this on what, different websites where it just kind of types it out by itself.
So we're going to add this effect or in style this, which isn't going to take too much.
And then also we're going to add this speed control.
So you can see it's at one right now.
And if I make it to two, it's going to go a little faster.
Three, four.
Five, so you can see it just keeps getting faster and it has a max of 10 right now, would of course
you could make that whatever you want.
So this is something you might see on like a hero banner on a website, obviously probably wouldn't
have the speed control.
But again, this is just to learn to add event listeners to make things happen in the dorm.
So let's go ahead and get started and I'll see you in the next video.