All right, so we're going to get started on our auto taiping effect and we should be able to do it
in this one video.
So let's start with the TML call this auto text fact.
And let's do an H1 here.
We're just going to say starting dot, dot, dot, because the phrase it's going to be typed out is
going to be set in the JavaScript and then we'll add it to this H1 using this idea of text.
And then under that, we're going to have a div that's going to have the speed control.
So we'll have a label for speed and speed colon and under Neath that will have an input.
And this is going to be the type of number and the name is going to be speed and I.D. is also speed.
And I also want to set the initial value to be one.
And we can set a minimum tax on a number of fields so men will be one and then let's set Max to five
and we'll set the step value.
What set that to one?
So it just it just counts up by one if you hit the little arrow up or down.
All right.
So we'll save that.
It's going to look like this.
And we're going to just add in our style here.
So the body let's add a background color and we're going to use dark samen for the background color
here and everything else we can leave.
That's fine for the div.
So basically the you know, where we control the speed, let's change that.
I'm going to position that absolutes and I want that to be at the bottom.
So let's do 20 pixels up from the bottom.
So move it down there and then let's do a background, kind of like a transparent, almost transparent
background.
We'll use a black and zero point one.
And then let's add some padding to this, so 10 pixels, top and bottom, 20 pixels left and right,
and then let's set the font size to 18 pixels.
All right.
And then for the input itself, will just grab it by input.
Let's set the width of that to 50 pixels.
Let's set the padding.
We'll do five pixels and the font size I'm going to set.
Let's do 20 pixels.
Actually, that's kind of big.
Let's do 18 and then let's set the background of that.
I want to set that to a background color of dark salmon as well.
And then the border.
We're just going to get rid of that.
Okay.
And then let's text the line to the center.
And I think we should be good now for the focus.
Like, if I click in here, I want to get rid of this border, this outline.
So let's say for the input when it's in its focus state, let's set the outline to none.
All right.
So now we can, you know, increase this decrease at.
So let's jump in to our JavaScript, so let's start off by bringing in our text element.
So when we call this text Al and we want document get element Bindeez, and we're going to bring it
in by its idea of text.
We also want the speed so the the no input has an idea of speed.
So we'll call this speed element and then I'm going to create a text variable which will have the actual
text we want to type out, which I want to say we love programming.
And obviously that could be whatever you want.
And then I'm going to initialize an index variable at one.
And this is going to pertain to where we are in the text because we're going to be typing it out one
by one and then also the speed.
So I'm going to say let's speed.
And you could set this in many different ways.
I'm going to just take three hundred and divide it by whatever the value of this is.
So we'll take the speed element and we can get the value with value.
So it'll be, you know, start out with three hundred divided by one or 300, divide by two and that's
going to make it faster as we increase it.
Now we're going to initially call a function called write text.
So we want to create that function.
And we want to take the text element and set the entire text, too, and then we will start off with
just the W in this case, because it's going to be the first letter in the string so we can take the
text, which is we love programming and then call dot, slice and with slice we can get a certain range
of the string.
So I want to get from zero to one in this case, which the index, which the index starts at 1:00.
All right.
So if I save that, we're just going to see a W on the screen.
Now, after we do that, we want to take the index and increment it by one.
So adding a plus plus just sets.
You know, if it's out one, it's going to go to two and three, four and so on.
Sharlie, you guys know that.
And then I just want to check to see if it's the end of the string that we're typing out so we can test
and see if the index is greater than the text length, which is going to be the entire length of whatever
we have here.
If that's true, then I'm going to just reset the index to one.
So it just will start over.
You don't have to do that.
You could just stop it or whatever.
But we're just going to have to keep going now.
We need this to keep happening, right?
So we need to keep calling this right text.
So inside here, let's call a set time out and we want we want to call.
Right.
Text would set time out.
Does is it runs a specific function in this case.
Write text and then it'll wait a specific amount of time.
So I could say like 100 milliseconds or 1000 milliseconds which would be one second.
Now I don't want this to be hard coded.
I want to wait whatever the speed is.
OK, so whatever that speed is, is what we want to set as a second argument to set time, OK?
Now, if I save this, it's going to go ahead and start to type out.
So it's basically just calling this and then when it hits the end, it starts over because we reset
the index to one.
And I could set this to anything I want up here.
So if I set the speed to a 1000, that's going to be every one second.
If I set it to, let's say 10000, it's going to be every ten seconds, 100 milliseconds.
That's going to be quicker.
But I'm going to keep it at that.
What I had of that.
And then for this, we want this to control, you know, how fast this goes.
So let's take the speed element and let's add an event listener on to it.
Remember, the speed element is a no input, and I want to listen for any input, meaning if we type
the number in or if we use the arrow keys and then we'll have an arrow function here with our event
object.
And when this is called, we just want to set the speed equal to 300 divided by whatever the value is
here.
So e dot target, dot value.
OK, so it should happen, you know, in real time or whatever.
If I click to two it's going to start going faster.
If I click to three faster four, five and that's the max I can go because we set that max here.
If I set this to ten and I can type in here too.
So if I type in ten, you see how fast it goes.
If I type in five goes a little slower, if I type in one.
So I mean you probably wouldn't have this control on your actual website.
Like maybe you'd have a hero image with this, this effect.
You probably wouldn't give the speed effect as well.
But this is just for learning, you know, so you can learn how to add events and manipulate the DOM
and do little things like this.
But of course, this would be cool just to have in your your hero page, your hero banner or whatever
on your website.
So that's it.
I know this is a very short project.
Hopefully you enjoyed it.
If you want to add to it, maybe you could add an input up here or down here that you could type in
the text and it would change this.
And I might even do some videos later on where I take some of the projects we've already done and add
to it.
But I would suggest you do that on your own as well.
All right, enough rambling.
Let's move on to the next video.