All right, so in this project, we're going to build a password generator, so the idea is we can choose
a line of 20 by default.
Let's say we want 10, a 10 character long password and we can choose if we want to include uppercase
letters, lowercase letters, numbers and symbols.
So let's say we want just uppercase, lowercase and numbers, but not symbols.
Click generate.
And that's what we get.
So we're going to get 10 if I change this to, let's say five and let's include symbols as well.
Now we're going to get you know, we're going to get a password with uppercase and lowercase letters,
numbers and symbols.
In addition to that, we're going to add the functionality where we can click this and it's going to
copy the password to the clipboard.
If I just go up here and my you are albar and paste, you'll see that it'll actually paste whatever
is in the password result here.
All right.
So let's go ahead and jump into it.
The JavaScript.
And this is going to be a little more complicated than a lot of the other projects, but we'll go ahead
and take it step by step and get it done.