OK, so we're going to get started on the HTML for a password generator.
Now, when I have my project starter open and I just have a link to the font awesome CDN from KD, SJS,
Dotcom, and because we do need that clipboard icon.
And then I'm just going to add let's save for the title here.
Password generator, and then we'll go down here and let's create a container for everything to go into
and then in that container will have an H2 and say password generator.
So under that H2, let's go ahead and have a div with the class of result dash, not generator container.
And basically this is where the actual password is going to go.
So in here we're going to have a span with the class of result and nothing's going to actually go inside
the span.
We just want that there and then we want the clipboard button.
So I'm going to say button class buttons, class button.
And I'm also going to give this an idea of clipboard and I'm going to use an icon here.
So I tag with the class of FLIR and then let's do a dash clipboard and a save that we get a little button
with a clipboard icon.
So that's it for the results container.
So under that div, under the results container div, let's create another div with the class of settings.
So this is where we're going to have like each setting, like the password length, the if we're going
to include uppercase letters, lowercase letters and so on and each one is going to have a class of
setting.
So let's create our first one here, which is going to be the password lank.
I'm going to use a label here, get rid of that, say, password length.
And this is going to be an input.
It's going to be type number and we don't need a name for this.
The I.D. is going to be length and then let's do a minimum.
So minimum allowed will be a four and then Max will be twenty.
And then let's do an initial value here of twenty.
So this is how long the password is going to be.
So the next one is going to be a checkbox, actually, the rest of them will be checkboxes.
So under that setting, let's create another div with the class of setting.
And this is also going to have a label and this label is going to be include uppercase letters and it's
going to be an input with the type of checkbox and we don't need a name.
The I.D. is going to be uppercase and then I want this checked by default.
So we're going to add checked.
We're going to have them all checked by default.
All right.
So if I save that, you can see the checkbox.
Now, the rest of these, there's going to be three more checkboxes.
So I'm going to just copy this down.
That's to want four altogether, three, four and under uppercase.
We're going to do lowercase.
So we'll take that and that change it to lowercase and then, whoops, I wanted to do that.
The second one, so this will be lower case and then after that we'll do numbers, so this and this
will be numbers and then symbols.
So this and this will be symbols.
All right.
So include Sweeney's password length, include uppercase letters, lowercase letters, including numbers,
letters.
That doesn't make sense.
Let's get rid of the word letters and then include symbols.
OK, and then after that, we just want to button.
So we want to go now outside of the settings container, which is this right here and here.
And let's create our button.
So we'll say button.
I'm going to give it a class of B10 and also BTE and B10 Dash large and I'm going to give you an idea
of generate and then we'll just say generate password.
OK, so that's the HTML.
So let's jump over to our stylesheet and I'm going to use the Mully font, which we've used quite a
bit.
So let's say success.
Questionmark family equals Muli, and then let's add that to our body Phonte family, and then we're
going to add a background color to the body.
So background color is going to be the hexadecimal value of three B three, B, nine eight.
So we'll have this blue background and then the color of the text is going to be white.
And then let's see, so we want to display flex flex column, let's add we'll just add padding here
as well, 10 pixels.
And then for the H2, I'm going to just set a margin of 10 pixels top and bottom or 10 pixels, top
zero, left and right.
Let's do 20 on the bottom and just make sure we text a line to the center.
Now, the container.
Remember, that wraps around everything.
So I'm going to set on a container, a background color of let's do two, three, two, three, five,
be on that and then let's do a box shadow as well.
So say box shadow and let's do for the offsets zero pixels, two pixels for the blur value, 10 pixels
and I'll be a I'm going to do white so two five five four red, green, blue and then for the alpha
will do zero point two.
So it gives a kind of a light, you see the light box shadow and then for the padding we'll just do
20 pixels all around and let's set a fixed width of three hundred and fifty pixels and let's set a max
width of one hundred percent.
All right.
So now we have the main container.
Now the results container, which I believe goes around this right here is a span, should be a span.
And then we have our clipboard.
So let's style result dash container.
Or did I call it a result of results, a result, container wraps around, spin result in the button
and for a result container?
Let's set a background color of our Giba Black and STOO zero point four, and then I'm going to display
flaks.
So all we have is the clipboard icon, the button and the span.
So now those are in Aflex row.
Let's justify content to the beginning.
So Fleck's dash start and then let's align items center and then I'm going to position this relative
and it's because I want to position the button inside of it absolute and then the font size.
Let's increase that to 18 pixels and then we're going to set the letter spacing to one pixel and the
padding will set to twelve on the top and bottom and ten, just not twenty ten on the left and right.
OK, we'll give it a fixed height of fifty and a width of one hundred percent.
All right.
Now for the C, we have a span with a class of results and actually I want that to be an I.D., not
a class, because we're going to insert it from the JavaScript.
Then we're going to inserted into there and I'm going to grab it by the get element by D but I do want
to just add to that, let's say result container I.D. results and I'm going to set the word wrap to
break word and then for the Emacs with I'm actually just going to use Calc here, so say Calc and we
want to take 100 percent and I'm going to subtract 40 pixels from that.
And the reason for that is because the button is going to be 40 pixels and we don't want the result
to go behind the button in this clipboard button is actually going to be positioned over here.
Now, both of these the clipboard in this button, the generate button, both have a class of BTN.
So I'm going to style that first and then we'll we'll style the clipboard button itself or position
it and stuff.
So as far as the button goes, BTN, I'm going to set border to none, so we'll get rid of that and
then let's set the background.
Color is going to be this right here, this three B three B nine eight.
And then the color is going to be white and set the font size to sixteen pixels and let's set some padding.
Padding will be eight pixels, top and bottom, twelve pixels left and right.
And let's set the cursor to a pointer.
All right.
So we style styling both of these because they both have that B10 class, this one has a class of BTN
large.
So I'm just going to add down here, BTM Dash large and I just want to instead of inline, display it
as a block and let's set the width to one hundred percent so it goes across the entire thing.
All right.
Now for this, for the clipboard button that's in the result container.
So what we'll do is take the result container BTN and I'm going to make that a little bigger.
Actually it's position at first, so position it absolute and we're positioning it absolute inside of
the result container, which we set to position relative.
When you want to position something absolute within a certain element, that container element has to
be relative and I want to set it from the top five pixels and from the right five pixels.
Uh, yeah, so we just want to change and make this a little bigger, so we're going to set the width
and the height to 40 pixels on this.
So height, 40 pixels.
There we go.
And then let's also increase the font size to 20.
All right.
So that looks pretty good.
Now, this stuff here, these these all have a class of setting.
So I want to fix how that looks.
So let's go.
I will just go down to the bottom here and say setting and I'm going to display Flex because the setting
has what it has, the label and the input.
So now each setting is a flex box.
And I want to take the I want to take the remaining space that is the horizontal space and set it in
between the both.
So we'll see space between and that will push everything, you know, over to the side because the remaining
space is now between the two flex items.
And then I just want to align itself.
I want to align items center on the horizontal axis, I'm sorry, on the vertical axis and just set
a margin to split them up.
Let's do 15 pixels on the top and bottom like that.
All right.
So I think that looks pretty good.
Yeah, looks good.
So when we generate the password, it'll show up here and the reason I did this, this smacks with Calc
on the result that is going to go on here.
So you're saying Max with will be 100 percent of this whole thing, but minus 40 pixels because the
width of the button is 40 pixels and we don't want it to, you know, run into that.
So now we have our design.
We have the, you know, the look of this, but we still have to make it function.
So in the next video, we're going to start on the JavaScript.