All right, so we're going to get started on our JavaScript here, and I'm not going to say that this
is like an advance project, but a lot of the JavaScript we're going to do here is more in depth than
some of, you know, the majority of the projects that are in this course.
So I'm going to start off by creating a few functions to generate an uppercase letter, a lowercase
letter, a number and a symbol, because we need to do that.
We need to randomly generate these things to create our password and we need to combine them.
So what I'm going to do is create some functions.
So this function is going to be called get random lower.
And it's exactly what it's going to do is return a random lowercase letter.
Now, there's a few ways we can do this.
What I'm going to do is use the string object.
And on that there's a method called from Char Code.
Now, I'm just going to bring this window over for a second here.
So this is the the string object, which is used to represent and manipulate a sequence of characters.
And, you know, there's there's you can you can convert something to a string, but there's a whole
bunch of methods that you can use on this, including from char code.
So the static from char code method returns a string created from the specified sequence of UTF 16 code
units.
So basically we can put a number in here which pertains to and this is just the W3 Schools website,
but you can find these and you know, many different places.
These are the ASCII printable characters and we have our characters over here.
So letters, numbers, symbols, and then they have a specific number or a specific code that pertains
to them.
So if we look at like the numbers here, zero, the code for that is 48 and then it just keeps going.
And the nine is 57.
If we want uppercase letters, starts to 65 and ends at 90, lowercase letters start at 97 and end at
122.
So using this from character code, if I put a 97 in here and then we'll just do a console log of get
random lower and if I go over here, we should get a lowercase A because 97 is the code for lowercase
A, the next letter B would be the code 98.
So that gives me B 122.
Should be A Z.
All right.
So what we want to do is just generate a random lowercase.
So we'll take the 97, which we know is a right lowercase A and two that I want to just multiply any
number up to 26 because there's 26 characters in, you know, 26 letters in the alphabet.
So what we can do is, first of all, first of all, just take math dot floor, which is going to round
down and then math.
So math dot random.
And then I just want to multiply that by the highest random number I want to get, which is 26.
And then I'm going to add to that 97.
So this could be, you know, one plus ninety seven, which would be 98, which would be a B or two
plus ninety seven, which would be C.
So let's just go ahead and save this.
And you can see right away we get a V if I reload W, X, L, Z, so it's just going to be a random,
you know, random lowercase number.
So there's other ways you can do this.
But this is just the way I'm going to do the lowercase, the uppercase and the numbers.
So let's just copy this now and paste that.
And this one is going to be get random upper and we're going to do pretty much the same thing here,
except we want to change the range we still want.
Twenty six is our random number to to add on because we're still dealing with the alphabet.
But we want to change this from 97 to 65 because in that chart I showed you uppercase A. was 65.
OK, so it's going to just be something twenty six, you know, between one and twenty six plus 65.
So if I go ahead and console law, get random upper we get uppercase B, we get O.
S G so it's going to be a random upper case.
Let's do the same for numbers.
So this will be get random number and instead of twenty six we want ten because it's going to be you
know, up to what's going to be zero through nine.
And then we want.
Add on to that 48, because zero has the character, the coat of 48.
So if I go down here and I say, get random number, we get three to five, a five eight one.
All right.
And then four symbols, symbols.
And I'm just going to I just want to use a certain set of symbols.
So let's just we'll just as a function, get random symbol.
And I'm just going to grab this string of symbols here.
So I'm going to say const symbols and set that to a string with these specific symbols in it.
And then we want to get a random one of these so return symbols.
And even though this is a string, we can still use an index.
Like if I get zero symbols, zero, and we go down here, we say, get random symbol, I'm going to
get the the exclamation.
If I do one, I should get the at sign.
So it's zero one, two, three and so on.
So I'm just going to get a random number and here that with a max of the length of the entire string.
So to do that will do math, dot for math, dot random and let's go ahead and multiply that math dot
random by whatever the length of symbols is the length of that string.
So now I see I get a percent if I reload slash.
So I'm just going to get one of these symbols here.
So now we have these four functions and we can implement them into, you know, the rest of the application.
Now, one thing I do want to do before we end this specific video is up here.
I'm going to create a variable called random func because I want it I want to be able to get a random
lowercase, uppercase number, symbol, whatever.
So I'm going to use this object here and give each function a key.
So lower is going to be get get random lower and upper, Olby get random upper and no get random number
and symbol will be get a random symbol.
All right.
So we have this object that has these keys that equal whatever these functions return.
And you'll see why in a little bit when we use these.
But I think we should stop the video here and in the next one will start to work with the DOM and,
you know, start to add some event.
Listeners want to be able to click this button, generate a password based on these functions over here.
We also want to be able to have the function to copy it to the clipboard.
So we'll get to that stuff in the next video.