All right, so we have these functions to generate random lowercase uppercase numbers and symbols.
Now we need to create the functionality for this UI here.
So I'm going to just bring in everything we need.
So first, I'm going to bring in the result element and let's use document dots, get element by D..
We have the idea of results.
So that's going to be the span that is this right here.
This is where we're going to want to show the result.
I'm going to copy this down a few times.
So two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, I think nine.
So all we need and then this is going to be the length.
So let's call this.
Length element, and we should have an I.D..
Yes, we have an I.D. length of uppercase, lowercase and so on, we should have an idea of generate
here.
We should have an idea of clipboard here as well.
So we want to bring all that stuff in so we have length.
Let's do uppercase.
So upper case element, and that has an idea of upper case and lower case.
It's lower case elements and then let's do numbers element.
And then symbol's.
Symbols element, and then this is going to be the generate an element, which is the button.
Generate, and then we have our clipboard.
All right, so that's everything that we want to bring in now, let's start off by creating an event
listener.
I'm going to leave this up top, this index of our, you know, functions down here.
But under that, let's take generates elements and let's add an event listener onto that of a click.
And when that happens, we'll run an arrow function.
And I'm going to get the length element here.
I want to get that and I want to pass it as a number.
So I'm going to call this length.
And we want a length element, dot value, because it's an input.
So we want to get the value and we can easily pass this to a number with just oops, I want to do that.
Just adding a plus sign on to it.
All right.
So if I cancel log here length and we open our console and I click generate, we get 20 and it's a number,
if I take that plus sign away and I generate it's 20, but it's white, it's actually a string.
So this will convert it to a number.
All right.
So we want to get the length we want to get if these are checks we want to know.
So basically, you know, if these two are unchecked and these are checked, we want to know because
we need to know what to generate.
So let's say CONSED has lower and we're going to set that to the lower case element, dot value, which
will either be true or false.
OK, we'll do consentual.
Just copy that down.
So that's lower case than we also on the upper case will call.
This has upper and the Sonobe has no and this is our numbers numbers element and then symbols element
value will be has a symbol and then let's go ahead and just cancel log here.
Has lower, has upper has no and has the symbol.
So if I go ahead and generate we get cannot riprap property value.
Now it's.
Oh, I put value here.
So these are checkboxes, we don't want value, we want checked, so we just want to change these two
checked.
All right, so cook that and we still get that error because a Broca's element that I misspell it up
here, I spell misspelled it right here.
So upper case.
All right, so if I click generate, I get true, I get for True's now, if I take away these two Vij
uncheck these and I check, I get false.
False, true, true.
All right.
So it's going to give us either a true or false.
Now we're going to set let's get rid of the console log.
But keep this and I'm going to say the result elements set the inner text equal to and then we're going
to have a function called generate password and it's going to take in all of this stuff.
And it's also going to take in the length we want the password to be, which is this right here.
OK, so we're just creating a we're going to create a function.
We're going to pass in all this info, which will be the length, as well as all the booleans for each
of these.
So let's create that function.
That's a function, generate a password, and it's going to take in, let's say, lower opper, make
sure it, you know, reflects what we're passing into it.
So lower upper number and symbol and length.
OK, so it's going to take in this stuff here and then let's let's go ahead and just initialize a variable
called generated password, which is going to represent the passwords generated and it's going to be
just empty by default.
Then I want to get the types count.
So what I mean by types is, you know, this lower upper number and symbol.
So and what is true, so let's say const low, not consed lower const types count and set that to lower
plus upper plus number plus symbol.
OK, and we can go ahead and console log and see what that gives us.
If I do type's count submit that we give for if I uncheck two of these I get two.
So it's going to give me the count of, you know, how many are selected.
Now I want to actually create an array of types.
So let's say const types array and let's set that to an array.
And inside here, we want to wrap these in curly braces lower.
What I want to end up with is something that looks like this.
So an array with objects that have like lower true that would be like the first one and then we'd have
upper true or false.
So that's what I want this to look like.
So we're going to say lower.
Upper.
Number and symbol of should a Akama.
OK.
And if we cancel like that, and I'm just console logging everything so you can see exactly what it
gives us.
So here we just have an array and we have lower, you know, true.
Uncheck those, we get lower false, upper false and so on.
However, what I want to do is if it's false, like if these two are false, I don't even want them
in this array.
So this should ultimately be just two with the truth.
So we can do that by filtering this array.
So this type array equals array, dot filter and we'll save for each item.
We're going to use object dot values of that particular item and we want the first item.
So basically what this will do is filter out anything that has false as a value.
So now if I save this and I uncheck the first two and I generate now you can see I only get number and
symbol because those are the only ones that are checked instead of getting all four and just saying
false, if I check all of these, then we get four that are all true.
OK, so next thing, now that we have that.
Let's let's check and see if if there's no time, because if nothing is actually checked, we just we
don't want to do anything right.
And notice this says undefined right now.
That's that's fine for now.
So I'm going to check if we can do this by checking the types count, which I defined above.
If that types count is equal to zero, then let's just return it.
We'll return nothing, an empty string.
So up here, I mean, if I do that, we get undefined.
But if I uncheck everything and generate we get nothing, which is fine.
That's what we want is we're not checking any of these.
All right.
Now to actually create the password here.
Like all the characters, we're going to create a for loop.
And we have all that.
We have these functions down here.
We have basically an index of them here.
So lower upper number symbol.
And those should match these lower upper numbers symbol.
And we're going to do a for loop here.
Let's say let equals zero.
And we want to say if I is less than the length.
OK, so meaning this right here.
In this case, it's 20 by default.
And then we want to increment I we want to increment I with the count, whatever the count is.
So types count so plus equals types count, which is going to be, you know, whatever we check here.
So in this loop, let's take the types array and we want to loop through that with a for each and say
for each type.
For each type, let's construct will safe funk name and basically want to get.
From this type here, because this is let me just console log this, actually, if I console logotype,
let's just see what we get.
So I'll generate we get a number.
So no true symbol.
True lower.
True upper.
I mean, they're all going to be true, but it's no symbol, lower upper, no symbol.
OK, so, I mean, it's always going to be in that order.
You could randomize it, but I think it's fine.
It's going to be a random number symbol, lower, upper.
So what we want to do with that is get the function for number symbol lower, upper based on this up
here.
So it'll basically get, you know, what's return from that specific function.
And we can do that, let's say const func name.
And if we use the object keys method in passing the type, we want to get the first value.
So zero.
And just to show you what that gives us, let's do a console log of func type.
So that gives us not.
Func type.
Func name.
So that gives us up or no symbol lower now we can take this random funk object here, which has these
as keys and we want to call that so let's say generated password generated, not generate generated
password is the string that is empty right now.
And we want to spend on to that.
So plus equals we're going to depend on to it and then take our random func object and then pass in
as an index, whatever the funk name is.
OK, which will be these here and we want to call the function, so we want to put a parentheses there.
So this is going to basically just loop through however whatever the length is and we're going to end
up with a random uppercase.
No, I'm sorry, uppercase.
What's the order here?
Lowercase, uppercase, number, symbol, lowercase, uppercase, no symbol.
It's going to be in that same order, but it'll it'll be generated and it'll be different every time
we generate.
And it's going to do that up until this length.
Now we want to return that from this function.
So we need to go outside of this whole for loop here and then let's say const final password and we'll
set that to generated password, make sure it's generated and not generate because that's the name of
the function.
And we're going to use slice here, which we're going to slice.
So we're going to get from zero to whatever the length is, which is 20 by default.
And then we're going to return that final password.
All right.
And whatever is returned from generate password, remember, gets put into the inner text of the result
element, which is this.
So if I click generate, we're going to get 20 random characters.
If I change that to five and I click generate OK, if I want, let's get rid of symbols and numbers
and I want to click this and generate I'm still going to get five characters, but they're only going
to be made up of, you know, uppercase and lowercase letters.
All right, now, no matter what the length is, like I said, it's always going to be the same order
of types, which is lowercase, uppercase symbol.
Actually, there's no number because I left that unchecked.
If there was and it would be number and then, you know, lowercase, uppercase symbol, lowercase,
uppercase symbol.
So it'll be that same type order.
And you can you can add some more code here if you want to randomize that, maybe that can be looked
at as a challenge for you.
But I'm just going to leave it as that.
It's always going to be something different, you know, it's just the same type order.
So that's it.
For that part of this, the next thing we want to do is be able to click this and have it in our clipboard
so I can come down and I can, you know, I can paste it somewhere.
So that's what we're going to work on next.