OK, so now we want to make this clipboard button work, so we already have our clipboard element that
we brought in, I'm going to go right above our generate element event listener and let's say clipboard
11 dot out event listener.
And we want to listen for a click event and then we're on a function.
And the way we're going to do this is first create a text area so we can use the document object in
the create element method to create a text area element.
And then I'm going to have a variable called password where we take whatever is in this result.
Hey, this is the right here result element, so we'll set that to result l dots and then we want the
inner text of that to be put in password.
And if there's no password, so we'll say if no password then we're just going to return.
Right.
So if we just click in here, it's just going to return and do nothing.
If there's no password, if there is, then let's take the text area dot value and we're going to set
it to whatever that password is.
Then we want to document take the body and we're going to pen child, meaning we're going to take the
text area and put it into the body and then we can use that text area and call a method called select.
So that will just select everything in the text area.
And then there's on the document object, we have a method called a command and we want to pass in here
copy because we want to copy whatever is selected and then we want to remove the text area from the
DOM.
So let's say text area remove and then we're just going to show an alert and we'll say the password
is copied to the clipboard.
All right.
So save that and let's see if this works.
I'm going to generate a password.
I'm going to click on this password copied to clipboard.
I'm just going to go down to my console and command V and then we go.
So now we can copy our password.
We do like a five password with just numbers and symbols.
If I click that, it's copied.
If I go down here and I paste it in.
There we go.
All right.
So now able to generate a random password based on these selections and we can copy it to the clipboard.