All right, so this is just going to be a fun little project where we actually take some checkboxes
and we style them to look like these little sliders here with these little balls that we can animate
back and forth.
OK, so we're going to add a little bit of success and style them with success and then add some animations
to give it this effect.
And then finally, we're going to add a little bit of JavaScript logic, because when you have a project,
you rarely get it to be good, cheap and fast.
So basically, if we choose good cheap and then we click fast, it's going to uncheck cheap sex.
So we might get it to be good and fast, but then it's not going to be cheap.
We can do cheap and fast and we can do cheap and good, but we can't do all three because that's very
rare.
So it's just a little it's just fun to add a little bit of logic to it.
But, you know, you can use these little slider widgets inside of your user interfaces and Web sites.
So let's go ahead and get started.