All right, so let's get started, I just have my project starter open here and we're going to change
the title here to let's call it good, cheap, fast.
And basically we're going to have just some checkboxes, but we're going to style them to look really
cool.
We're going to add some animation and we're going to add some logic so that you can't pick, for instance,
all three because it's hard to get a project that's a good, cheap and fast it'll be.
They're cheap and fast or cheap and good.
So we'll add some logic with JavaScript later on.
So let's go ahead and add here.
I'm actually going to use an H two here.
So let's put an H two and say, how do you want your project to be?
And then we'll have our toggle.
So we're going to have three separate divs with the class of toggle container that are going to surround
the input, the label and the text, the spane text.
So let's create toggle dash container and in here let's put an input with the type of checkbox.
And we don't need a name.
We don't need a name for the I.D., we'll say good and let's also give it a class of Torkel.
OK, so that's our input.
Now we want a label because when you have a label for a form field, you can click on that label and
it will in this case, it'll check or uncheck the check box.
So let's say label for good.
So the I.D. should match the ID for the input, should match the four attribute on the label.
And then I'm also going to give this a class of label and then inside the label we're going to have
a class of ball.
So this is going to be the you know, the round part of the the the slider, whatever you want to call
it, that's going to go back and forth that we're going to animate.
So we're not going to put anything in this div.
We just want to have it here for styling.
And then outside of the label, we're going to have a span with the text.
So this will say good.
I will say that it's not going to look very good until we add our success, but we want three of these.
So this div of toggle container, I'm going to just grab that space that in here and here and then just
change.
The second one is going to be cheap.
So we'll change this.
Actually, this idea right here, the four and that's too cheap.
And just going to add uppercase here.
No, I have cheap in the last one is going to be fast.
So let's change this too fast and just make this uppercase
that and that should do it for the HDMI.
Also pretty simple.
Now the success is going to really change how this looks.
So we have quite a bit to do here.
Not all, not too much, but we're going to do some animation.
Let's start off with the body here.
So we'll just stick with the Raboteau font display, flex line items we don't need.
Well, yeah, we'll keep the column.
I don't think we have to change anything here so we can just leave that.
So let's start to style the toggle container.
So the toggle container, I'm going to display Flex and I want to use a line.
Items here to display everything are aligned to the center.
I'm going to add a margin here of ten pixels on the top and bottom and then a width of 200 pixels to
remember the container wraps around the input, the label and the span text.
Now, the class of toggle,
so we have the class of Torgau, which is the on the input itself, the checkbox, we don't want to
show that because we're basically replacing that with the cool ball look or whatever that whatever you
want to call it, the slider, the ball, whatever.
So let's grab the toggle class and I'm going to set the visibility to hidden.
So now we can't see the actual checkbox.
Now we have the label
and for the label, let's give this a whiff.
We'll give it a width of 40 or 80 pixels and then let's give it a height of forty pixels.
OK, so, I mean, it's just it's here.
You can't see it yet.
So let's give it a background color of grey.
So we're going to use D zero three times here.
There we go.
We want it wanted to have really rounded corners.
So I'm going to set the border radius to 50 pixels like that and we want to set a cursor pointer.
So when we hover over it, we have a cursor.
I'm going to display it as an inline block because it's in line by default.
And I want to be able to add a margin of do zero 15 zero.
OK, so I kind of put some space around it and that actually should do it for the label itself.
Now, if it's checked, then I want the background color of the label to change.
So what we can do is take the toggle, which is the checkbox, and we can say colon checked, which
means when it's in, it's checked state, then we want to style the label and set the background color.
I'm going to set it to hexadecimal value eight E four for a D like that.
Now, as soon as I do that, the first one is purple because it's checked.
If I click it again, it's going to uncheck and it's going to be gray.
OK, so we can now do this.
Now the next thing I want to do is the ball.
We want to have that little circle inside so we have a class of ball and let's set the background for
that to white, which you're not going to see because it doesn't have any content and it also doesn't
have a height or width.
So let's set the height to thirty four pixels and also the width.
Let's set that to thirty four pixels.
OK, so you can see the the white square in here.
We want it to be round so let's set border radius to 50 percent.
OK, and then we want to position it.
So let's position this absolute and we're actually going to want to have the label position relative
because we're positioning the ball absolu within the label.
So the label then has to be positioned relative.
So let's add that here relative.
OK, so we're going to position absolute.
And then as far as where we want to put it inside the label, let's do three pixels from the top and
let's do three pixels from the left.
OK, so it fits right in there, nice and snug.
And it's also just a line items center and justify content center as well.
OK, now when I click, you can see it just turns purple.
We don't have the animation here.
So what we'll do in the next video is add the animation.
So when we click, it slides over and click again, slides back.