OK, so now we want to create the animation for the ball to move back and forth when we click it, so
we're going to have two animation.
So let's create those will say keyframes.
This one is going to be called slide on.
And this is just going to have it go from here to here.
And we're going to do that by just changing the value of the translate x axis.
So we'll use a transform property and set to translate X to be further over.
We'll also scale it a bit.
So let's go ahead and say at zero percent of this animation, we want to transform and we're going to
set translate X because we're moving it on the X axis right to left or left to right.
In this case, we're going to start at zero and the scale is going to start at just one, which is what
it is by default.
And then at 50 percent, we want to set transform to translate X and go from zero to twenty pixels and
then set the scale to one point two and then at 100 percent.
So say 100 percent, we want to transform, translate acts and this is going to be 40 pixels and set
scale back to one.
OK, so that's the slide on.
The slide off is basically just going to be this backwards.
So I'm going to just copy this and let's set this to slide off.
And zero percent is going to be at 40 pixels because it's going to be at the end scale one.
And then second is going to be the same 20 pixels and then third or 100 percent, I should say, is
going to be back at zero with a scale of one.
OK, so pretty simple animations.
Now, we need to implement this because, you know, we haven't added it to anything.
So for the ball, let's add animation and we want to set this to slide off and say zero point three
seconds for the duration.
We want it to be linear and forwards.
All right, and you can see as soon as I save, since I'm using live server, it automatically reloads.
It shows you that animation.
Now when we click on it, we check it.
We want to run slide on.
Right.
So let's go right here.
In the way we can target this with our success is the toggle, which is the checkbox input when it's
checked.
OK, so Colin checked OK means in the checked state.
Then we want to add the label class and then the ball class.
That's what we want to animate.
OK, so this is basically by default it'll have the slide off, but when it's checked it'll run slide
on.
So let's set animation to slide on zero point three seconds, linear and forwards.
OK, so save that.
And now since the first one is checked, you'll see that it's pushed over to the side.
If I reload this, they're all going to be unchecked.
But now if I click that, click that, that, and then if I click it again, it removes the checked
and it runs this, which is slide off, which brings it back over because of where we're setting it
on the x axis.
All right.
So we have that part done.
Now, the only thing we have left is the logic because we don't want to be able to say good, fast and
cheap, because that's very rare that you get that.
So we'll be able to do like cheap and good or cheap and fast.
So we'll add a little bit of JavaScript to this next.