OK, so in the last video, we did our little animation, and right now we can put these wherever we
want, but I want to make it so that if we try to do all three, it's not going to let us do good,
cheap and fast.
So we want to have it.
So, you know, it can do cheap and good.
It can do cheap and fast, but it can't do all three.
So first thing I want to do is bring in everything we need.
Let's bring in the toggles, which is the checkbox themselves.
So let's say document dot, query selector, all because there's more than one and we want all the ones
of the class of toggle and then let's get each.
Basically we want to grab, you know, the the label.
I'm not not the label but the idea of good, cheap and fast.
So toggles gets all of these, but we want each individual one by its side.
So here we'll say I good.
This is going to be query selector and set this to good.
And then this one here is going to be cheap query selector and let's do I d of cheap and then this is
going to be fast so I'd fast.
Make sure you use query selector since it's a single element and fast.
So we were bringing in everything we need.
Now I'm going to take toggles and I'm going to loop through with a for each and see for each toggle.
Let's add an event listener.
So say toggle dot add event listener and the event is going to be a change.
When you have a checkbox and you want to add an event to it, you want to use change, not click.
So when that runs will have a function and we're going to have a function run called Do the Trick.
And passing the target value, which is the whatever we select and we have to pass in here our event
object.
OK, so now each time we click on one of these, it's going to, you know, fire off the change event
and it's going to do the trick and pass in whatever the target is passing that element.
So let's create a function called Do the Trick and it's going to take in we'll call the collect one.
That's what it is.
It's the one we clicked on.
And we want to check first to see if all three are checked so we can say if good dot checked, because
when you have a checkbox, you bring it into the dorm.
You can you can access if it's checked or not with Dorchak, then it'll be a true or false.
So we'll say if good is checked, if cheap is checked and if fast.
Checked.
OK, so if that's true, let's say if good is equal to the clipped one.
So basically the you know, the clipped one, meaning the target that's passed, and then we're going
to say fast dot checked and we want to uncheck it.
So we're going to set that to false.
OK, and then let's say if.
Cheap is the correct one.
OK, so if we click on cheap, then we'll take good and let's get checked and set that to false.
And then if we have fast that's clicked, then we want to set cheap checked to false.
All right, so let's save that.
Now, if I go on a good cheap and then I click fast, you'll see cheap automatically slide back over
because it's it's set back to false right here.
OK, if I click cheap then good is going to be unchecked.
If I click good fast is going to be unchecked.
OK, if if cheap is already selected we can do good and not cheap and not fast.
We can do fast.
Not cheap, not good.
We can do cheap and fast or good.
But we can't do all three.
Ah it's very rare at least.
So it's just a fun little project.
And you know, you could use these nice sliders, these style checkboxes in your UI.
The, the logic here was just really for fun.
But that's it.
Let's go ahead and get started on the next one.