So in this project, we're going to build a notes app and we're actually going to be able to save these
notes to local storage, so we'll be using the local storage API, which is built into the browser.
So I have nothing here but an add note button.
And if I click that, it's going to add this little note here so I can click in here and I can type,
you know, hello world or whatever.
And this here is going to toggle.
This is the edit button.
It'll toggle from text area to just a regular div that shows the text.
All right.
I can add another one.
Say hello again.
All right.
So we have two notes here.
And if I reload, they're going to stay because they're saved in local storage.
If I delete this, I reload.
It's going to stay the same because, again, it's being saved to the browser.
It's being saved in local storage.
Another thing we can do is use markdown because we're going to be using a small library called Markt.
So if I want this to be a heading, I could do a number sign.
I'm not going to go through all the markdown syntax, but you can look up that.
You can look at that on your own.
I do have a crash course on YouTube, on markdown.
If we want to do like an unordered list, we could do like hyphen space.
And if we take a look at that outside of edit mode, we have a heading and an list list.
OK, if I reload is going to stay because again, being saved.
So I think it's a it's a pretty neat application if you're learning, you know, local storage and how
to work with the DOM, add and remove things and so on.
All right.
So let's go ahead and get started.