OK, so we should be able to get the Temel on the CSFs done here now, ultimately all we're going to
have in the TML is an add button to add a note and then the note will be put in via JavaScript.
But for now, like with many other projects, we're going to just type out the HTML first so we can
style it and then we'll get rid of it.
We'll make it dynamic so we can insert a note with the JavaScript.
Now I have my project starter and I have a link to the font awesome CDN so that we can use icons.
There's one other small library we're going to use called Markt.
So I'm going to go to NJ Ask.com and just search for Markt, which allows us to use markdown.
It will allow us to use markdown in our notes.
So if we want to make something bold, we can, you know, surround it in asterisks.
We can create lists and headings and stuff like that.
So I'm going to just copy the script tag here and I'm going to put it right above the script.
Yes.
OK, so we're just going to include that CDN and then we'll be able to use the marked library.
Now, as far as the HTML goes, like I said, we're going to have an add, but actually it's out of
title first.
So just call this notes app and then we're going to have our add button.
So it'll be a button.
Let's give it a class of add and an idea of add and then it's going to use font.
Awesome.
So we'll do an ID tag with Faez in the class of a dash plus which will give us a little plus sign and
after that we'll say add note.
OK, so that gives us a button.
Now like I said, we're going to be inserting notes through JavaScript, but for now we'll go ahead
and just type it out so it'll have a class of note, each one.
And then inside here we're going to have a class of tools.
And this is where the edit and delete buttons are going to go.
So we're going to say, button, let's give us a class of edits and inside here will have an icon.
So IFRS and then F.A.A. dash edits and it's just going to be the icon.
No text, then the copy that down and this is going to be a trash dash ALZ and the class for this button
will be delete.
All right.
So now we have our added delete button for our note underneath Tool's.
We're going to have a div and the way this will work is will have a div and then we'll have a text area
and get rid of all this stuff.
And depending on the state of the note, it d may or may not have a class of hidden.
So I'm going to add a class here of hidden, which is just going to be basically display none and I'm
going to leave it off the text area so it'll be active by default.
But like I said, these notes are going to be put in through JavaScript and these classes will be dynamic
depending on if there's text or not.
So that should do it for the HTML.
Let's jump into the stylesheet here and we're going to use the Poppins font with a weight of 200 and
400 and will replace this Poppins, OK, and then display flaks.
We don't need Flex Direction column, but I am going to set Flex wrap and set that to wrap so that the
notes will go on to the next line when needed.
And then let's see, we don't really need to do the A line items or the justify content or the height
or the overflow because we might have scroll bars.
If we have enough notes, margin zero will keep that and then I'm going to add some padding to the top.
We'll do three REM units for that.
All right.
Now the add button.
Let's do that.
So this I'm actually going to position this fixed into the into the body.
So let's say position fixed and then let's put this from the top.
We'll do one room, which is just a multiplier of the the root HTML element, which by default is sixteen
pixels.
So we're seeing top sixteen pixels from the top and also from the right.
OK, so it's going to put that right there.
Now we want to style this, so let's add a background color to this and we're going to use the hexadecimal
value of nine c eight six to go down here a little bit.
Let's take away the border border none.
Let's add a border radius of, say, three pixels and then four padding.
We'll do zero point five REM top and bottom one left and right.
And let's make the color white, which will actually move up here.
And then let's do the cursor pointer.
And that should do it, so we have our ad note button up in the corner.
Now we want to style the note, which has a class of note.
So let's say note, and I'm going to set the background color to white and then let's do a box shadow.
And for the box shadow, the offsets will set to zero 10 pixel for pixel and then Najiba Black with
zero point one alpha gives it a slight shadow and then let's add some margin.
So 30 pixels top and bottom, 20 pixels left and right, and then let's set height.
So a fixed height of 400 pixels and a width of 400 pixels.
And of course you could change this stuff if you'd like.
All right.
So that's kind of the outline of the of the note.
Now, for this part, here we have the edit and delete button.
Remember, that has a class of tools.
So let's say note tools and go ahead style that area.
So it's going to have a background color of hexadecimal, nine E, C, eight, six to also give a background
and then let's display flex so the buttons will be flex items and then we're going to justify the content
to flex and that'll put them over to the right.
And let's add some padding to the flex container to the tools.
So the zero point five REM.
OK, now we want to style the buttons as well.
So let's see note and then the tools class and then the button for the buttons inside.
Let's give them a background color of transparent.
Let's get rid of the border.
So border none.
Let's make the color white and let's set the cursor to be a pointer.
I'm also going to change the font size to one ram and add a margin left of a half ram.
All right, so I think that looks pretty good for our buttons now for the text area, let's say notes,
text area.
So I want to get rid of any outline.
So outline none.
And let's make sure the family is inherited and let's set the font size to one point to room and set
the border to none.
OK, and then we'll set the height to 400 pixels, which is the same as the note, and the width will
just set to 100 percent of its container, which is the note.
And then padding.
I'm going to add 20 pixels padding so it's not right up against the edge.
So now we can, you know, type in this text area.
One thing that I realize, though, I forgot to add the background color to the body.
So let's go up here and add background color and I'll set that to a light blue.
So it's going to be seven BD a F three for that.
OK, so that gives it some contrast.
And then the last thing is just didn't want to do that.
The last thing is to add a class of hidden and hidden is just going to be display none, which will
be able to add to the elements that we need to later on.
OK, now if we add another note, like if I take this whole div right here and just copy it down a couple
of times, you'll see that it'll add more notes.
And if I make this bigger, it's going to, you know, align horizontal, but it'll wrap when we when
we're on smaller screen.
So it's pretty much, you know, inherently responsive.
So we'll just leave it as is and now we can get rid of let's just undo that and that.
And I'm just going to leave one of these notes here for now.
But ultimately, we won't need it here because it's going to get inserted when we click add node.
OK, so we'll get into the JavaScript to be able to do that next.