All right, so now we're going to start on the JavaScript and ultimately this is going to come from
the JavaScript.
But one thing I want to do is on this div here, I want to add a class of Maine, and this just represents
where the text will show when we're not in edit mode because the text area will be hidden when when
we're not in edit mode.
And then when we toggle it with this and we go to edit mode, then the text area will show.
So I'm actually going to just get rid of that hidden class for now and then let's let's grab everything
within this div.
So I'm just going to cut that and then just delete this because we're going to create this with JavaScript
and then we'll just insert what I just covid.
So I'll save that and go to my script and let's bring in our add button.
So say add Vitton equals documents dot get element by D.
We want to grab the idea of add then we want to add an event listener.
So add button dot add event listener.
Listen for a click and when that happens we'll have an arrow function and then we'll call a function
called add a new note.
And down here let's create that function.
So add new note which is going to take in an optional text argument which will set to nothing by default.
And then I want to build that that div with the class of notes, it will say const note equals and then
on a document object we'll call create elements and we want to create a div.
And then I want to just add the class of note to that.
So we'll say note class list, not add and add the class of note.
Then we want to take that note and set the inner HTML equal to a set of tactics.
And this is where I'm going to paste in what I copied and we'll just kind of clean this up a little
bit.
Yes, we'll just move this over, OK, and then down here.
So basically if there's text, we want to add the class of hidden on the text area.
So both of these classes where we're going to add a dynamic class.
So right here, let's open up our our expression syntax with money sine curly brace inside the class
quotes.
And I'm going to say if text then have no class else then have a class of hidden, which is display
none, and then on the text area will do the opposite.
Right.
So say class and we'll say if there's text then have the class of hidden inside the text area or else
have no class.
OK, and then to put this into the DOM, we can take our document body, which is just, you know,
the the browser body and append child meaning we want to add something in it and we want to add the
note every time we click the button.
So now click it, click it again and it adds the notes to the DOM and they're in text area mode by default.
Now this right here can we can add something in here, like to put a string and just say hello world.
Now, if I save that and I add a note, notice how I can't click in here because of this right here.
We're saying for this div, if there's text, which we did pass in, then have no class here and down
here, if there's text and hide the text area.
OK, so we passed in text.
So it's not a text area.
If we do it without passing anything in it is a text area.
Now we want to make these buttons function as far as in this video will go as far as the dorm.
So like deleting it from the dorm and toggling the hidden on these two.
But we're not going to get into local storage until the next video.
But let's inside this add new note before we add it to the dorm, let's bring in from the note, the
edit button.
So edit BTN and we can actually take from the note, this current note, we want to query selector and
we want the class of edit.
Right.
And then I'm going to copy this down.
We want for these because we also want to get the delete.
So this is going to be the delete button and then we want to get the main.
So that's class of main and then we want the text area.
So I'm just going to grab it by text area and we'll call this text uppercase A.
Area and then let's add an event onto delete, so will take the delete delete button and add event listener,
want to listen for a click and when we click, we'll call a function.
And for now we're just going to remove it from the dorm.
So we'll take that specific note and we'll just call remove, which does just that.
It just takes it away from the dawn.
So if I go on, I add a note, I'll add another one.
If I click on the trash icon now, I can delete them, OK, or remove them.
Now for edit, what we want to happen is we want to be able to toggle main and text area.
So I'll just just grab that and change this to edit.
OK, so when we click on edit, what we're going to want to do here is take main class list and toggle
the hidden class.
OK, we're going to do the same thing for text area.
So text area, make sure you use the uppercase A version.
And now you can see when I when I first click it, we have a text area.
If I click edit now I can't now it's now the main is showing the div with the class of main so text
area main type in here.
Can't type in here.
OK, and that's all I wanted to do for now.
Now if there is text passed in to the function like
Hello World, I want to be able to see that here.
So I'm going to go right, right below where we were.
We brought in all this stuff and let's say text area and set the value to text.
Now, I also want to set the main area.
So I'm going to say main dot in our HTML over text area has a value.
So you don't do text area in HTML.
Main is a div.
So I'm going to set the entire HTML to the text, but I want it to be markdown so we can use the marked
library by just simply wrapping this in marked.
So if we save that and if I click add note I already had Hello world in there.
So this is the text now.
This is the main version.
I can't edit it and then if I click edit it's the same thing now I want to make it so that if I update
this like I change that high and then I click that, that shows here as well.
So what we can do is add an event listener on to the text area.
So let's say text area dot add event listener and we want to listen for any input on that text area.
And when that happens, we're going to run a function with the event object and we want to get the value.
We want to get e dot target dot value and I'm going to use D structuring to pull out value from target.
So since value is on target, I can use curly braces here and say const value and take that from E target
and then I'm going to take main and update the inner HTML to the marked version of that value.
So let's save that.
And now if I go here and I change this to high and I click that, you'll see that also says hi because
as I type in the text area, this is going to update.
Now, since we're using the marked library, we should be able to add markdown.
So let's do a heading will say like list.
So no sign, I'll be an H1, H2, H3, etc. and then we could do like an order list with hyphens.
I'm not going to go over like all the markdown syntax, but it's pretty easy to learn.
I have a mark down crash course on YouTube and if I click that now, you can see we actually have a
heading and we have our list items.
We should probably add some padding to that, I think.
Yeah, we added padding to the text area right here.
So let's also add to main padding.
Yeah, there we go.
All right, cool.
Now, it just it still says, hello, world, when I delete and I create a new one because that's just
coming from here and we don't actually want anything to start with.
Right.
And we can you know, we can put something in here and it shows in both text area and main.
But when I reload, the note goes away.
So what we want to work on next, since we have, you know, the functionality that we have so far in
terms of the DOM, we want to be able to save these to local storage and in the browser.
We want to also fetch them from a local storage and show, you know, each note inside of an actual
note.
So we'll get into that next.