All right, so now we want to implement local storage so that when we add a note here, it basically
gets saved in our browser, gets saved in local storage, which is a it's a native browser API.
It's not like an extra library or anything that we have to add or we don't need a CD and or anything.
So basically to set items, we would say local storage dot set item and we could set a key like name
and we could set a value like Brad.
So that's how we would set something to get something.
We would say local storage doget item and we would get a name and that would give us Brad.
So it's pretty simple.
It's just key value pairs.
In fact, they can go ahead and save this and just run this and we can check what we have in local storage,
in our dev tools if we go to the application tab and if I go down to storage, local storage and my
local host, you'll see I have this key value pair with the key is name the values Brad.
And then to get rid of it, if you want to delete something, you can say local storage, dot, remove
item name.
And now if I save this in this reloads, it does create it, but then it removes it and you can see
there's nothing there.
So the API is pretty simple to work with now.
We can only store String's in local storage and if you want to store an object or an array, like maybe
you have an array with, you know, I.D. one or whatever, you can't store it like this.
It has to actually be stratified.
So it has to be a string.
And you can do that with a method called that, a method called Jason Dot String Afie.
And you can pass in, you know, whatever that object to object is or array or whatever.
And then when you pull it out, you just have to wrap this in Jason Dot Pass and that would pass it
as an array or object or whatever you want it to be.
All right.
So with that said, let's have a function here called update URLs.
So this is going to update our local storage and we're going to run this whether we delete or we're
adding notes.
So we'll start with adding.
So in our text area when we're typing out, I'm actually going to call after we add it to the, you
know, the main entry HTML.
I'm going to call update.
OK, and then down here, let's say const notes text and I'm going to say document dot, query selector
all.
And I want to get all of the text areas.
OK, so say text area and then I'm going to create an array here called Notes and Empty Array and I
want to take the notes, text and loop through because this gives me a no list.
So basically all the text areas I have and I'm going to loop through with a free agency for each note,
we're going to go ahead and take that notes array and we're going to push onto it.
So we're going to add to add to the end of it, whatever the note dot value.
OK, and this note, this is the you know, for each no will add the value to the array.
So what I'm going to do now is just
I'm going to console log the notes array.
It says we have not doing anything with local storage yet, but we just want to store it as a string
of fine array.
So I'm going to just go to my console here and I'm going to add a note and type in here and you'll see
that everything I'm typing is getting stored inside of this array.
So this is an array with just a single item, actually.
Let's make this a little more clear.
So I'll say item one.
So we have an array with one string unit called item one.
If I create another note and I put in here item two, the second item is whatever is in this second
note.
So this array is what I want to store in local storage.
Right.
So what we'll do is, you know what?
I just showed you local storage.
And we want to set an item I'm going to call the key of this is going to be notes and that I want to
store my notes array.
However, I can't just store it as an array.
Right.
I have to Jason Dot string of Afie and then go ahead and add that our surround that.
So now let's go ahead and add something here.
I'll say item or let's say note one.
I'm going to add a new note and say notes to now if I look in my application tab.
You'll see in my local storage, I have it's a string of fine array of right here, No.
One, and I'll just make this a little bigger so you can see so we have no one to know to stored in
local storage.
OK, now we want to load this, like if I reload the page, it's not showing in the dorm, but it is
in local storage, so I want to fetch it and display those notes.
So up at the top here.
Let's go right here and let's say CONSED notes and we want to pull this from local storage.
So remember, we use local storage to get item and we want to get the notes.
However, we don't want it to be a string, we want it passed as an array.
So I'm going to wrap this in JSON dot pass.
OK, so now if I console log notes and we go down here to our console, we're going to see the notes
that we have in local storage.
And then what we'll do is get rid of that and let's check for notes.
So if there's notes in local storage, then let's loop through, let's say, notes for each.
And we're going to say for each note, I want to call add new no, which adds it to the dorm.
And for the text, it'll be that that particular note.
So let's save.
And there he goes.
Now, I have two notes.
One has no one written in it.
One has No.
Two written in it.
And that's what we have in our local storage.
Now to delete is going to be very simple.
We can just simply go down here to where we remove from the dorm, because right now I can I can delete
from the dorm.
But if I reload, it's still there.
Right?
We have an update, local storage, so we can just simply now call updates, local storage inside the
delete.
So now if I delete, that goes away.
And if I reload, that's still gone.
If I look in my application tab.
We only have no one.
If I click delete there now, it's empty, if I reload nothing.
All right.
So it's that's a pretty simple way to be able to add and remove.
Basically, we have a crawdad application.
We can create, read, update and delete notes.
And I mean, if I add if I add No.
One and note two, that gets saved.
Right.
And then if I edit No.
Two and change it to note three and then reload, it stays at No.
Three, because every time I type in to these text areas, it's updating my local storage.
It's calling this function here and getting all the text areas.
It's slipping through those and adding whatever is in each one to an array, and then it's saving that
array in local storage as a string.
And then we're pulling it out up here, parsing it from a string to an array, checking for it and then
adding it to the DOM with add new note.
And of course, in addition to that, we can add markdown.
So if I make this heading and we'll just say, I don't know, I'm.
OK, so that displays the markdown and if we look at what we have in local storage, it's going to be
a string version of this.
So it has like the you know, the numbers sign and then it has these things here, the hyphens, but
it's going to pass markdown.
All right.
So that's it.
Hopefully found this useful.
And if you didn't know about local storage, you can use it, you know, for many different things.
Very it's very helpful.
Even if I closed the browser and come back, it'll be there.
If you want, you can use section storage as well.
I might as well mention this.
So if you section storage, it works the same way you have the same methods and stuff.
But if you close the browser and come back, it'll be gone.
Local storage will keep it there until it's it's cleared.
And you can also use local storage clear to clear everything you could even out of clear notes button
for that.
That may be like something that you can add yourself.
All right.
So that's it.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next project.