All right, so in this project, we're going to be building an animated countdown and what you're seeing
right here is basically the final message or the final state.
But if I click replay or I just reload the page, you can see we get a really cool looking animation
from three to zero.
And of course, you could you can make it whatever numbers you want, whatever range you want.
And it's something you could put before your website loads or before your application loads.
We just have a very simple screen here, but this could be your website or whatever, and we can just
click replay to make this keep happening.
So what we're going to do here is deal with CSFs animations, keyframes.
We're going to be using the transform property with translate rotate scale and then we're going to use
some JavaScript to basically check certain conditions and either add or remove certain classes based
on those conditions.
Because we need to know, you know, are we should we add the in class or the out class to to create
the rotation or should we stop it?
Are we at the end of the numbers and so on.
So there's a little bit of logic that we have to add with JavaScript.
But what we do in quite a bit with keyframes, animations.
All right.
So let's get into it.