All right, so we're going to get started here, I have the final project open and you'll see that there's
basically two screens or two states.
We have the countdown and then we have this final message.
So we're going to start off with the HTML, creating those two sections and then we'll go ahead and
we'll start to style it.
So I just have my project starter boilerplate open here and I'm just going to change the title to,
let's say, animated countdown and get rid of that H1.
So basically, like I said, we have two sections.
We have the counter.
So that's going to be the numbers and that's going to be the heading that says get ready.
And then under that so under that closing div, we're going to have a class of final, which is going
to be that, you know, the button, the replay and so on.
So inside counter, we want to have a class called Nums, OK, Nums.
So that's going to wrap the numbers which are going to be in Span's.
So there's going to be four altogether.
So we'll create four spans with the numbers, three to one and zero.
And what we want to do here, since we only want one number to show at a time, we're going to have
a class of N and whatever.
Ultimately, whatever number has that class is going to be the number that comes in that's showing,
OK, now under these spans and then under this div, we're just going to have in each four and we're
just going to say get ready.
And then down here in the final class here, this div we're going to put in, each one says go and we're
going to have a button to replay it.
So I'm going to give this an idea of replay so we can grab on to it in the JavaScript later on and we'll
just say replay.
All right.
So that should be it.
Now we can see both sections, the counter and final right now, but we're going to only show one at
a time and we'll do that from within the success.
So let's jump into the styling.
So as far as the the the base styling here, one thing I'm going to do is get rid of the flex.
We are going to have everything centered, but we're going to do it in a different way.
We're going to use Tranz, Transform, Translate so we can get rid of these lines here.
And then the only other thing I want for the body is just to zero out the margin.
OK, now everything's going to get pushed up to the side.
So let's start off here with the counter.
So for the counter, I'm going to set the position to fixed.
OK, so this is another way you can center things when you set this to fixed, which just sets it fixed
within the browser window and we can set the positioning to top.
I'm going to set it to 50 percent from the top and then let's say we want it to go 50 percent from the
left.
So this puts it in the middle.
However, when you do this, it puts the edge, the left edge in the top, in the middle.
So it starts here.
We want this entire thing to be shifted over and up into the you know, so the middle of this is in
the middle of the screen.
So to do that, we use transform and then we can use translate.
So translate without X or Y, we can we can do both X and Y values in here.
And for both of those, we want to do negative 50 percent.
And you'll see that once I save, it gets shifted up and over so that this is directly in the middle.
And I just want to also text a line to the center.
OK, so now we have that good, so the next thing we'll do is let's position this.
So this is the final class, so we'll go ahead and say final and let's do the same thing.
I'm actually going to copy.
Let's see.
Let's just copy all of this, OK?
That's going to basically position it in the same place as the counter.
Now, as I said, we only want to show one of these at a time.
So the way that this is going to work is the counter.
The div that has the class of counter will also at times have the class of hide for when we want to
hide it.
So let's go ahead and add the styling for the Hyde class and the way that I want this to to to basically
hide it is to scale it down to zero.
So and I'll actually show you.
So as soon as this count ends, watch what happens.
See how it kind of scales down and out and then this scales up, so it kind of comes from nowhere.
So that's what I want to do.
And the way I'm going to do it is on this side.
We're going to set transform and we want to just position it correctly again with translate and then
negative 50 percent on the X and Y.
But we also want to add a scale so we can use multiple transforms here.
So in addition to translate, we can use scale and we want to scale it down to zero to nothing and we
want it to have an animation.
So call this animation hide and we'll see point two seconds for the duration and then ease.
Let's to ease out.
For that and I get to put my semicolon here.
So now if I apply the Hyde class right here to the div with the class of counter, I can see that that
that one away.
Now for the animation, we're going to use a key frame, so it's a keyframes and we called it hyd,
call it whatever you want, just make sure it matches this and we're going to have something happen
at zero percent.
So basically, when it starts and then when it finishes at 100 percent, so at zero percent, we're
going to just grab this transform.
So that's the default state, right.
So scale zero and then I'm sorry, scale one is the default state and then we want it to hide.
So then we want to set it to scale zero.
So we're just giving it a smooth.
You can see right here how it just kind of fades and fades out but goes in now for this for this final.
It's going to work in the opposite way with counter.
It's going to show by default.
And then we can dynamically add this hyd class, which I'm going to remove right now with final.
We're going to actually have it not shown by default.
And then when we apply a class of show that we'll show it.
So I'm going to set the scale by default to zero, which will make it go away.
And then what we'll do is we'll have a final a show class on that same div.
And I'm just going to copy what I have here in the hide.
And instead of square starting off at scale zero, we want to want this to be scale one because we're
showing it.
All right.
We are going to call an animation here as well to show it because we want that same kind of effect,
that animated scale effect.
So let's create
keyframes show.
So I'm just going to actually copy these to zero percent and 100 percent, but we're also going to add
at 30 percent, I just want to scale it up a little bit so it'll have like that.
You know, it'll scale up just for a second and then scale back down.
So let's grab this.
So for zero percent, we want that to be zero, OK, because remember, we're showing it.
So we're starting with it hidden and then we're going to scale it up to one point four.
So a little more than, you know, the default one.
And then finally, we'll end up at one.
So let's save that now, if we apply the class of show here, you see how it came in when I when I keep
saving, you can see the effect, OK?
And if I add hyd here, you can see the effect.
All right.
But we'll be applying those with JavaScript.
So I'm going to get rid of both of those for now.
And we should only see the counter right now.
So in the next video, we're going to go ahead and finish up the styling for the numbers.
And then we have a couple other animations to do right now.
We took care of, you know, the the counter going out and the final coming in.
But we need to do this animation of the actual numbers coming in and out.
All right.
So we're going to get to that next.