OK, so now we want to start to work on the numbers and that animation, so first thing we're going
to do is style numbers.
So remember, we have the class of numbers and we're going to give the NUM the color of a hexadecimal
value of three four nine eight DB.
OK, so we'll give it that blue color and then we want to increase the font size a lot.
So let's do 50 pixels and we're going to position this relative because the span inside that that are
around each number, we want those to be positioned absolute.
So the container should be positioned relative.
And we're also going to set the overflow to hidden because we don't want anything to go out of the container
and we want to set a width and height on this.
So we're going to set the width to 250 pixels and we're going to set the height to the same as the font
size, which is 50 pixels.
All right.
Now, we only want actually, you know what?
Let's position the numbers first.
We want the number to show right in the middle here.
So what we'll do is take the spans that are in the nums and we want to position those to be absolute
within its container, within nums.
And then we also want to set the position to let's do from the top 50 percent and from the left, 50
percent.
OK, and then what we'll do is to fix that positioning.
We'll add a translate transform I'm sorry, those backwards transform translate and then negative 50
percent.
Negative 50 percent.
OK, and now you can see that it's right in the middle.
Now we want to start off with a little bit of a rotation, because you can see that the way these numbers
come in, they come like that and they they turn they rotate.
So we're we're going to start this off.
So they rotate and we're going to do one hundred and twenty degrees.
So it's going to start off like that.
Now we want to change what's called the transform origin.
We don't want when this starts off, we don't want it to start here.
We wanted to start here when it rotates up like this.
So let me just show you real quick
transform origin.
So right here you can see it set to center.
But what I'm going to do is set it to the bottom center.
So if I do that, you can see that it's positioned differently.
It's going to come from from here rather than smack dab in the middle like that.
All right.
So it's just going to move it.
Now, you could also do like top center.
It could come from that way.
So you can change, you know, how it rotates.
So I'm going to go ahead and set the transform origin and let's set it to bottom center.
And as soon as I save that, we're not going to see anything here.
Now, if this 120 degrees are set to zero, then we would be able to see it.
And what I'm going to do is take the class of N because remember, we have this class of end that starts
on the three and have that at zero degrees.
So that that that's in focus right here.
So let's say NUMS and we want to grab the band that has the class of it.
And then let's go ahead and take this line here and just change this to zero degrees.
And that way we can see whatever number has that class on it.
Now, we also want to add our animation to the in class and we're going to call this animation go in.
It will be a duration of zero point five seconds and it'll be for my colon here and then it'll be an
let's do he's in out effect, OK, because essentially what we want is it to come from here and go over
like that, like you can see here.
All right.
So each number that's coming in has that go in and then we'll have a go out to go this way and we're
going to use transform, rotate to be able to do that.
So we might as well create the out as well.
I'll just copy this so we'll have a class of out.
And this isn't going to have the starting point here.
So you get rid of that.
We're just going to call an animation called Go Out.
So let's create both of these animations, these keyframes, so say keyframes, and this will be the
go in animation.
Now we're going to have multiple states here, so let's do zero percent.
It's going to be our starting point.
Then we'll have a 30 percent and then a 60 percent and then a 100 percent, which is where it will end.
So we just want different levels of rotation in these different states.
So I'm going to copy this line here, the transform, translate and rotate and we're going to start
at 120.
And because we're going to be, you know, over here and then at 30 percent, I'm actually going to
go to negative 20 because I don't want to go right just from 120 to zero, because I want to have this
little bounce effect so you can see how it kind of goes forward.
And then back if you want, you can do just one twenty two and then put, you know, down here zero.
That's fine.
But if you want that bouncy effect, we're going to go negative 20 at 30 percent and then we're going
to go to ten degrees at 60 percent, which will give it that effect.
And you could see when I save it, you can see how it works.
If I take out this and do it, it just comes right in.
And it's slower because remember that no matter what, the duration is always going to be zero point
five seconds.
All right.
So that's go in.
Now we want to create our go out.
So I'm just going to copy this and let's change this to go out.
And we want to start at zero degrees now because remember, we're starting here and we're going out.
So start at zero degrees and then we don't need a 30 percent, but it's 60.
I want to go to 20 degrees.
And then at 100, I want to go to negative 120, which is obviously the opposite of 120.
So negative 120 will be over here.
All right, so that should do it, the last thing I want to do is just style.
This age for sprog should have done that earlier.
I'm going to put that up here somewhere.
Just say age four, and it's going to set the font size to 20 pixels and margin five pixels and let's
make it uppercase.
So text transform is going to be upper case.
There we go.
OK, so we have our success done.
Now we have to do a couple of things in the JavaScript we need to control when we want to show this
and when we want to show our final message.
We also need to basically loop through these spans here and add and remove the in and out class so that
we can have that animation happen continuously.
All right.
So we're going to do that in the next video.