OK, so now we want to make this thing dynamic and there's a few things we're going to do in our JavaScript
file, we want to run our animation.
We also want to control when the counter shows and when the final message shows, the first thing we'll
do is bring in excuse me, bring in the stuff that we need from the DOM.
So we need the numbers.
So we're going to use document dot.
And then since there's multiple spans that we need to bring in, we're going to actually use query selector
all.
And we want to bring in the class, we'll say nums and then the spans within nums.
All right.
Now, query selector, all is used if there's multiple elements that you're selecting and what it does
is it puts it into what's called the node list, which is kind of like an array you can use for each
on it.
You can use, you know, array methods and stuff like that.
So next thing I want is the counter itself.
So it's a counter and document dot and it's just a single element.
So we can just use query selector and we want the class of counter.
Copy that down.
We also want the final message.
So that has a class of final and we'll call this final message and then we want the replay as well.
So it's a replay and that I believe is an I.D. So we want to change this to a no sign and then replay
or you can use to get element by bidi.
So we want to call a function here when this starts called run animation, because we wanted to run
right when it starts.
So let's call that and then let's create that function.
All right, now we want to deal with these numbers here that we're bringing in, you know, the three
to three through zero.
So I want to loop through those so I can take numbers, which is a node list, because we use query
selector all.
And like I said, I no, this is similar to an array and we can actually use the for each method to
loop through.
So for each will take in a function you can put in function like that, or you can use an arrow function
which is a bit cleaner.
And what this takes, what this, this callback that we put into for each takes is whatever we want
to call this num item, whatever you want to call it, it just represents each individual item in the
node list or in the array.
And then you can pass in a second parameter of index, which will just be, you know, to start at zero.
And then when it goes through the next iteration, it'll be one and then two and so on because we're
going to need the index.
So within this loop, let's go ahead and actually let's let's consider log just so I can show you.
If we can also log NUM and index and we go ahead and open up our dev tools here.
You can actually see we put the put this down here.
You can see each span.
So the span is what we're getting right here.
NUM it's not just the NUM, it's this is an element that we brought in the span.
So it's going to show the entire element and then this the zero, this is the index.
So it starts at zero sort of zero one, two, three.
So we have access to those within this loop.
Now I'm going to create a variable here to get the next to last value because we're going to need that
in order to to do what we need to do.
So I'm going to get the total length of nums using the length property and just minus one from that.
OK, next thing we want to do is create an event listener because we want to know when the animation
ends.
And there's actually let's close this.
There's actually an event listener called animation.
And so I'm going to take NUM.
So basically whatever iteration we're on, whatever item or whatever number.
And let's add an event listener to that.
And when we get an animation end event.
OK, so just animation and we're going to fire off a function with an event parameter here and we want
to first check to see if the animation that's ending, if the name is go in and we can do that using
that event parameter.
So this E here actually we can say animation name that'll give us whatever the animation name is and
we want to see if it's equal to go in.
OK, we also want to see if the index is is not the last.
So let's do a double ampersand and then we want to take the test, the index and see if that's not equal
to.
And what I'm going to do here is just actually I will just add next to the next to last here.
So if that's true, then we want to take the current number and we want to remove the in class and then
add the outclass.
And that's what's going to give it that, you know, in and out effects.
So let's take NUM in use class list and then we can use the add method to add a class and I'm sorry,
one to remove in first.
So we're going to remove in and then we're going to add out, OK, and all that's doing is taking in
off of the current number and adding Oh.
Which in turn is going to call this which will then rotate it down that way.
OK, so the second condition here that I want to check for, let's say elusive and right here where
removing if it's go in, then we're removing the in class, adding the out.
Now we want to check to see if it's go out.
So let's say if e dot information name is equal to go out.
And we also want to see if there's a number after it because we don't want to add in in class if there's
no next element.
And we can do that by checking let's say, and num dot.
And then there's a method called Next Element Sibling, which we'll see if there's a next sibling.
So these spans are all in the same level.
So they're siblings.
So if we're here, it's going to check to see if if this exists.
If it does, it's going to add the class of N.
If not, then it's not because there's there's no more span's.
All right, so we'll say no dots, next element sibling, and then in here we want to take num dot,
next element sibling and we want to add the class of N OK, so class list add because we want to add
it to the next one.
Right.
Not to the current numbers.
So that's why we're using next element sibling here and then we're adding the in class.
OK, and then else that means that we're done.
So we want to show the final message inside the counter.
So let's say counter dot class list and we want to add onto that.
Remember, we have that hyd class.
OK, and then we're going to take the final message
and we want to add the show class.
OK, so when it's done with, it's just going to show that final message.
So I'm going to save that and I can see where we go.
So the last thing we need to do in our JavaScript is call this this replay here, we want to be able
to click this and have it happen again.
So let's create a function up here.
And we're just going to call this a reset, Dom, because we're basically just resetting it to its start
starting state.
So we'll take counter and class list, dot remove and we want to remove the high class.
And then on the on the final message, we want to then remove the show class.
OK, and then we want to loop through the numbers again.
So nums dot for each and's takes in a function.
So we'll say no.
So for each number I just want to clear the value.
So do num dot class list dot value and set it to just an empty string.
All right.
And then here we want to add the class of in to the first span.
So NUMS is a node list which is similar to an array so we can access specific elements.
So zero is actually going to give me the first one here and we want to add this class of into it.
Right.
So let's say nums zero class list dot add and we want to add in.
All right.
So that will kind of just reset everything to this initial state here.
Now we want this to happen when we click this button.
So let's take the replay and let's add an event listener and we want to listen for a click event.
And when that happens, we're going to call a function and we want to reset Dom.
And we also want to run animation.
All right.
So save that.
So as soon as this ends, you can see that we get this go.
Let's actually center that.
I don't know why we didn't center that.
So let's see, final message or final and let's say text str text align center.
There we go.
OK, so if I click replay.
It happens again.
OK, so that should do it.
So we have this cool little animation and you could implement this into some kind of website or app
so that you show your, you know, you show your screen once it loads, you could do a bunch of things
with it, but that's it for this project.
And let's jump into the next one.