All right, so we're going to get started on our image carousel, so I have my project starter open
and let's head to the title here and say Image Carousel.
And down here, we're going to have a div with a class of carousel that wraps around everything and
then side here will have our image container.
And I'm also going to give us an idea of IMG s four images and then you can just put image tags in here.
It can be as many images as you want.
I'm going to use for images from unselfconsciously.
These are just links to, you know, stock images.
And then I just have first image, second, third and fourth.
All of these should probably be consistent.
And then if I save that, you'll see we just have these large images now.
We do want previous and next buttons.
So outside of the image container, which ends at this div, we still want to be within the carousel.
Let's create a div with the class of buttons dash container and we'll have a button with an idea of
left and we'll see preview for the text so previous.
And then this one will be the next button and we'll call this one.
Right.
So that should be it for the HTML.
Pretty simple.
Let's jump into our stylesheet and in the body here we can keep most of the stuff.
We don't need to display Fluck column or flex direction column.
We don't need overflow hidden.
We'll get rid of that.
Let's see what else we want to do here.
That's pretty much it as far as the body goes.
So let's go down and let's do the class of carousel.
So this wraps around all the images.
I'm also going to just take the images themselves and I want to, first of all, set the width and the
height to 500 pixels.
So let's change this to height.
And then I just want to make sure that if it looks right, so we're going to set object fit to cover.
There we go.
Now we have our images.
We have our buttons down at the bottom.
So for the carousel, which wraps around everything, I'm going to add a box shadow here.
So box shadow takes in horizontal and vertical offset.
I'm going to do two pixels for both and then we'll do a five pixel blur and our for the color which
will be black.
So zero for red, green and blue.
And then the alpha value, which is that the level of transparency will be zero point three.
And then let's set the set.
The height here to five will do five hundred and thirty pixels because it has to account for the buttons
as well as the image, and then the width will be the width of the image which is five hundred pixels,
OK, and then I'm going to set overflow hidden so that nothing breaks out of the container.
Now we can still see part of the second image here.
So what we can do is take the image Dasch container.
OK, so image container.
Remember, that wraps around all the images.
I'm going to display that as a flex box.
So what that did is it put these into a flex row, which is horizontal.
Now we can only see one image because the image is 500 pixels wide and so is the container.
Now, the way that this is going to work in terms of the carousel, the slider is we're going to move
the image along the x axis using transform, translate X..
So what I'll do is set initially with set transform and then translate X, which basically means translating
it, moving it along the the X axis, which is vertical.
And we want to set that to an initial value of zero, which isn't going to change anything.
But we want to set that initially and then in the JavaScript will change this so that, you know, it
can move the images over.
So we'll we'll move it over 500 pixels and get the next image in.
That makes sense.
Now, we don't want to just flick flick right in.
We want it to have a transition.
So we want to make sure we add a transition property here.
And I'm going to set a transition on the transform property that I just created.
And then we'll do zero point five seconds for the duration and we'll do an ease in effect.
OK, so that should be it for the image container.
Now the buttons don't look too good.
So let's go ahead and I'm going to move this.
Let's move that up at the top.
Here we'll go, Underbody.
All right, and then for the button container, save button dash container and all I'm going to do is
display flex so each fluck, each button will be a flex item.
And then I'm going to justify content, which aligns them on the main access, which since it's erro,
it's going to be on the horizontal axis.
I want to do space between because I want to take the space that is remaining here next to the flex
items and put them put it in between the buttons.
So if I save that now, it's going to put each button on each side, which is what I want.
So now let's dial the buttons themselves.
So you know what?
Let's you can just grab it by button if you want, but I'm not actually going to give these a class
of B10 just preference so that to be ten.
All right.
And then we'll style dot btn and let's go ahead and set the background color and I'm going to use Rebecca
Purple for the background color and then set the color to white and let's get rid of the border.
So border none.
OK, and then let's add some padding.
When you do zero point five REM units, arem unit is just a multiplier of the root HTML element, which
by default is 16 pixels.
So point five, sixteen point five would be eight pixels.
And you can use pixels if you want.
Just just switching it up a little bit.
So cursor pointer and let's set the width to be almost houts do forty nine point five percent.
OK, so they take up almost half each.
And then I just want to add to the cover.
So b10 Colen Hover, we'll just set opacity to zero point nine.
So we have a slight fade out effect when we hover over and then let's get rid of any outline on the
focus state.
So button focus, we're going to set a line to none.
OK, so that's it for the CSFs.
Now obviously we want this to function.
We want to be able to click next and preview.
We also want it to to go automatically, to slide automatically.
So in the next video, we'll get into the JavaScript to add that functionality.