OK, so now we're going to start on the functionality for this now, if you have a decent experience
with JavaScript and working with the DOM and all that, you can attempt to try this on your own.
And in fact, I would encourage that for a lot of these projects.
And if it doesn't match up to exactly what I have, that's absolutely fine, because there's so many
different ways to do stuff like this.
We're not working with a framework or something like that.
I mean, when it comes to vanilla JavaScript, there's so many different ways to do the same thing.
So let's start off by bringing in what we need.
We have our images container.
So I'm going to call us IMGs.
We'll get it by I.D. So get Element Bidi.
And if you remember, the image container also has an idea of images.
So that's the same element right here.
ID images is our image container that wraps around all of these images.
So we also want to bring in our buttons.
Let's do left BTN and set that document dot get element by D and that has an idea of left and then we'll
also get a right button and we'll call this right button and then we want to get each individual image
as well.
So let's say Consed and we'll call this.
I already have images, we'll just call this IMG and it's going to be a node list so we'll be able to
do like IMG zero, IMG one and that'll get that specific index just like an array.
So we do that by fetching it with document dot query selector, all because there's more than one.
We want to get inside the images container, each image.
All right.
Next thing I'm going to do is set an index.
So the index is going to be, you know, where we're at.
The first one will be whatever, zero, one, two, three and so on.
It doesn't matter.
You can put more images or less.
Doesn't matter.
We're going to start it at zero and make sure you let because we're going to reassign it.
And then let's also create an interval because we're going to want this to keep running.
So let's say set interval and this takes in a function which I'm going to call run.
And how often do we want to run it?
I'm going to do two thousand milliseconds, which means two seconds.
So every two seconds this function called run is going to run.
And all this is going to do is increase the index or increment the index by one.
So IDEX plus plus and then we'll have a separate function to actually do the change image and we'll
call that change image, OK, which will go ahead and create a function change image.
And really all this has to do is change the translate value on the image container right here.
You can see we have transform and then translate X, which is, you know, where it is on the x axis
set to zero, which is going to by default, put it in the first image.
What we're going to want to do is slide it 500 pixels over to the next image and then 500 pixels to
the next image.
And we want to use a negative value because we want this to go this way.
If we do, positive value will go this way.
And I can just show you right here, if I set this to negative 500, I probably should showed you this
earlier.
That's automatically going to bring me to the next image if we do negative 1000 next image, OK, if
we do, you know, positive 500, it's going to go the other way, which we, of course, we don't want.
So we want this to be at Loop's.
We want this to be at zero for now.
And before we even do the transform, though, let's let's check to see if we're at the beginning or
if we're at the end, because then we'll have to reset the index to either zero or the last image.
So we can do that by setting an if statement here.
And we'll say if the index is greater than the image length.
Remember, image is a no list of all the images.
So the length will give us exactly how many images there are now.
The thing with this is actually I'm just going to console log real quick image
and let's go to our console here so you can see it's a no list of four images, but the index is at
zero, right?
So zero one, two, three.
So I want to see basically if we're at the end of the node list now, image dot length is going to give
us four because this four total, that's the length.
But I want to see if the index is at three because remember, the index starts at zero.
It's going to go zero one to three.
So we don't want to check to see if it's greater than the length because that's four.
We want to see if it's greater than the length minus one.
OK, which will be in our case three.
And if that's the case, then we just want to go back to the beginning.
So we'll set index to zero.
OK, and then else or else if we want to check to see if we're at the beginning.
So we can easily do that by saying if the index is going to be less than zero, then let's set the index
to the end.
And we can do that by setting it to the image length.
Except remember, the image length is for the last index is three.
So we just want to again, minus one from that, OK, once we figure out if it's at the beginning of
the end, we can take the image container, which is images, and set the style dot transform and we
want to set that to some back ticks and then translate X.
And in here, let's open up our expression syntax and remember, we want to go negative whatever.
The current index is multiplied by 500 because that's it's 500 pixels.
And make sure you put pixels outside of this right here.
And it's just going to do what I just showed you when I put, you know, negative 500 pixels in here,
negative 1000.
It's just going to move the image and it does it smoothly because of this transition.
Without the transition, it would just flick to the next one.
So let's just try that will save that.
And now you'll see after two seconds, the image changes on its own and it goes back to the beginning
when it hits the end.
Now, if we don't have a CSFs transition here, if I comment that out, it'll still work.
But it just like, you know, flick's to the next image.
So you want to have a transition.
So it's nice and it's nice and smooth.
And of course, you could change the duration if you want here for the transition.
But yeah, I think that's good.
So that handles, you know, the the automatic carousel.
We also want these buttons to function.
Right.
So let's go ahead and create some event listeners down here.
Let's do the left button, OK?
Sure.
We'll do the right button first.
So right button.
We want to add an event listener.
We're going to listen for a click and on that click will run function.
I'm going to use an arrow function.
And since we're going right, we're going to want to decrement the index.
So index minus minus and then we can just call change image.
All right.
Now, I'm going to save this and click next.
Now you see how we're having a little issue here because the interval is not resetting.
It's still has that same two second interval.
And when I click next, it's not like it's not resetting.
It's not disturbing it so it does some weird stuff.
So what we can do is create a function right here and we'll say reset interval.
And there's a JavaScript function called clear interval, which will do just that.
And we want to clear the current interval, which we, you know, described above, and then just reset
it.
So we'll reset interval to set interval and set set it to run the run function into two seconds or twelve
milliseconds.
And then down here, right after we change the image, we'll call reset interval.
We should ask you, you don't need this right here.
All right.
So now if I click next.
Actually, wait a minute, this is going the wrong way, this should be a plus plus.
All right.
Sorry about that, but you'll see, even if I if I get rid of the reset interval, it's still you know,
it still messes up because it's not resetting when I click on the the button and switch the image.
So you want to make sure that you reset that in order for this to work.
All right, good.
Now we want to do the same thing with the left button, which is going to be very similar.
So I'll just copy that and we'll set this to the left button click and all we need to do is minus minus.
And now if I click preview for at the beginning, it's going to take us to the end.
So it's going to go back and forth to the end.
But if I keep clicking previous, you know, I can go next previous, next, next previous.
And you can add as many images as you want in the HTML.
It doesn't matter if you have, you know, two images or you have, you know, 20 images, it doesn't
matter.
So I think that's pretty much it.
Let's get rid of this console log here.
And if you did try to do this on your own, if it doesn't look like this, that's fine.
It might even be better than this.
We're just trying to kind of simplify things for people that are fairly new to JavaScript.
So that's it for this project.
Guys, hopefully you enjoyed it.
Let's move on to the next one.