All right, guys, in this project, we're going to create a hoverboard, so it's just kind of a cool
little effect.
We're going to paint these boxes onto the screen.
We're going to style them with success, and we're going to basically set a certain number.
So right now, it's set to 500 in the JavaScript and it's going to paint that number of boxes.
And then we're going to have event listeners for most over and most out so that when we hover over,
it's going to give us a random color.
OK, so you can see if I hover over that, it's blue, then it's purple.
So we'll have an array of colors that will basically have to choose from for each box when we hover
over it.
So it gives us this cool effect.
And this could be used for some kind of drawing application or something like that will be using CSFs
transition.
So we have that cool fadeout effect as well.
All right.
So let's go ahead and get started.