OK, let's go ahead and start on this hoverboard project.
So in the HTML here, let's change the title up to hoverboard and all we're going to have in this HTML
is a class of container, because in this container we're going to have a bunch of divs with the class
of square like this.
In fact, what I'll do is just I'll put some in here now, but later on we're going to get rid of these
because they're going to get inserted via JavaScript and we're going to set a certain amount of squares
to be painted on to the screen.
So for now, we'll just throw these in and let's jump into our stylesheet and let's see for the body
here.
Let's set a background and I'm going to set that to one.
One, one.
So, I mean, it doesn't really matter, but we're not having any fights here, if you want to add some
text or something, you can, but I'm just going to get rid of all that.
We don't need it, OK?
And then let's do display flex.
And we don't need Collum just to put everything in the middle.
We're going to keep this.
And then we have the container, which actually gave it a class.
Let's.
Let's give it an I.D. as well, so I.D. container, because I'm going to use that for the JavaScript
and then here, let's say class container and we want to display flex actually before we do the container.
Let's do the squares.
So I'm just going to comment that out for a second and then let's add our square class and set a background
color and background color.
I'm going to set this to hexadecimal one D three times.
So let's see.
We can't see anything just yet.
Let's add a box shadow of zero zero for the offsets to pixel blur and black.
OK, and then for us to be able to see the squares, we have to add height and the width.
So let's give these a height and the width of 16 pixels.
So we'll do height, width of 16.
Good.
So now we can at least see the squares.
I'm going to just add a margin of two pixels as well.
Just pull them apart a little bit and we're going to want to transition.
So ultimately we're going to paint these on the screen and then we're going to make it so that when
we enter it turns a certain color, a random color, and when we leave it, it gets rid of that color.
And we want that to happen at kind of with a little fade effect.
So I'm going to add a transition here for, let's say, two seconds ease and let's also set for the
square cover.
So when we hover over it, I'm going to set the transition duration to zero seconds so that we have
an effect where when we hover over it, it immediately lights up.
And then when we come off of it, it will basically take two seconds for the color to disappear.
So it'll have that fade effect.
OK, we're not going to see that just yet, but we'll we'll get to that.
So the container see, we want to display Flex.
As soon as I do that, it's going to display in a row.
And I just want to set a line items to center and justify content to center.
And I want these to wrap.
So we'll set flex wrap to wrap.
We're not going to see a difference now because we don't have that many boxes, but we want to give
this a max width of 400 pixels.
OK, so if it goes beyond that, then it should wrap onto the next line.
So just to test that out, let's take these and let's create a bunch of them and save.
And now you can see when it gets past that 400 pixels or whatever, it will wrap onto the next line.
OK, so that looks good.
I think that's all we need to do for the season.
So let's clear out all of these squares, because like I said, we're going to paint them with the JavaScript
depending on, you know, what we set for the amount of squares.
And that's all we need is just this one container.
So in the next video, we'll jump into our JavaScript and we'll get started on that.