All right, so now we have the fun part, which is the JavaScript.
So let's jump in to skip James.
And first thing we want to do is grab the container, which is the only element that we have in the
in the body.
So let's say document dot, get element bidi in that has an I.D. of container.
Now we want to create an array of colors here because we want to we want these to be random colors when
we follow along the squares.
So I'm going to just paste in some hexadecimal values.
You can use absolutely any colors you want.
They can be hexadecimal, they can be RGB, they can be color names, whatever you want.
And then we want a variable here.
I'm going to give this just all caps here.
Call the squares and then the amount of squares that we want to put on the screen, which is going to
be 500 in this case.
I don't know why I put a semicolon.
I don't use semicolons.
So those are the variables we need.
And then the way we're going to do this is create a for loop.
OK, so we want to say for and let's let AI equals zero.
So it's going to start at zero.
And then as long as I is less than whatever we have in squares and then we want to increment I by one.
So in here we're going to create an element.
So let's say conse square and on the document object there's a method called Spell This Right document.
There's a method called create element and we can create any type of the DOM element that we want.
I'm going to create a div and then I want to add the class of square.
So I'm going to take the square element and I'm going to say class list dot add and I want to add the
class of square because that's, you know, the square we restyled this, this square class and that's
what we want to show.
Now this isn't going to do anything just yet.
We want to take the container that we brought in and we want to append child because we want to insert
this into the container and we'll pass in here square like that.
OK, now, if we save this, you can see that 500 squares have now been painted.
If I change this to two hundred and I save now, we have two hundred.
So you can change this to whatever you want, but we're going to go ahead and paint 500 squares.
And then what we want to happen is when we hover over these, we want to basically have them light up
with a random color.
So inside this for loop, let's take the square and I want to add an event listener.
So I'm going to say add event listener and pass in the event in this case is going to be mouseover.
So when we just hover over a square, this is going to fire off.
And I want this to call a function that we're going to create that says that's called set color and
we want to pass in that particular square.
All right.
We want to do the same thing when we leave.
So we'll have an event listener on mouse out.
So when we leave a square and then we'll call remove color, OK?
And then let's go down here and let's create function sets, color and say element.
And just for now, let's console log here element.
So if I save that and I open up my console to remove color is not defined.
So I just need to define remove color elements.
All right.
So now if I hover over a square, you can see it's just going to or I shouldn't say hover, but if I
mouse over, it's going to call that.
All right.
If I come out of it, it's going to call remove color.
So that's why I just do like console log one, two, three.
And we go over here, you'll see that each time I get out of a of a square, it's going to fire this
off.
All right.
So let's get rid of that and let's do the set color first.
So we need to have a specific color.
I'm going to have a function called Get Random Color, because we don't want it to always be the same
one.
So down here, let's say function, get random color and we want to return.
And remember, we have that colors array and we can access like the zero index is going to give us this
one then one, two, three, four.
So I want to get a random index.
So inside here, instead of hard coding a number, I'm going to say math dot floor because I want to
round down and then math dot random.
So math random gives me a random decimal I.
We want to multiply that by the length of the array, so colors, length, that way it's going to be
somewhere in between zero and what, four?
So zero.
One, two, three, four.
OK.
In fact, I can go ahead and console log here the color.
And if I go over and hover, you'll see that it's going to be one of those colors.
Good.
So now we just need to set it to the actual square.
In this case, the element because the square is getting passed in is the element.
So we can set the style, let's set the style dot background and we're going to set that equal to whatever
the color is.
And then also the box Shadowlord set element, perhaps element, dot style, dot box, shadow.
You want to use Camil case for this and we're going to set that to show you some back ticks here.
And it's going to be zero zero two pixels and then whatever the color is.
So in here we'll pass and the color and then another shadow so comma zero zero 10 pixels and then whatever
the color is.
All right.
So I save that.
Let's close the console up and go over here.
And you can see wherever I go, it's going to give me a random color.
So you could you could create like a drawing app with this.
You can make them smaller and you could add some other functionality to it.
I just want I just want them to disappear once we come off it, because right now we can fill the whole
thing.
I mean, if that's what you want to do, that's fine.
But I want to remove the color.
So what we'll do is one that remove is called we'll take the element and set the style dot background.
And we want to set it back to the original the original color of the box, which is this right here.
OK, so we're going to set that equal to that color on remove and then set the box shadow.
So element dot style, dot box shadow.
We're going to set that to the original box shadow, which is this right here.
So pass that in here.
All right.
So let's save that.
And now you can see I can go over and get a random color, but it disappears and it fades out like that.
It takes two seconds to fade out because of this transition right here.
OK, so if I if I take this transition off, then it's just going to do this.
And that is kind of stupid.
So we want to leave that trail by doing that, adding that transition.
And just like with any other project in this course, I encourage you to add to it, maybe have some
select a select box where you can choose different color schemes or something like that.
I'm sure that you can think of something.
This is just a good template to create some kind of drawing application or something like that.
All right.
So that's it.
Let's move on to the next project.