All right, so we're going to get started, I have my project starter open here, and I'm just going
to change the title here to pokey decks and we're going to have an H1 with pokey decks.
And I think that we're going to have a container that wraps around everything, which will have a class
of pokey dash container.
I'm also going to give you an idea of pokey container and inside here will be basically each card is
going to have a class of Pokémon and these are going to be there's going to be a bunch of these and
it's going to ultimately come from the JavaScript.
We're going to construct this div in the JavaScript, fetch the data and put the data inside here and
then put it in the dorm.
But right now I'm just going to hard code the HTML just so we can see it and we can at least style the
card.
So they're going to have an inline background.
So let's say style here and set the background color because each type is going to have a specific background
color.
OK, so apparently Pokémon, they have different types.
I honestly have never even looked at Pokémon, so I have no clue about it.
All I know is the data that we're fetching.
So if you're a big Pokemon fan and I make a mistake, please don't, you know, get pissed off at me.
So let's set the background.
I'm sorry, did that set the background color to be so red, green, blue.
Two, two, two, two, five, three and two to four.
OK, and then inside here, we want to have an image container div.
So let's say image container and then an image.
And I'm just going to grab the link here.
So this is a link to the Bulbasaur Pokémon.
So it's looks like this and it's going to be really big to begin with.
But when we get to the success, we'll fix that up.
So under the image container here, we're going have a class of info which will have some info on this
particular Pokémon.
So spane, let's give this a class of no and just hardcoded in here, zero zero one.
Ultimately, like I said, this stuff is going to come from, you know, the API.
So H3 with a class of name and we'll say it's Balbus or Balbus or like that, I believe.
And then small tag here with a class of type.
And let's just put a label of type and then another spane.
And inside here is going to be the type name which in this case is grass.
OK, so that should do it.
I'm also going to put a link to the design that this was inspired by from Dribble.
So I'm just going to pass that in down here just to give them credit.
All right.
Actually, one more thing I want to do is just create a couple of these cards.
So this divide the class of Pokémon, let's just copy that down twice so that there's three of these.
OK, so we have three of these cards.
And ultimately, again, this will be coming from the JavaScript, so we won't have this HTML in this
file, but we just want it.
There's a style.
So we're going to use the little fonts I'm going to grab from here to here and let's say questionmark
family set that to lieto.
So let's go.
And then Colen 300 and 400.
And then let's add that font family here.
So change that and then the background, so for the background, we're going to use a linear gradient,
but for any browser that doesn't support that, we're going to put a solid color first.
So EAFE, FBB will be the solid background.
And I know we can't really see it because of the cards here, but we'll fix that in a minute.
And then let's also set another set, another background here as a linear gradient direction will be
to the right.
First color is going to be D four D, three D D and then comma and then the next color will be EFP FPP.
OK, so that'll be the background which we can't currently see, and then all the Fleck's stuff can
stay, the alignment will get rid of the height 100 viewport, we'll get rid of the overflow hidden
because we do want scroll bars.
And now you can see the background gradient here.
So for the H1, I just want to separate out the letters.
A little soul set the letter spacing to three pixels.
And let's do the container, so the pokey dash container that wraps around everything on want to display
that as flax.
So if we look at our e-mail poky container wraps, all of these Pokémon, so basically all the cards.
So we want to use flex box to turn those into flex items into a row.
So display flex, it's going to put them side by side.
And I know the image is giant right now, but we'll fix that in a few minutes.
We want to display flaks.
We want it to WRAP'S If it goes out of its container, it'll wrap onto the onto the next line.
OK, and you can see now that it dropped down to the next line.
As far as the remaining space, we want to align items to space between.
And then let's justify content to the center and we want it to be in the middle, let's say margin zero,
top and bottom, auto left and right, and then offset a max width of twelve hundred pixels and we will
make this responsive.
OK, so now we have the class of Pokémon which wraps around all of you know, each one has a class of
Pokémon on each card.
And for this let's set a back an initial background color of Tripoli.
But these are going to be called background colors are going to be dynamic depending on whatever the
type is.
OK, but we'll set it to that initially.
Let's set the border radius to 10 pixels.
Actually, you know what?
We can't even see any of this.
So let's do the image.
Let's just take care of that image.
So the Pokémon image, Dasch container, let's do that first.
And for the container, we're going to set a background color of our GBA white.
So two five, five, four, Rajeeb.
And then for the alpha value will do zero point six for that.
Right.
And then we want these to be rounded images, but we're going to put the border radius on the image
container.
So that's going to be 50 percent.
And I want to have a with and height of 120 pixels.
Okay, so right now, the images is you can see these are lined up and you can see the image container,
but the images are busting out of the container.
So before we actually add anything on to that, I just want to do text line center.
But then for the images, let's grab this and say for each image, I want to set a max width on that
image to be 90 percent of its container.
So that will put it inside its container, which is that, you know, this right here.
And let's just also add a margin to a margin, top of 20 pixels.
All right, so now that we've done that, let's go back to to this class right here, the Pokémon class,
and I want to box shadow on these cards.
So let's set the box shadow here.
Will do zero four vertical I'm sorry, horizontal three pixels for the V offset and then 15 pixels for
the blur and then for the color.
It'll be Vuh.
Let's do 100 for each of those and then zero point five for the transparency.
So you can see now we have that box shadow for spacing.
Let's add the margin to ten pixels that will bring them apart.
We need some spacing inside the card.
So let's do twenty pixels inside and you can see it.
This gets knocked on to the next line because we have flex wrap.
If we didn't have this flex wrap right here, then it's not going to do that.
But this will help us make it responsive, and then finally, I just want to text a line to the center
right now for the bottom part here, the info.
Let's do that.
So it's a Pokémon dot info.
All I want on this particular class is a margin, top of 20 pixels.
So it's going to push everything down a little bit.
And then I want to style the number.
So it's a Pokémon info.
No, so I'm going to add a background color here and I'm going to use RGB because I want it to be like
a transparent looking background.
So let's do black and then zero point one.
OK, so you can see it gives it that transparent background.
Look, we're going to have a little bit of padding to it.
Let's do five pixels, top and bottom, 10 pixels left and right and set the border radius and we'll
do 10 pixels on that.
And let's make it a little smaller.
We'll do font size and we'll set it to zero point zero point eight AM units.
So that's going to just be whatever the the wrapper is, the container font size, it's going to multiply
it by zero point eight, which is going to make it a little smaller.
OK, so last thing is the name.
So it's a Pokémon info name at the margin to let's do 15 07 and then let's just do the letter spacing
to one pixel.
All right, so it looks pretty good and you see, if I extend it, it'll go they'll all be on the same
line.
So that's a success.
In the next video, we want to actually fetch this data because right now it's just we just put it in
the HTML.
We want to go ahead and fetch it from the API and inserted into the DOM.