All right, so in this video, we're going to fetch our data from the API and then in the next video
will take that data and create these cards.
Now, the API that we're using is from this poky API diko.
And there's a bunch of different endpoints we can hit.
We can get the Pokémon by name, I guess.
So Pokemon Ditto will give you all the info you can get by I.D. Pokémon, Pokemon's one.
You can get by type abilities and then you can get a bunch.
If you see Pokémon you can also set a limit and this will give you a results array.
But if we look at each object, it just includes the name and a Eurail to that particular Pokemon with
the I.D..
Now what we want to do is show different cards on the same screen with with the name, the type, the
ID, the image.
So we're going to have to make separate requests for each card, which, you know, if you were getting
thousands of items you probably wouldn't want to do for performance issues.
But for this, it should be fine.
We're just going to get 150 different cards.
So we want to make requests to the I.D..
Right.
If we look at some of the data here, we have the name, which is Bulbasaur, which is the same one
we used.
We get the ID, which is one.
We get the type.
Now, the types is going to be tricky because it's an array of objects that also has a type.
So it has a type object with a name.
So we need to kind of we're going to have to use the map are high order array method to get that and
basically get an array of types.
But we'll talk about that when we get to it.
So first thing I want to do is just kind of bring in what we need.
So let's say pokey container and we want to get that from the DOM.
So let's use document get element by D and I have an idea of pokie Dasch container because that's where
we're going to want to fill fill it with all these cards.
Right.
Which is this right here.
Ultimately all this stuff in here is going to come from the JavaScript.
So I'm also going to set a variable for the number of account that we want.
So let's say Pokémon underscore count and I'm going to set that to one fifty and we're going to have
an object called colors that will be key value pairs of the type.
So, for instance, the type of fire is going to have a color of F.D. FTF.
And for the rest of this, I'm just going to copy and paste them in sort of the type them out.
And then what we'll do is create a function when you use an arrow function called fetch Pokemon's.
You don't have to use an arrow function, but I'm going to.
And this is going to be a for loop because we basically want to loop through this amount of times.
And each each number, each iteration is going to be used as an ID for the Pokémon that we're getting.
So let's start off here with one.
So let I equals one, because that's the first ID we want to get.
And then as long as I is less than or equal to the Pokémon count and then we want to just increment
by one, we'll have a function called Get Pokémon and pass passing AI is the ID.
Now this is going to return a promise.
So we need to await and appear.
We want to call a sync.
OK, now for that function, let's create that, get Pokémon also use arrow function.
That's going to take in an IED and we're going to use Fach here.
So let's use a sink away.
So this is a synchronous and then I'm going to put the Eurail into a variable here.
So tactics and the API you URL is going to be coqui api dot seo slash API slash version two slash Pokémon
and then the OK and the IDs being passed and then we want to fetch.
So let's say the response is going to be equal to await the fetch promise that pass that pass in the
URL.
We want Jason data so we want to await resident Jason OK, and then we'll go ahead and console log data
so you can see what we get.
And if I open up my console, we have to call this.
So we want to call the fetch.
So fetch Pokemon's.
And you can see down here, we get these objects with all of the each Pokemon's data up to 150, and
of course, you can change this number here if you want.
So we're able to fetch the data now.
We need to insert it into the dorm.
So in the next video, we're going to create a function called Create Pokémon Card, where for each
one that we fetch, it creates a card and inserts it into the DOM.