OK, so now we're able to fetch the data or just console logging it, though, we want to insert it
into the dorm.
So let's replace this console log here with a function and we'll call that create Pokémon card.
And it's going to take in the Pokémon data.
So here will say CONSED create Pokemon card and that's going to take in data.
We'll call Pokémon.
OK, so for each, for each one that we fetch, it's going to create a card.
Now obviously if we had like thousands of results, this wouldn't be very efficient because we're making
all of these separate requests.
But I mean, this isn't a production app or anything.
It's basically just, you know, for learning purposes and for fun.
So and there's only one fifty.
It's not you know, it fetches it pretty quickly.
So we're fine now.
And here we want to, first of all, create a div.
So I'm going to call this pokey, call us Pokémon L for Element and say document dot creates elements
and we want to create a div.
So basically what we're doing here is constructing these divs, these Pokémon devs, and they have a
class of Pokémon.
So we want to add that by saying pokie or Pokemon elements, class list dot add class of Pokémon.
Now we're going to create basically a template here for our HTML, so let's call this Pokémon in our
HTML and we'll set this to some back ticks.
And what I'm going to do for now is just grab everything that's in one of these Pokémon divs, which
is just the image container and the info.
I'm going to copy that and then I'm going to get rid of everything that's in the initial pokey container.
So all of those devs, all you should be left with in the HTML is just this.
OK, so in our script here, we just going to paste that in and we'll just kind of fix this up a little
bit.
OK, and then we want to insert this into our HTML.
So let's say our pokey, we want our elements of Pokémon element.
We want to set the entire HTML to Pokémon in our HTML and then to put it into the DOM.
We want to take the container so poky underscore container and we want to call append dot the pen child
and we're going to put in the Pokémon elements or Hokey Pokey Marnel.
So now if I say if we get all these cards now, these are just as hard coded data, we need to make
this dynamic right.
So the image is really easy because it's just this Eurail and then the I.D. and we have the ID on this
object.
It's just dot I.D. So let's replace this one here with money saying Curly Braces Pokémon dot d.
And now you can see we have all the different images.
The next thing would be the name.
So the name is right here.
Now, I could we could do Pokémon name, and that's fine.
But you'll see it's lowercase.
I actually want to uppercase the first one.
So I'm going to create a variable up here called name and take the Pokémon dog name.
And if we say Daudt to uppercase, so if we add that and then we put down here just name, you'll see
that it's all uppercase because that's what this method does.
I want just the first letter uppercase.
Now with a string you can grab, you can use an index just like an array.
So if I want just the first letter, I can take just zero.
All right.
So I'm going to set this name variable to just the first letter uppercase.
And if I save, that's what we get.
Now, let's add on the rest of the word so we can do that by taking the Pokémon DOT name and we're going
to use slice and with slice, we can get part of a string.
So I want to say I want to I want to slice from the one position on K, because you can look at it like
a string.
The first one zero second one one.
I mean, you can look at it like an array, even though it's a string.
So we want from the second letter, which is the one position on so if I save now, you can see we have
uppercase and the rest is lowercase.
So let's see for the I.D. here.
Where is that.
So we have number and we could do Pokémon dot I.D. but I do want to pat it with zeros.
So what I'll do is create a variable up here called I d set it to Pokémon dot I.D. and we want to first
make it to string, so convert it to string and then I want to pat it with zeros and there's a method
called pad star.
OK, we want to pad the beginning.
So basically three spaces, we want to pad it with zero.
And then down here, instead of Pokémon ID, I'm going to use just I.D. and now we get zero zero one
zero zero two, so on.
Now the type is going to be a little difficult because it's an array, right?
If we can so log Pokémon DOT types and we look down here, we have an array.
Some have to, some have one.
They're objects with a type, object with a name value.
So let's create a variable here called type and set that actually first of all, let's get.
Let's get the type names, so let's say pokey dash types and set that to Coatimundi types, which is
what I just showed you, but I want to use MAP to create a new array.
So map we loop through and we'll say for each type I want to return the type, which is an object and
I want to get the type dot name.
OK, and if I cancel like this, so poky underscored types.
When we take a look, we have these arrays with zero fire, one flying, so just an array of objects
with the type.
Now, to get the actual type of the current Pokémon, I'm going to first go up here.
So we have the colors, which has all the types that we need.
So I just want to create an object that'll be, you know, zero fire, one grass and so on.
So I'm going to create a variable called main types right here.
And we can use object dot keys because we want to use these keys here as the values.
So let's pass in colors.
And now if I can so log main types and we take a look, we just have an array of all the different types
with no indexes.
So let's go back down and underwear.
I have Pogi types, let's say consed and tie all this type.
Want to take the main types, which is just a numbered list of types and we want to find.
So I'm going to call find where the types are going to loop through and say we're the type
or I should say where the Pogi types index we're going to use index of and then pass in that specific
type or that iteration.
And we want to see if it's greater than negative one, because if there's no match index of this method
right here returns a negative one.
So we want to see if it's greater than negative one.
If it is, then that type is in there and we'll get put in this variable.
All right.
So now down here where we have the type this grass right here, I'm going to replace with type.
OK, so you can see grass, grass, grass fire, fire, water, so now it's just taking the main type
and putting it in there.
Now, we also want the color to change depending on the type, right, so now that we have this type
variable, let's set a variable here called color and set that to the colors array.
And remember the index or the keys, I should say, of these colors are the types.
So we just want to use that particular type for that card or that iteration as the index for colors.
And then we just can simply set the element.
So Pokémon element will set the style so we can grab any excess style.
We want the background color, so background, color, and we want to set it to that particular color
so we'll save.
And now the background is going to depend on the type.
So fire has this red grass has this green water, blue bug is this orange and so on.
OK, and that's pretty much it.
And of course this is responsive.
It just it's a twelve hundred pixel container with flex items that wrap.
So they just go on to the next line.
All right.
So that's it.
Hopefully you guys enjoyed this little project.
And like I said, this API is really cool.
You can if you know more about Pokémon, you can deal with abilities and stuff like that.
I don't I don't really know anything about that.
So, yeah, like like most other projects, I'd encourage you to build on to this.