OK, so in this video, in the audience, I should say, this project, we're going to be creating this
mobile looking UI here with an image for the content and then some tabs down here.
We have homework blogging about us, and it's just going to show a different image, depending on which
tab we click.
If I click this one, you'll see the image changes.
So basically we're going to have a specific class of show on the content and a specific class of active
down here.
You can see the active one will be highlighted in purple.
So basically, we need to loop through these list items here, this menu, and add an event listener
on to each one so that we can remove, add and remove certain classes onto the content here, as well
as the items themselves.