All right, we're going to get started on our mobile tab navigation, so let's go ahead and create the
user interface.
I just have my project Project Starter open here.
Let's open up all of these files.
And I'm also bringing font awesome in using the CDN because we will be using font awesome icons for
the menu items.
So let's call this mobile tab navigation and get rid of that.
So everything is going to be wrapped in a class of phone.
So we'll have kind of like a phone UI container here.
And then for the images, I'm actually going to paste these in.
Let me paste in the first one.
So these are from on splash.
Of course you can use any image you want or you don't even have to use images if you want it to be content
or whatever text content, that's fine.
But we're giving this a class of content so all of them will have this content class.
But whichever one is showing is going to have a class of show.
OK, so I'm going to grab the other three images, which all have the class of content but do not have
the class of show.
OK, only the first one has the class or show.
So let me just push these over three or four images.
Now, the navigation we're going to put right under the last image here, let's put a nav tag and in
here we're going to have a little with a list item and then we'll have our icon.
So let's use font.
Awesome here.
It's going to be Fayaz and a dash home and underneath that will have a paragraph with the text of home.
OK, right now these images are going to be giant.
So just ignore this for now and then let's copy this list item here.
We're going to have three more.
So the second one here, the icon will be Box and this is going to be work and this one here.
Let's do the icon book Dash Open and this will be blog.
And then this last one here is going to be for users and this one will be about us.
All right, so that should do it.
Let's jump into the stylesheet here and I'm going to use Open Sans for my phonte, so I'm going to get
rid of this.
So to success and then questionmark and let's say family equals open, plus Sande's.
And then for the family here, we'll say open sans.
And we want a background color on the body here.
So background color.
I'm going to use Rajiva so red and will be 155.
Green will be 89, blue will be 182 and the alpha value will be zero point seven.
OK, so give us that purple color and then we have see flex direction.
We can get rid of that midnite, we get ready overflow hidden and you can go ahead and you can scroll
down, see all the images actually there.
They're all out of whack.
So we'll fix that soon.
So the class of foam wraps around everything.
And for that, let's set set the position of that to be relative so we can position stuff absolute within
it.
And I'm going to set overflow to hidden on that.
And let's set the border so we're going to have a border of three pixels solid and the color will be
triple he and let's set a border radius.
And also the border radius to 15 pixels and then let's at the height of this to six hundred pixels and
the width will be 340.
OK, so now we can see our image, the content inside.
So each image has a class of content.
Right.
So let's say phone and then the content, which is the image.
We're going to initially set the opacity to zero.
As soon as I do that, though, it's going to go away.
I'm going to just comment that out for now so we can style the rest.
Let's set object fit to cover and let's set the position of this to be absolute and then we'll set from
the top zero and from the left zero.
And you might see a different image, too, because remember, they're just all the images are they
are they're just in the same place.
And then for the height of this.
Basically, we're going to have down here our tabs and it's going to be about 60 pixels high.
So what we'll do is use calc here and we can calculate, we'll say 100 percent of the high, but minus
it by, let's say, 60 pixels so that it gives us a little bit of room down there.
And let's just make sure the width we set this to 100 percent and we're going to have a transition on
this, because when we change the image, basically when we, you know, rotate the class of show,
we wanted to have that kind of fade in effect.
So the transition is going to be on the opacity property zero point four seconds.
And he's.
Now, the content that has show, so let's say phone dash content, if it has a class of show, we want
the opacity to be one.
So let's go back up here and uncommented this that way.
The only image that's going to show or the only content that's going to show has that opacity of one.
OK, so it's this first one here because it has that class.
If I go on, I put show on this one, it's going to show that image OK?
And it doesn't have to be an image.
It could be some kind of content if you want.
Now it's style, the navigation.
So the NAV, I want to position that to be absolute within the phone container so you can see that we
can see it now, but it doesn't look very good.
Let's put it to the bottom so we'll see from the bottom zero and from the left zero, which is going
to move it down there.
And then let's set a margin top of negative five pixels, which is going to just bring it up a little
bit and let's set the width so the width here to 100 percent.
OK, now let's style let's style the menu because, you know, we don't want this to be going vertical.
We don't want list spots.
We want it to go across here.
So we'll start with the US.
So let's say now, well, I'm going to set the background color to white and let's set it to display
flex so that all of the list items will line up in a row as flex items.
I'm going to set list style type to none because I don't want any bullet points.
I'm going to set the padding and the margin to zero.
And the height is going to be 60 pixels and you can change this, but it should match whatever you have
up here in this calc value where we're taking that away from 100 percent of the height of the phone.
And I think that's all we want to do there.
Now for the list items, let's say NAV list items.
Let's do a actually one background color.
We want to color of seven.
It's going to make those lighter out a cursor pointer and we want them to be all spread out the same
width.
So out of flex value of one.
And the padding, we'll just do 10 pixels all the way around and let's text a line center.
So move the text moving from the left to the center and then let's see for the the text down here is
wrapped in a paragraph.
So we'll say NAV Ally paragraph or nav doesn't really matter, but we're going to select the paragraph
and I'm going to just change the font size to 12 pixels.
So make it a little smaller and then let's at the margin to two pixels, top and bottom zero, left
and right.
So paragraphs have a margin of 10 pixels by default.
We just lessened it to two when it, you know, took away that space.
And then whichever one is covered are active.
I want to change the color.
So let's say NAV will ally hover.
And also we want NAV.
You will ally if it has active
color.
And let's set that to hexadecimal eight E four for a D.
So basically we have you know, we have the show class on the image and that's that's what we want to
show.
And then whichever tab here is active, we'll also have a class of active like this.
And now you can see, since I put that class of active, it has that purple color, so that should be
it for the success in the next video, we'll go ahead and make this function to where we can click on
one of these and it will change the content to, you know, whichever tab we're clicking on.