OK, so we're going to start on the JavaScript, which is going to be pretty easy, and I would challenge
you to try and do this yourself beforehand.
Basically, we need to bring in all the contents, which are, you know, these images here with the
class of content.
So query selector all will bring all those in.
You also want to bring all the list items in and then add an event listener on each of these.
OK, so you might want to loop through with a for each and add an event listener and then you want to,
you know, add the class of active to whichever one you click on and also add the class of show to whichever
of these images or whichever content should show.
So let's say const contents and we use document got query selector all because it's more than one.
We're going to select the class of content.
And then let's also grab from the NAV you'll we want all the list items and we'll call this list items
and we'll take the list items and let's loop through those.
So for each and we'll pass in here and arrow function and say for each item.
And we also want to get the index.
So I'll just use IDEX here.
This should be a fat arrow and then let's add an eventless star.
So add eventless onto the item that we want to listen for a click and on Click we're going to first
of all, hide all the classes of show or I should say, remove all the classes of show and active.
So let's have two different functions.
This will be hyd all contents and let's say hide all items.
OK, so we'll go down here and create these functions.
So hide all contents.
And what we're gonna do here is take the contents and then for each one of those.
So for each content, which is each div with the class or I'm sorry, each image with the class of content.
Right.
Yeah.
So class of content.
We brought that in here.
Now we're looping through and we want to take whichever content is current in the iteration and remove
that class.
So class of star remove of show.
OK, and then let's copy this and let's do hide all items and take say for each of the list items,
you will change that to item and let's remove the class of active.
OK, so I save that and I go and I click on one of these.
You'll see that there's no active class now on any of these because none of them are purple and there's
no image showing because there's no more show, there's no more show class.
And the show class is what makes the opacity one.
The opacity is zero by default.
So after we initially hide those, let's take the item that we click on and let's take the class list
and add to it the class of active.
So if I click on this one here, you'll see that this is active, this is active and so on, and then
we also want to add the class of show on to the correct content.
So here, let's say contents and remember, contents is a node list, so I can access zero one whatever
index I want.
I want to use the index from this foreach so that the first one shows the first one second item shows
a second and so on.
So we want to add that class of show on to that.
So now we start off here.
This is already active because, you know, we have it right here.
And then if we click on the second one, this will be active.
It's purple and it should show the second image.
OK, the second one in the node list, this one here will show the next one.
This one will show that one.
OK, so it's always going to show the correct one because of the index that we're adding that show class
on to.
OK, so hopefully that makes sense.
So I will see you in the next video.