OK, so this is a pretty simple project, what we're going to do here is have a form.
It's basically a login form and the length of the password is going to be detected.
And this image, it's going to start off blurry.
And as the password gets longer and stronger, this is going to become more clear.
So you'll see if I go ahead and enter one character, it gets a little more clear.
Another another.
And eventually it just ends up as a completely clear image.
So it's a cool little way to test password strength.
Now, this is obviously very simple.
It's only going by the password length.
You could add on to this after and you could, you know, see if there's special characters or uppercase
letters and numbers and all that.
But this is this is going to be pretty simple to begin with.
We're also going to be using the Tailwind CSFs framework and we're just using a CDN.
We're not going to, like, download it or compile it or anything like that.
We're not using NPM.
We're just going to throw the CDN link in so we can use some of the classes and make the styling a little
easier on us.
All right.
So you'll get a little bit experience with some of the tail when utility classes in this project as
well.
OK, so let's begin.