OK, so let's get started on our password image strength project, whatever you want to call it.
We'll go ahead and just call this password password strength background.
Now, this is going to be a little different because we're actually going to use Tailwind CSFs, which
is a framework access framework, just so we don't have to actually write a lot of success.
And it's just a really cool framework.
We're not going to get deep into it and, you know, and compile it or anything like that.
We're just going to use a CDN.
So if we go to a CDN J.S. dot com and just type in tailwind, we want to grab this and this right here,
this tailwind dot access.
We're going to copy that link tag.
And let's put that right above our custom style access and we'll save that.
You can see the font already changed and we're now using the default tailwind access.
So for the HTML, let's let's close this.
First of all, actually will open up the rest of our files here and then close that and let's get rid
of this H1 here.
So I want to have a background image that we can work with to, you know, add that blur effect to.
So I'm going to have a div here with the class of background and also an I.D. of background and nothing's
going to go inside of it.
We're just going to use that for the background.
And then let's have basically a wrapper around everything and we're going to give us a few tailwind
classes like BGU Dash White.
So this is going to be the box in the middle with the with the form the form fields.
I'm also going to make it rounded.
So we'll add rounded and these are tailwind classes so we don't have to actually create the access for
this.
Want some padding.
So I'm going to do p dash tend to do padding all around.
I want center so text center and let's add a shadow to it as well.
So Shadow will do shadow MMD Shadow Medium.
All right.
Now and again, these are Tailwind classes.
If you're interested in tailwind, I have a crash course on YouTube.
There's there's a lot of videos on YouTube is paid and free courses.
It's a really, really cool framework if you want to look more into it.
So here I'm going to have an H1.
I'm going to give this a class of text, dash three Excel to make it a little bigger.
And inside here, we're just going to say image, password, strength.
You can put whatever you want.
I'm just putting that.
And then we'll put a paragraph here.
I'm going to give this paragraph a class of text which will make the text smaller and then text dash
grea dash 700, which will give it a shade of grey.
And we're just going to say change the password to see the effect.
All right.
And then under that paragraph, we're going to have a div.
Let's give this a class of Mooi.
So my intelligence is margined on the Y axis, which is top and bottom.
I'm going to do dash four and it's also do text dash left.
And in the stiv here, we're going to have our label and our input for the email.
So let's add let's just go down here a little bit.
Let's add a label.
So the label is going to have a class.
We'll do text Gray Dash nine hundred.
And in the Slovo, we're just going to say email whoops.
Oh yeah.
We can say for email.
And then inside here we want to say email and then under that label we're going to have our input.
So this input is going to have a few classes.
We're going to have border, let's do block.
So it's a block level, it reaches all the way across.
Let's make sure the width is full.
So w dash full padding to P two once a margin on the top, so empty dash two and I want it rounded.
So I'm going to add the rounded class.
OK, and then we want to have a few other attributes so we have input type text in the classes.
I'm also going to add an idea of email and I'm going to add a placeholder as well and just say enter.
Email.
All rights that should be good, it's actually put a call in after the label so you can see over here
we have our email now we want to do the passwords.
I'm going to copy this div that wraps the label and the input.
You know, let's put that here and just change this to password.
Let's change the type two password and the classes here.
We can actually just leave those the I.D. password and the placeholder enter password.
All right.
So now we have our two fields.
The last thing we want is the button.
So let's go outside of this div here and let's put in a button here.
So this is going to have quite a few classes.
I want BGU Dash Black and let's do text dash white and for padding, let's do piecewise of padding on
the top and bottom two and let's do margined top to push it down a bit.
Will do empty two.
And I want to display this actually it's too empty for and I want this to be an inline block.
So we'll add the inline block class and let's do with dash full and rounded.
OK, so those are the classes we want for the text.
We'll just say submit and let's give it a type of submit as well, even though it doesn't really matter.
But we'll just go ahead and save that good.
All right.
So now for this for the customer access, let's go to our stylesheet.
A lot of the styling is already there from the tail when utility classes.
But we want to give it that background image with the blur.
So as far as what we have in our default styling, I'm just going to get rid of the fonts.
We don't need to include that with Castalian has its own font.
And then for the styling of the background, we have a class of background and all that is, is a div
at the top.
Right.
So we want this to cover everything and we want to add the background image to that.
So let's first of all, set the background image.
So it's going to set background to a neutral and the image link I'm going to paste in.
And you can if you want to use the same image, you can just you know, you can either copy this, you
can get it from the repository.
Let's set it to no repeat and let's set the positioning to center center on the X and Y axis and then
cover for the background size.
Now, we're not going to see anything just yet because it's just an empty div.
We want to position this to be absolute and we want to set I'm going to set the top to be a little further
than the edge.
So we'll do negative twenty pixels and let's set bottom to negative twenty.
We're going to set it on all sides of top bottom left, negative twenty and write negative twenty.
And if I do that we're going to see the image here.
Now it's it's covering, it's covering the, the login box which obviously we don't want.
So we'll just change the Z index.
Let's make this the index to negative one and then the login box will be on top of it.
Now I want to start start the image out to be blurred.
And then the longer the password gets, the less the the the less of a blur the image will have.
So insists we have this filter property and we're going to use Blur and we're going to set it to twenty
pixels blur like that.
So basically the higher this is, if I set this to thirty, it's going to be even more blurry, but
we're going to set it to twenty zero obviously is knobler ten is a little blurry, but we're going to
set this to twenty to start off with.
OK, so that's all we need to do for the HTML and access.
In the next video we're going to do the JavaScript which should be really, really quick.
It's only like nine lines of code or something like that.
All right.
So we'll do that next.