OK, so now we want to add the JavaScript here, and this is this is actually an area where you could
pause the video and try to do this yourself.
So basically, as we start to type, the longer the password length is, the less blurry we want the
image to be.
And remember, it starts at 20 pixels.
So you essentially want to subtract from that 20 pixels, whatever the length of the password is, and
then multiply that by two.
That's going to be the the the math that will be using here.
So if you want to try it yourself, you can do that.
But I'm going to go ahead and start and bring in, first of all, the password input.
So let's call this variable password and document Doggett's element by D and we should have an idea
of password.
Let me just double check, make sure I put that.
Yep.
So idea of password.
And the other thing we want is the background, which is this div here and that has an idea of background.
So let's also grab that.
We'll call this background, all right, now we need an event listener on the password input, so let's
take that password input and let's add an event listener onto it.
And we want to listen for any input and then fire off a function.
So I'm going to use an arrow function.
We're going to pass E in here the event parameter because we need to get the value.
So let's say const input and let's set that to e target dot value.
OK, so that way we get the input and we'll just go ahead and test it with a console log here and let's
open up our console, get rid of that.
And as soon as I start to type it, we'll show whatever we're typing, whatever that input is.
Now, the next thing we want is the length of the input.
So let's create another variable here called length and set that to whatever the input dot length is.
And we can go ahead and console log the length here.
You see, it'll just give us the number, the length, and then we're going to take we're going to take
the the twenty.
That's what we have the blurr set to initially.
And we want to subtract from that the length.
Let's actually let's console log this.
All right.
So if I type in here, you'll see we get 19, 18, 17.
So I actually want to multiply that by two so that we get if I have one character, we get 18, 16,
14, 12, because I want it to go down by two each time.
And then when we get you know, we get start getting here.
We passed zero and we go negative.
So what I'm going to do is put this into a variable.
We'll call this blurr value.
And then we'll take the background and we want to edit the filter properties to the assess filter properties,
so we'll say style dot filter and we're going to set that to let's use a template literal here.
So use tactics and set it to blur.
So what we're doing is just essentially setting this value right here, the filter and the blur.
And instead of 20 pixels, we're going to use whatever the blur value is.
So we'll pass in blur value and then be sure to just add pixels after that.
All right.
So now we go back here.
I'm going to close that up and I start to type.
So I'll just type something and you can see it got a little less blurry.
So it should be at, what, 18 now and 16, 14, 12, 10, eight, six, four, two and zero.
So now anything negative obviously will still it'll be a clear image.
OK, now this is this is a really good project for you to to expand upon.
Right now, it's it's just testing the length of the password.
But you could test for things like special characters and numbers and all that, and you could use like
regular expressions.
There's there's a whole load of things that you could do.
But I think it's a good project to to add on to.
But that's all we're going to do for now.
So I will see you in the next one.