All right, so now we're going to create this 3-D box's project and we're going to be using some modern
access to create this 3-D effect where we have this angle here and here and we connect the right in
the bottom side and it just gives us a 3-D box look.
And then we're going to be using a background image or a background gif for each of these boxes.
And it's all the same image.
It's this minyon image.
And what we're going to do is extend the background size beyond the single box to make it as big as
this container here.
And then what we'll do is dynamically calculate the background position so we can move these around
and basically form what looks like one big image when really this is just a bunch of the same image.
We're also going to add an event listener onto this button here.
So when we click this, this whole area shrinks and it also gives us this rotate effect on each box
and then it combines them all together.
So there's no spacing in between.
And it just looks like one big connected image.
All right.
So we'll be using things like CSFs transforms and transitions.
We'll use the after and before pseudo selectors.
We're going to be using a loop and JavaScript to go through these boxes and calculate the background
position and also add an event listener onto this with some success transitions to give it that rotation
effect.
All right.
So that's what be doing.
Let's go ahead and get started.