All right, guys, we're going to get started on the 3D box's background project, so I have my project
starter open my three files here.
Now, the HTML for this is going to be really simple.
It's actually only going to have two lines in the body.
One will be the button and one will be the box container and then the individual 16 boxes that are going
to transform into one box.
When we click the button, those are going to be created from within the JavaScript.
However, for now, until we get to that, I will just hardcoded them and then we'll remove them later
on and and add our JavaScript.
All right.
So let's go ahead and get started here.
Let's just change the title to see 3D Box's background and let's get rid of this H1 and let's put our
button so we have a button.
And I'm going to give you an idea of BTN and a class of magic.
And inside here we'll see magic.
And I'm just going to paste in an emoji here.
You don't have to, but if you want that, you can just grab it from the repository and then we're going
to have our boxes container.
This is going to have an idea of boxes because we do need to use it within the JavaScript and for styling
we'll add a class of boxes.
And inside here, like I said, this is ultimately going to come from the JavaScript, but for now,
we're just going to hard code them.
So let's go ahead and say a class of box and we want 16.
So we're going to do asterisked 16 enter and that will give us 16 divs with the class of box.
Go ahead and save that.
And all we're going to see is the button, because obviously these are just empty divs.
But we have to go ahead and style these.
So let's jump into our style access.
And we have our our boilerplate, our Raboteau font.
We are going to use the Poppins font for the buttons.
So what I'll do is just go ahead and duplicate this and let's go right here, right before the ampersand,
get rid of this and let's put in toppings like that.
And then down here in the body, we're just going to add a background color, a very light gray.
So it's going to be F A three times.
Can't even see the difference, but just a light gray background.
And then let's start on the styling for the button, which has a class of magic.
So it's magic.
And we're going to give this a background color of a yellow.
So we'll use hexadecimal here with the value of F nine, C A two for.
OK, so that would be the background.
The color is going to be white.
Let's add our font family here of Hobbins.
Sans serif, save that good, want to get rid of that ugly border and let's make let's give it some
rounded corners.
So border radius, border radius, I'm going to do three pixels and let's make the font size 16 pixels.
Add some padding to make this bigger.
Will do twelve on the top and bottom 20 on the left and right.
Good.
We want to have a cursor pointer so that when we hover over it we have our pointer.
Let's, let's position this to the top.
So I'm going to use position fixed which we'll position it fixed in the browser window and we'll see
from the top 20 pixels.
So let's move it up and then let's also add some letter spacing to space out the letters a little.
We'll do one pixel for that.
Good.
And let's see, we're also going to add a little box shadow on the bottom.
So for Box Shadow, we have our X offset, which I'm going to set to zero, and then the Y offset.
I'm going to set that to three pixels because I just want it to be slightly on down here on the Y axis,
right on the bottom.
And then for the color we'll use in RGB, a yellow.
So red, green, blue, alpha.
So two four nine four four red, 202 for green, thirty six for blue and then for the alpha, which
is the transparency will do zero point five.
So now you can see that there's a slight box shadow underneath.
All right.
Now I want to get rid of this ugly outline on the focus state.
So what we can do is take the magic class and say focus state.
We want to set the outline property to not get rid of that.
And then I also want to an effect that when we click, click and hold, when it's in its active state,
that it moves down a little bit and gets rid of the box shadow.
So it gives the effect of it's going over the box shadow.
So how we can do that is with magic in the active state.
We want to first remove the box shadows or set box shadow to none, and then we'll go ahead and set
the transform property and we're going to use translate.
Why?
Because we want to translate.
We want to move it along the Y axis, just two pixels, which will move it down.
If I did negative two pixels, it would move it up.
So let's save that.
And now you can see when I click and hold it basically like covers that box shadow.
All right.
So I'm also going to add to this magic button, a Z index of we'll just put one hundred because I want
it to always be on top, even if the browser is really short and the image the boxes go underneath,
I want the button to be on top.
All right.
So that takes care of that.
Now we're going to start on the boxes.
So we have the boxes container and then we have the individual box class.
Right now, I want to be able to see what we're doing with the boxes.
So for now, I'm just going to add a background of yellow and the height and the width here are very
important.
So that's going to be one twenty five for both.
OK, so the width is going to be one twenty five.
Now the reason for that is because the box is the container is going to have to do a height.
Is going to have a Hitner with a 500.
Which is one one twenty five times four is 500, and we want four across now to create the rows and
columns with with our success, we'll go ahead and use flex box on the container.
So let's say display flex.
As soon as I do that, they all get put in a row.
However, they're not being knocked down to the next.
I mean, there's only four that can fit here.
So I want them to wrap.
Basically, if it hits the edge, I want them to go on to the next line, create a new row so we can
say flex wrap and set that to wrap.
OK, now the reason it looks like one big block is because the numbers here are exact, right?
One twenty five times four is five hundred.
So there's no in between here.
Now, ultimately what I want to do is click this button and have them separate, have each box separate.
So what I'll do is I'll add a class onto this called big.
OK, I'm going to save that.
And then I'm going to say down here, if if the box is class, also has a big class, then let's go
ahead and extend the width and the height to six hundred pixels.
OK, so from 500 to 600, 600.
And that's going to make the container bigger.
Now this obviously doesn't look right.
We want this remaining space over here to be around each element, around each box.
So what we can do is where we where we display flex here, we can set the justified content to be space
around.
Now, if I save that, you can see now the remaining space is around each element.
All right.
We're also just going to add a position so that position relative to boxes and then down here for each
box, let's go ahead and replace the yellow with an image with that gif.
OK, so we're going to say background image and we want to set that to you, Earl.
And the link I'm just going to paste and this is from Jiffy dot com.
And if you want to use a different gif from this website or something else, you can do that.
So I'm going to go ahead and save that.
And now you can see that we just have this this one image in every box as the background.
All right.
Now, ultimately, we're going to want to change the positioning and the size of each of these.
So let's let's actually add a background repeat and we'll set that to no repeat.
And then for the for the size background size, we want to set this to the same size as the the initial
boxes because we want it to take up that entire thing.
Right now we have the class of big on, so it's at 600.
But ultimately we want the size to be 500 pixels on X and Y.
OK, so now you can see that it's stretched out and you can only see part of the image and it's the
same part in each box.
But later on we're going to change the positioning of each of these so that it looks like one big image.
All right.
So let's see the next thing that we'll do here.
We want to have a position of relative on this because we're going to be using the before and after
pseudo selector to give that that cubed border look.
And we need to position that absolute.
So we want the container of that to be relative.
Now, another thing we want to do is when we do click this button, what's going to happen is it's going
to toggle this big class, OK?
So it's going to go from that to that.
And when that happens, I want to have a rotate effect.
So we want to add a rotation to to to the boxes if it has that big class.
So let's go right here and let's say so.
Boxes has the big class.
We want that each individual box to have a transform and we're going to use rotate Z with a 360 degree
angle, OK?
Now we want this.
When this happens, we want it to transition nicely.
So let's add a transition on two boxes.
So transition just so you know it rotate smoothly and we'll use four point four seconds with an EZ effect.
And then I'm just going to copy this and put the transition in the box as well.
And now as soon as I save, you can see that it actually does that effect.
OK, because when that big class gets added, it will go ahead and do that.
And we're going to make this button ultimately add and remove that class, which will make it toile
into place.
OK, so it'll twirl or.
I should say rotate and then go all together, and then it'll rotate and split apart.
All right.
Hopefully that makes sense.
Now, the last thing that I want to do here is add that kind of that cubed effect.
So not only do we want, like a border on the right and the left, but we want it to skew.
So it goes like this at an angle.
So to to do this, to do the right side, we're going to use the after pseudo selector so we can take
the box class and then say double colon after.
And you can use this to insert content.
It needs this content value and we could even put something in here.
And now you can see that after that box element, it puts telo.
But we don't want that.
We just want to leave this blank.
The only reason we need this is to add some styling so you can think of it as kind of like a like an
invisible element.
So as for the styling, let's go ahead and add a background color and we're going to use the background
color of F what is it, F sixty five eight D it's going to be the background.
We're not going to see anything just yet.
We need to add the sizing and position and stuff like that.
So we want to position this absolute OK, so we're positioning in absolute and you need to have relative
on the box because absolute should be.
It's relative to the box.
Right.
And then for the positioning, the coordinates will do eight pixels from the top.
We want because we want to push it down a little bit because we're going to add that skew and then over
let's do from the right let's do negative 15 pixels because we want it to be, you know, going this
way.
And then for the height, we want it to take up one hundred percent of its container, which in this
case is the box itself.
And then the width is going to be 15 pixels.
So if I save that, you can see we have this yellow part here and it's pushed down a little bit because
of this eight.
In fact, if I put a zero here, you can see it's flash.
However, I want to use that.
I want to have that SKU effect here and here.
So it'll be on both sides.
And to do that, we can just use transform and we want to skew on the Y axis because it's up and downs
vertical.
So skew y forty five degrees.
And if I save that now, you can see we have that effect of it's coming off here and going, you know,
at a skewed angle on both the top and bottom.
Now we want to do the same thing here.
We basically want to come from here and go over so it looks like has that 3D effect.
So I'm actually going to just copy this whole thing and now we're going to use before.
OK, and for the background color, we're going to change it slightly.
We're going to use the same yellow robes.
We're going to use the same yellow that we used.
Or is it or is the yellow that I used for the button right here.
So we're going to just we'll just copy this background color here and set that here.
OK, just slightly different yellow.
And for the positioning, we want it to be absolute, although we want to change.
We're going to go let's see from the bottom.
We want to go negative fifteen and then from the left.
We want to go eight pixels.
OK, so it's basically the reverse of what we had before and then the height, the width is going to
be 100 percent and then the height will be 15.
So it's basically just the horizontal version of what we just did.
And then we want to skew on the x axis because it's horizontal.
So I'll save that.
And now you can see we basically have that same thing, but going this way.
So what we want to do in the next video is, of course, we want to add the functionality where we click
this button and it does its little rotate and goes into what looks like one big image.
And we want to be able to toggle that.
But we also need to change the background position.
We need to make that dynamic within these boxes, because right now they're just all in the same position,
which obviously doesn't look right.
We want it to look like it's one big image.
All right.
So that's what we're going to get into next.