OK, guys, now we want to start on the JavaScript, which isn't a lot, actually, it's only about
about 20 lines or so, a little less.
But I first want to just explain what we need to do with the background position.
So ultimately, as I said before, all of these boxes are going to be inserted to the DOM via JavaScript.
We're not going to have these hardcoded and we're also going to add a background position to each one.
Now, I'm going to do that manually just so you can see what the values are going to be.
So for this first one, we'll just go ahead and set a style here and set the background position.
So background position has an X and Y property for this first box.
It's going to be zero zero, OK, which is the default.
So, I mean, it's not even going to change, but that's going to be the first one.
The next one.
Let me just copy this right here, this whole style and put that.
And so this one here, let's let's think about where this needs to be.
So remember, these are one hundred and twenty five pixels with and height.
So for this one, we want part of the 125 pixels to be shifted this way.
All right.
So with this background position as first value is the X value, so we want to go negative one twenty
five pixels.
And if I save that now you can see that it basically looks like it's connected.
In fact, if we get rid of this big class and we save it is connected.
So for the next one and if you guys want to take a second and think about what you should put here,
go ahead and do that.
So we did for the X value, for the second box, we said negative 125.
Now for this one here, we want to actually double that.
Right.
So instead of negative 125, because if I do that, it's going to just match this one.
We want to go over 125 more.
So we want to change this to 250 fifty.
OK, and now it looks like it's part of the image.
Like it's one big image for this one here, the fourth one.
Let's go ahead and do negative three.
Seventy five and then we go.
So now we have our top row now four for this one here.
It's going to be a bit different because now we're dealing with both X and Y values.
So for that for this one, we're going to have and I'm going to get rid of this.
I'm just showing you what these are, what we need to do within the JavaScript.
But this is going to be zero on the X axis because it's it's the first one and it's going to be on the
Y axis.
We want to do negative four and twenty five because we want to bring it up.
OK, now the second one we need to bring over and up.
I should say that it's actually the six one we need to bring over.
And so what we would do is on the x axis one twenty five and then on the Y negative one twenty five.
There we go.
OK, and then we would just continue that, bringing in, bringing these up and over.
So what I'll do is just completely get rid of all the boxes.
OK, we just want to have the container here.
I just want to have this ID boxes, class boxes and then that's going to completely go away.
Now we're going to jump don't jump into our script and do this with JavaScript.
So first thing we need to do is bring in any elements that we need, such as the boxes container.
So we use that document object and we're going to use the method get element by D and we're going to
get the ID by the boxes ID.
And then we also want the button because we need to add an event listener to that.
So let's say const BTN and we'll use document element by day.
Believe it has an idea of B10.
OK, so we bring those in.
Now the way that I'm going to do this is we're going to do a function called create boxes and we want
to call that function and then inside create boxes.
We need to create four boxes for each row.
So four columns of four rows, four columns.
So the way we can do that is we can use two for loops.
OK, so let's say for and I'm not going explain what a for loop is.
It is expected that, you know, at least the fundamentals before taking this course.
So let's say let's I so we want to set it to zero.
And then the condition here is going to be if I is less than four and then we want to increment I by
one.
OK, now we have rows and columns here, so we want to put another for loop and we have to use something
different than I.
So let's do that.
J equals zero.
And then as long as J is less than four and then J plus plus increment it by one.
Now within here we want to construct those 16 boxes.
OK, so this is going to look through 16 times and we're going to create this with document and then
there's a method called Create Element and we want to create a div member.
So we're just creating these these divs here, that's all.
That's all we're doing right now.
And we can even go ahead and console log box.
And if we go over here and open our console, you see that we now have should be 16 divs.
Now, remember, they need to have the class of box.
So what we can do is take our box variable or box element, take the class list and call the add method.
And we want to add the class of box.
So if we save that now, we can see that over here in the console.
Now this is where we're going to do the positioning.
So to add a specific style, we can use DOT style and then whatever property we want.
And it has to be in Camil case, obviously.
So we want background position and we can't do background Dasch position, which is what we would do
in case we do it like this with Camil case.
So background position and the way we can set this to be dynamic is we can put some template literals
here so that we can use variables and expressions.
And remember, it's going to be something like, you know, negative one twenty one twenty five pixels
zero.
It's going to be something like this.
But of course this is going to be dynamic.
So what we can do is we can put a variable syntax.
So dollar sign and curly braces, we can put in a variable or an expression in here and we're going
to take negative J because remember it's going to be negative, negative 125, negative 250, etc..
So we want to take that and multiply it by 125.
So it'll loop through.
It'll be, you know, zero then negative 125, native to 50.
Negative three seventy five.
So that's the X value.
Now for the Y, we're going to go ahead and put another variable expression in here and use negative
eye and also multiply by one twenty five.
So this will do exactly what I did manually a few minutes ago, but it will add it through the JavaScript
dynamically with these calculations.
Now the last thing we want to do is not console log.
Let's get rid of that.
We want to take our box boxes container that we brought in earlier and we want to call Append Child
and we want to add in the box.
So if I go ahead and save, let's see.
Something's not right here.
Let's see, so we set the box start style background position to oh, I forgot pixels.
So right now it's just setting it to the numbers we need to actually add in after these pixels.
And there we go.
So right now we have the class.
Or I'm sorry, we don't have the class of big, so it's 500 pixels which squishes them all together
and there's no in between.
But if I add the class of big, it separates them, but it's still intact.
Now, we just want to add an event listener onto let's actually get rid of.
No, we'll keep the class there to start with.
But let's go back to our script and let's go up here.
Actually, we'll go and we'll do it right here.
So we'll take our button.
And we want to add an event listener.
So we want to listen for a specific event.
Now, this takes in the event we want, which is a click and then a function so we can either put a
function or we can use an arrow function like this.
OK, and we just want to we don't even need since this is only going to be one line of code, we don't
even need these curly braces.
So we'll just take the boxes container and take a class list and then toggle so it'll add and remove
the class of big.
So let's save that.
Let's go over here.
Let's click and there we go.
So we get that cool effect.
And just to show you, let me just make this bigger.
So we're just about done.
If I show you in the console, put this over here and we look at this class, right.
So you can see that the class of big is there.
If I click that, it adds and removes it.
And that's what causes that effect.
And we have that rotate in the success.
Right.
So right here, we have this rotate which is causing that to happen.
We also have a transition of point four seconds.
You can increase that if you want or decrease that if you want a different speed.
But yeah, so that's pretty much it.
All right.
So hopefully you enjoyed this little project.
And let's move on to the next one.