All right, so in this project, we're going to create a verify account UI and you might have seen this
if you you know, you sign up for something or whatever and they send you a code and you have to validate
that code on a Web site or some kind of app.
And this is just the UI part.
We're not adding any kind of functionality other than the UI and typing in numbers and having it hot
to each input here, because these are all separate inputs.
So basically when you come to the page, it's going to focus on the first one and I can put in a number
and then it's going to bring me to the next input.
I can put another number, another one.
And then if I want to change a number, if I want to go back, I can hit backspace and put a different
number in continue on.
If I want to change that again, I can change that and then enter.
And then you would have it, you know, validate with whatever with your database and authentication
and all that stuff.
But this is just the UI.
So that's what we're going to be building in this project.
Let's go ahead and get started.