OK, so let's start on our HTML here, and I have my browser a little wider than usual just because
of the width of the UI.
So in the title, I'm just going to change that to verify counts.
And down here, we're going to have a container.
And in this container, let's do an H2 and just say verify your account and then a paragraph and I'm
going to just copy and paste that paragraph in which basically just says, you know, we emailed you
a six digit code, enter the code below, and then let's do a code dash container, which is going to
wrap around the code, which is going to be six inputs.
So let's say input and let's give this a class of code, except it's not going to be text, it's going
to be a number type and we're going to add a placeholder of zero and then let's set a minimum and a
Mac.
So on a number input, we can set a minimum, which is going to be zero.
And Max, let's set that to nine and let's make this required, OK?
And then I'm gonna copy this down.
That's two, three, four or five, six.
So we want six total and then outside of the the code container still within the regular container.
Let's do a small tag with a class of info.
And in here I'm just going to paste in some text and basically just says, you know, this is the design
only we don't actually take your email, we don't have your email and that should do it for the HTML.
So let's jump into our stylesheet here and I'm going to use the Molay font.
So success question mark and set the family to emulate I and then say Colen 300 for the weight 700.
And then we're going to change that here as well.
And let's just add a very light background color to the body.
So for that we're going to do hexadecimal F, B, F, C do CFT.
OK, so not much of a difference.
It's just it's a light gray, very light gray.
And we can get rid of flex direction.
Whoops.
Didn't want to do that and get rid of Flex Direction column, which I just did.
And then the rest of that can stay container.
So container wraps around everything.
And for that I want to do a background color of white and then let's do a border of three pixels, black
and solid, and we'll give it some rounded corners of border radius, ten pixels to add some padding,
gives them some space in there.
So padding will be thirty pixels and let's do a max width for this container of will do 1000 pixels
and then let's text align everything to the center and that should do it for the container.
Now for the code container which wraps around these right here, all these inputs do that code container.
And we're going to display flex, so we're going to make this a flex box, which will make all the items,
all the inputs, flex items, and I want a line to the center.
So we want line items and justify content to the center.
And let's also just add a margin to the container, 40 pixels on the top and bottom.
OK, now we want to do each individual input, which has a class of code.
So I'm going to set the border radius to five pixels.
I'm going to make the font size much bigger.
So 75 pixels and we'll give this fixed height of, let's say, 120 and a with of 100 pixels.
And then for the for the border, let's do border one pixel and we're going to make it really light.
So we'll do solid and then triple E.
OK, so very faint border.
And then for the margin, I'm just going to do a one on one percent margin.
So kind of break them up a little bit.
Texta line.
Obviously we want the numbers in the middle.
So text align center.
Let's set the font weight, make sure that that is set to 300 and then I think that's it.
So that looks pretty good.
We're going to get rid of these arrows here.
I don't want those.
The way we can do that is by taking the class of code, which is the input, and then colon, colon
dash, web kit dash.
What is it?
Outer outer spin button, and then we want the inner spin button as well.
So code colon, colon dash, web kit dash, inner spin button and we're going to set dash web kits,
appearance to none.
And let's set margin to zero.
So if I do that now, you can see that those are gone.
However, that's going to be chrome and safari to get rid of those arrows on Firefox.
We can go right into code, into the code class and use Mozi Dash appearance and we can set it to TextField
so that should get rid of the arrows on Firefox.
Now when I click in here we put something.
I already had zero in there, if I put a number in here and go to the next one, I want this to have
like a box shadow around it and change the border color so we can do that by using the valid state.
So if we take the input of code and say Colen valid, let's do a border color of three four nine eight
DB and then let's change our let's add a box shadow.
So Box Shadow will do zero 10 pixel offsets, 10 pixel blur negative five pixel and then legba.
So the color got the X, the color is going to be black with zero point two five for the alpha.
So now if it has the number in it, you'll see that it has this border.
It also has the box shadow.
Now for the for this down here, I'm just going to add a little bit of style to that which has the class
of info.
So out of background color of E.A. three times.
And let's let's display this as an inline block because it's a it's a small tag, so it's displayed
in line by default.
And I'm going to add padding to it of ten pixels and let's do a line height of twenty pixels and let's
do a max width of 400 pixels.
So just kind of squeeze in and we'll change the let's do color seven seven seven.
So it's very light.
And also a border radius will make its border radius five pixels.
OK, now I do want to have this wrap because if we you know, if we make this smaller, just kind of
cuts off.
So what we'll do is just add let's add a media query here, so say media, and let's do a max width
of 600 pixels.
So when this is six hundred pixels or less, let's take the code container and set Fleck's wrap to rap.
So that way it goes on to the next line.
And then I'm also going to shrink the inputs a little bit.
So code, let's set the font size, which I think is 75 by default, will set it to 60.
And the height, which I think is 100, will set that to 80 or it's 120.
I believe we'll set that to 80 and then let's set a max width of 70 pixels.
OK, so it'll make it a little smaller.
You know, rap, all right, so that's it for the success of the JavaScript isn't going to be too bad.
What we want to do, though, is make it so when I click in here and I put it, I type a number and
then I type another number.
I don't want it to be in the same box.
I want it to be in the next one so we can quickly just type the code in.
All right.
So let's jump into our JavaScript and let's bring in the inputs so we'll say const codes because they
all the class of code and we're going to use document dot, query selector, all because there's more
than one that we want to grab.
So the class of code that will put these into a node list.
Now, we initially want to focus on the first one.
So just like an array with a node list, I can take an index.
I want zero, which is the first one, and I'm going to call the focus method.
So as soon as I do that and when we come to the page, it's going to automatically put the cursor in
there, because when we come to the page, we wanted to just go right into the first one and then as
we type go across, you know, across these inputs.
So next thing we'll do is take the codes and we can loop through with a foreach.
So I'm going to say for each code and I'm also going to grab the index of each code, each input, and
I want to add an event listener.
So code add event listener.
I want to listen for the key down event.
And when that happens, we're going to run a function with an event object.
And I want to just check to see if the key so I can take this event object and say, Dorcy.
So if that is greater than or equal to zero and I also want to check to see if it's less than nine.
So e dot key if that's less than or equal to nine.
Now, if that happens, I want to then move to the next one.
So if I type like two in here, I want this to focus on the next code and the next input so we can do
that by taking codes, which is a node list or basically an array.
And we want to set, let's say, index.
So when we loop through, we have an index that starts at zero, then the next one will be one, two
and so on.
We just want to add one to that index and we want to focus on that one.
Now, if I go down here and I do that, it does move to the next one.
But notice it.
Whatever I hit, which was a three in this case, it goes into the second one here.
If I hit it again, I mean, that works.
But for that first one, we want it to go in that first box so we can just add a little set time out
here and wait, you know, ten milliseconds or so and then do it.
So set time out, which takes in a function.
So I'm just going to take this and put that here.
Since it's a one liner, we don't need curly braces and then set time.
I'll take the second argument of the time out, which is going to be for us.
We'll just say ten milliseconds.
So that way if I go down here and I put something in here, it waits and then it allows us to put the
number in the first one and then we can keep going.
Now, if we hit delete, I want it's not doing anything now, but I want it to go back to the one before
it.
If, you know, if we mess up and we need to put a different number.
And so let's do an else if and I want to check to see if the delete button is hit or the backspace key.
So let's say e dot key.
If it is equal to backspace, which with an uppercase B, then I want to do the same thing that I did
here, except I want to do index minus one to move backwards.
So now if I do like three, five, six and then say I messed up with the six, I can go back.
However, this gets kind of messy because now if I hit delete again to try to delete that six, it goes
back to the next one.
And then I end up with two numbers there.
So it's still it's kind of messed up right now.
So this is a really easy fix.
What we can do is as soon as we hit, you know, a number here, we want to basically just clear it
out so we can take, we'll say codes.
And then whatever the current index is, we're going to set the value to an empty string to just nothing.
So now if I do like two, seven, six, and let's say that six was a mistake, I can hit backspace and
then hit another number and it will replace it.
OK, five backspace, change that to a seven, three, four and then whatever, whatever you would have
happen after you enter the code.
This is just the UI part of it.
All right.
So, yeah, hopefully you guys enjoyed this and we shouldn't end up.
With two numbers in any of the spaces, no matter how fast we type or anything like that.
All right, so that's it.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next project.