OK, so in this project, we're going to create a live user filter where we're actually going to fetch
a bunch of users from an API called Random User Dot Me.
So we're going to fetch them, put them in here, and then we're going to be able to filter these users.
So if I just do if I type in an are here any user that has an R in either their name or their location
is going to show I'll do our oh, let's say let's search for this Roman guy.
So our M and you see that the only user that matches that is this Roman Roberts.
And if I delete it's going to still it's going to continue to filter.
OK, if I want to search for this all over and if I delete, it's going to just match whatever I put
in here.
All right.
So we're going to be dealing with the API.
We are going to use a sink await as opposed to the then syntax for fetch, which returns a promise.
So we'll first create the UI style with access and then we'll fetch the data and will implement the
filtering.