All right, so we're gonna get started on the on access for this project.
So let's jump into our index e-mail here for the project starter.
So we're going to call this live user filter.
And let's go ahead and get rid of this one here.
So basically, we're going to have a we're going to have a container here and then we want the the input
and underneath that will have an analyst with the users.
Ultimately, the users will come from the API that we're going to fetch from, you know, through the
JavaScript.
But for now, we're just going to hardcoded them just so we can see it.
We can style it.
Then we'll move on to, you know, making it dynamic.
So let's create a header here.
Go ahead and just create a class of header.
And let's use an age for give it a class of title and say live use or filter, and underneath that age
four, I'm going to put a small tag and give this a class of subtitle.
And here we'll say search by name and or location.
And then under that small tag is going to be our input and the input is going to have an idea of filter.
Type text, and let's just add a placeholder to it, so Placeholder will say search.
OK, so that's the header, so we can go underneath that div, actually we can use a header tag here,
he's a header tag and then underneath the header, let's do our U.
L am going to give this an idea of result.
This is where we want our results to show up and we're going to give it a class of user Dasch list.
All right.
So inside this ule, like I said, the the list items are going to be generated with dynamic data,
but for now, we're just going to hardcoded them.
So let's add an image here and I'm going to use https and let's use random user MI API, which where
we're just going to get just a static image now.
But later on, when we actually fetch the users, the random users, it's going to be from the same
API.
You can use it just to insert a random user image or you can make a request to get some Jason data for
random users.
So right now we're just going to do portrait portraits slash and then we can do like women slash 33
JPEG.
If I save that, we're going to get a random image here.
And then for the ALZ, we'll just use a name, say, Sahra, and under the image here we're going to
have a class of user dash info and in here will have an H for with the name, let's say Sarah Smith.
And underneath that let's do a paragraph with the location will say Wexford Ireland.
And then what I'll do is just copy that list item and I'll just put two more, I'm just going to use
the same image and name.
It's fine because like I said, this is going to come in from the API.
Ultimately, we also want an ally for that.
Just says loading while we're fetching the data.
So I'm going to put that in as well.
So that has to be a list item within page three that says loading dot, dot, dot.
OK, so that'll be our HTML.
Now let's jump into our stylesheet.
So for the styling, see, we use this font for the body.
I'm going to add a background color of hexadecimal, Efate F nine F.D. and C display Fleck's.
We can get rid of the Flex Direction column on everything centered.
OK, that's good.
Now the container wraps around everything.
So for that, let's add a border radius of five pixels and I'm going to add a box shadow.
So for the box shadow, let's do three pixels for both of the offsets, 10 pixels, blah, blah, for
the color, which is going to be black, and then zero point three for the transparency actions to point
to.
And why aren't we seeing that, because I spelt container wrong.
There we go.
So now you can see the border radius with the box shadow.
Let's also add overflow hidden.
So how many scroll bars, the width, I'm going to set that to 300 pixels.
OK, so that should do it for the container.
So the title here, let's remove any margin from that.
So margin zero and then for the subtitle, oops, let's go let's go under here and add the subtitle.
And I want to display that as an inline block because remember that's a small tag which by default is
in line.
And then I'm going to add a margin of five pixels, zero 20 pixels, and I'm going to add an opacity
of zero point eight, which will make it even, you know, faded a little bit.
And let's see for the header.
So we have a class of header.
Let's add a background color for that.
And that's going to be three, say, three five seven DB for that background.
And then the color will be white.
And then let's add padding for let's do 30 pixels, top and bottom, 20 pixels left and right.
OK, so our header is starting to look a little better now.
The input, we want to style that.
So let's say the header input.
I want to set the background color to be a value.
Zero zero zero so black and then zero point three, so it just looks, you know, has that kind of transparent
look to get a get rid of that ugly border.
Let's do a border radius.
We're going to make this rounded, so 50 pixels for that and the color of the text is going to be white.
And let's set the font size.
So font size is going to set to 14 pixels, this is on the input and then we're going to set the padding.
Let's do 10 top and bottom, 15 left and right, and then let's make it go all the way across so we'll
set the with two 100 percent.
All right.
And I also want to get rid of this this border here, so let's say heter input's focus, we want to
set the outline to let's do not.
OK, so of get rid of that ugly outline, good, so the next thing I want to do is this user list here.
So it's a you and has a class of user Dasch list and let's set the background color to white and let's
set the list style.
We'll do list style, type none, which will get rid of the bullet points.
We don't want those.
And then I'm going to remove any margin and let's set a max height here of 400 pixels because you don't
want this to be too long.
We're actually going to have a little scroll here, if, you know, to to check out all the users in
the list and then let's do an overflow, because right now we won't have any scroll bars.
But if we set overflow, why so basically on the Y axis, let's set that to auto.
And if we need scroll bars, it's going to give us this little scroll bar on the side, which doesn't
look too bad.
And then finally, let's set padding to zero as well.
And I'm just going to move that up next to the margin.
All right.
So now the list items.
So we have our user list and we want to style the allies I'm going to display as a flex box and let's
set padding to 20 pixels.
OK, now let's do let's see.
All right, let's do the let's do the image so we have a user list image and I want it to be rounded,
so we'll use border radius at that to 50 percent.
That'll make it rounded.
And let's do object fit cover.
We want the whole image to show in there, and then we're going to make the width and the height 50
pixels.
OK, so kind of small, but I think that looks all right, the user info, so we have user dash list,
dot user info.
For that, let's set margin left to take it away from the image, some margin left 10 pixels that will
push it over and then let's set on the floor.
I'm just going to grab this through the floor and they're going to set margin zero zero ten pixels.
And for the paragraph,
let's just set the font size to 12 pixels will make that a little smaller.
All right.
That doesn't look too bad.
Let's have a border one, a border in between.
But we don't want to border on the last list item.
So what we can do is say user list and then the ally.
And I'm going to use the pseudo selector of not.
And in here we use the pseudo of last of type.
So basically what we're saying here is, you know, any list item that is not the last, then we want
to add a border bottom.
So let's say border dash bottom and we'll set that to one pixel solid and let's do triple E for the
color.
OK, so we have a slight border there.
Now we're going to have a class of hide because when we start to, you know, filter these users, if
it matches, we want to add the class of hide, which will basically display none.
So let's say user list elai.
And if it has a class of hide, then we're going to want to display none.
OK, so if I manually, you know, come over here and put on one of these allies, a class of high that's
going to get rid of it.
OK, but obviously that will be dynamic because we want to filter it out with whatever we type here.
So I think we should be good.
The loading you know, the loading will show before any any of these users show.
Right now, we just hardcoded it in here just so we could see.
So now I'm just going to remove everything, all these allies except for the loading.
So we'll get rid of those now that we know that those are styled correctly and save.
OK, so our basically our UI here is is complete.
We just now need to make it function with JavaScript.
So we'll do that in the next video.