OK, so now we want to fetch some data, some users from a third party API at random user dot me.
So this API is pretty simple.
It's it's it's open.
So you don't need any kind of key or anything like that.
You don't need to sign up for anything.
You simply make a request to random user slash a random user, me slash API and you get I think you
get one user by default, but you can set a query param of results and get as many as you want.
So we can actually just show you this in the browser.
I'm just going to copy this.
So random user API, if I run that it gives me the it looks like it gives me one user, but if I put
on this a query string, so if I do questionmark and then results and set that, let's set that to 20,
you'll see it gives me 20 users and it gives you all kinds of fields, your name, name, location with
a full address, age, phone number, even password, username and password.
So it's a really useful API for just like dummy data.
So that's what we're going to use.
So let's close that up, go into our script and I'm going to start off here by just bringing in what
I need.
So let's bring in the result.
So in our index, each time we have this right here, the USA, with the idea of result.
So we want to bring that in.
So document dot, I'll go ahead and use git element by these and result.
And then we also want our filter, which is our input.
So that has an idea filter or at least it should just make sure I put that.
Yeah.
So idea filter right here.
OK, so bringing in those and the next thing I want to do is just initialize a very an array here called
list items and it's going to be just an empty array.
So basically where we're going to put the data that we fetch and let's create a function and this is
going to be asynchronous because I'm going to use a sink away.
I'm not going to use the DOT then syntax.
So I'll say async function and we'll call this get data and let's say Congress.
So this is going to represent the response from our request.
Now, this fêtes returns a promise.
So we want to await since we're using a sink away, we want to await, fetch and let's pass in here
http s random user dot mi slash API and I'm going to get fifty.
So we'll do let's say results equals fifty.
OK, now what the API.
We need to then call resident Jason to get our data.
So let's create a variable called data and let's await because this right here, this says that's going
to be this resident Jason here is going to be a promise.
We want to await that.
And then that should give us our data and I'll go ahead and just cancel log data just so we can test
this out.
And we're going to run this function right here, say get data.
And then if we go over here and open up our console, we should see, OK, so we get an object with
two things.
We have info and this has like I guess pagination and stuff like that, the number of results, the
page.
So results is what we want in this should have 50 different users.
All right.
So let's.
Let's go down here.
Let's get rid of this console log here and I want to clear the results before we do anything.
So we'll say results and set the inner HTML results start in our HTML, set that to just an empty string.
And then we're going to have to loop through the data here, actually know what we can do since we need
to do data dot results, because remember, this gets an object with info in results.
So we could we could go down here and say data dot results or we can just d structure here so we can
just pull out results from the data, actually.
Yeah, that's fine, because we called this result singular so we can use the results here and then
we can just grab that and we can loop through that.
So for each.
For each so say for each user, because that's what it is.
So each user then let's go ahead and I just want to console log here user just to make sure we're getting
this good so you can see it's logging all the users.
And let's construct an ally, because right now in our HTML, we just have you know, we have the intel,
we do have the loading here, which is going to show initially, but we want to construct the list item
for that are going to have the users.
So let's do that in this foreach will say const ally and let's use document dot create element because
we want to create a list item for each of these users and then we want to take our list items array,
which starts off as an empty array, and then we want to push on each of the allies.
OK, so we push that on and then we'll take the lie and add the inner HTML.
So this is going to be, you know, similar to the hardcoded HTML that we had for each user.
It'll have the image and stuff like that, which we can get from this user object that's passed in to
this foreach when we loop through the array.
So in here, let's say image and set the source and we want to set this to we're going to use this variable
syntax and let's take the user now.
We can access user dot picture and then there's different sizes.
I'm going to do large.
So user picture large and you can see all this stuff if you make a request, you know, either in your
browser or with something like Postman or whatever the ALZ, I'm going to use the the user's first name.
So we have user dot name dot first.
And if you're wondering, you know where I get this name dot first and stuff on this picture dot large,
every API is different.
You just have to, you can look at the documentation to see what it gives you.
Actually we can see right down here where I logged it.
Let's see.
So you can see name.
So name is actually an object with first last and title.
So I'm getting the first picture.
Should be in here somewhere to so picture we have large medium thumbnail so it just depends on the API.
I know when I first started learning this stuff it confused me.
Like where did you get this from.
It just it depends on the data that's being sent from the API.
Same thing with, you know, here where we get results, sometimes some APIs, the data might just come
as, you know, one array or our single array or it might come in different objects like a results object.
This one also had an info object.
So it just depends on the data you're dealing with.
So this image here, let's finish this up.
And then we have under the image, we have a div and let's give this a class of user Dasch info
and user info, we're going to have the name.
So it's going to be in an age four and that's going to be the first and last name.
So let's go ahead and get the user dot name dot first and then MySpace and then we'll get user dot name
dot last.
And then underneath that we'll have our power graph and this is going to be the location.
So with this particular API in the data it gives us, we have access to user location, dot city, and
then I'm going to put a comma and then I want to get the country.
So user dot location, dot country.
OK, and you can see that right down here.
So in location you have city, you can have coordinates.
So you could place them on a map.
I mean, you can do a lot with this little API.
So that's that.
Now we have the list item created.
We added it to the array, we added the entire HTML.
Now we just need to put it into the result, into the HTML.
So we have that result that we pulled in.
That's the you'll we want to append child because we're putting this elai into the U.S. So we want to
just pass lie in there.
All right.
So if I save that, you can see here now we're getting 50 closer.
So we're getting 50 different users.
Now, the loading shouldn't be showing, and that's because it should be clear result.
So I'm not clearing the results.
The data I got, it's the result you all that I brought in.
So let's save that.
And I can see that's not going to show now for the filtering.
We need to have an event listener when we type in this input.
So let's go right down to where we call, get data initially and let's take the filter, which is the
input and let's add an event listener on to it.
And we want to listen for any input.
And when that happens, we're going to fire off fire off an event that's going to call a function.
We're going to pass our event, object in and then call a function called filtered data that we're going
to create and we just want to pass in e so our event dot target dot value, which is going to give us
whatever is being typed in.
So down here, let's create our function for filter data and that's going to take in let's call search
term.
So whatever is being typed in and just to show you can console log search term.
And if we open our console up here and I start to type, you can see we can capture whatever we're typing.
So I'm going to then take the list items, which is the, you know, the array of users and loop through.
So we'll say for each call this item.
So for each item I want to check.
So we want to basically check to see if it matches the user so we can do that by taking the item, see
if the item dot in our text.
So in our text for the item, remember list items is the elai.
So we're going to go through the allies and check each item and check the inner text and I'm going to
make it lowercase by using to lowercase like that, because even if we even if we type in uppercase,
I still want it to match.
So we'll first convert it to lowercase and then we're going to use the includes method.
So we'll say if the inner text, when it's lowercase or not, when but we're going to convert it to
lowercase if that includes the search term that's passed in to this function.
And we also want to make that lowercase.
So they're both going to be lowercase.
We're going to match that.
If it matches, then we want to remove any class of hide.
Remember, the high class is just set to display none, right this right here.
So we want to just take the item and set class list, dot remove and we want to remove any classified
else.
So if it doesn't match, basically if we're not matching what we type in, then we want to add the class
of hide.
So let's say item dot, class list, dot, add and then we want to add the class of hide.
OK, so now you can see we have Rothesay, Roger right here.
If I do r so now it's going to filter anything that has an R is going to be included here and this includes
anything that's in here.
So the name and location.
So you can see these all have ours somewhere in here.
Right.
Let's do our O and now it's only giving us either names or locations with R.
Oh G.
And that leaves us with Roger.
All right.
If I do you know Roger and then I start typing more letters, it's not going to match.
And if I remove, it's going to if this you know, if it matches again, it's going to remove the classified.
So it's just adding and removing that Hyde class as we type and as we delete.
Right.
So that's it.
And you can apply this to to, you know, any kind of list that you want to be able to search through.
Really easy to put together.
But that's it.
It's go ahead and move on to the next project.