Hey, guys, this is another project from Dribble, so this is by a DIKO gas bar, hopefully I pronounce
that right and this is a survey or feedback UI design.
And basically we just have, you know, these a couple of smiley faces with unhappy, neutral, satisfied,
and we can submit the feedback and then just show a thank you message here.
So that's what we're going to do.
And this is the project here.
So it says, how satisfied are you with our customer support performance?
We have three choices.
I can click on one and you'll see that it highlights it with the box here.
So basically, we're just going to change the class to active and I'll click send review and then we
see.
Thank you with whatever we chose for the feedback, which is satisfied.
And it says we'll use your feedback to to improve our performance.
All right.
So pretty simple, but when we get to the JavaScript, we're going to do things a little different instead
of just looping through, you know, these these ratings here, these boxes and adding an event listener
on each one, we're going to take advantage of event bubbling and add an event listener to one of the
parent nodes and then target the specific rating nodes.
All right.
We're going to look at some different properties for dealing with the DOM and, you know, moving to
different elements and stuff like that and also, of course, the success to create this interface.
All right.
So let's get started.