All right, let's get started with our feedback design or feedback UI design, and I just have my project
starter open here.
I do have a link to font.
Awesome, because on the you know, once we submit the feedback, there's an icon on that screen there.
So we're going to use that and we're just going to change the title here to let's say, let us know
your feedback and we're going to get rid of this H1 here and let's create a container here.
I'm going to give us an idea of panel and also class of panel Dasch container.
And in here, we're going to have a strong tag and let's say, how satisfied are you with our.
And then I just want to put a line break here to make sure that the rest of this goes on to a new line
and then say customer support performance.
And underneath that strong, we're going to have a ratings container, so it's a ratings Dasch container
and this is going to contain the three boxes with the, you know, those the faces.
So each one will have a class of rating.
So it's two rating and inside here will have an image.
And these images are actually from flat icon dot com.
So I'm just going to pieces and these are FGs.
I'm going to paste in that first one there and underneath the image still within the rating div will
have a small tag with the actual rating, so this would be unhappy.
So if I save that, that's what we're going to see.
It's not going to look too good until we get to the styling.
But for the other two.
So that's our first rating div and then we have two more.
So I'm just going to paste these in.
OK, so we have the first one here.
We have the second one which is neutral, which is a different image, and then we have this one here
satisfied and noticed.
The last one does have the active class on it.
So it'll have the outline.
So let's save that.
But we'll have the outline once we have the success.
Right now, it's just going to look like this, OK?
And then at the bottom, let's see.
We want to go outside of this div and this div and right above the ending panel contain or div and have
a button.
And I'm going to give this a class of B10 and let's give us an idea of send, because we're going to
need to add an event listener in the JavaScript onto that and we'll say send or view and that's it for
the HTML.
So let's jump into our stylesheet here and for a font we're going to use Monserrat.
So I'm going to just right here.
It ends with success.
Will do Questionmark family equals Monserrat.
And let's add that to the body.
OK, and for this stuff here, we're going to display flags and we actually don't need the Flex Direction
column, we do want to align center and height 100 viewport.
That's good.
And let's start on the panel container, which wraps around everything.
So panel container is going to have a background color of white.
And actually, one thing I want to do on the body is out of background, so on the body will say background
color and this is going to be hexadecimal value F F nine, f two.
So just like, great.
And you can you can barely see the difference.
So you can see the background.
It's almost like a very, very light tan color.
And I also want to add a box shadow on the panel container so we'll do zero zero for the offsets and
then 10 pixel blur and then GBA for the color, which is going to be black.
Zero zero zero and then zero point three.
OK, so you can see we just have this slight box, shadow border radius.
So I want this to have rounded corners just slightly, so do four pixels, border radius, and let's
set the font size of the text in here to a default of 90 percent.
And I want to display flaks.
As soon as I do that, it's going to look like this.
We don't want this.
We don't want to row.
We want these to be, you know, on top of each other.
So we'll set the flex direction to call them instead of Roe, which is going to make it look similar
to how it just did.
But we want to justify content center.
We want to align items center.
And let's go ahead and add some padding to this container.
So 30 pixels padding, take everything away from the edges.
Let's add a max width of 400 pixels here and let's text a line to the center, which I'm actually going
to put up here.
So next, we're just going to increase the line height of this right here, which I believe that's a
strong tag.
So, yeah, we just have that wrapped and strong.
So let's say panel container strong and let's set the line height to twenty pixels.
And then we're going to start to style the ratings, so ratings container wraps around this, the three
faces here, three boxes.
So it's a ratings Dasch container.
And for that, we want to display as a flex box, OK?
We want that as a flex row.
And then for margin here, let's do 20 pixels on the top and bottom.
Now, for each rating, remember, we have the class of rating and I'm going to set I want them all
to be equal columns, so let's use flex one for all of them.
And then we're going to set the cursor to a pointer because we're going to be clicking on them and then
padding.
Let's do 20 pixels all around, kind of separate them out.
And then for margin, let's do 10 pixels, top and bottom, five pixels left and right.
All right.
Now let's handle the hover.
We want to have that the box around it when we hover.
Also, we want to make it when we click on it so the box stays on it for the hover and active.
Let's do a class of rating and hover.
We also want this on the class of rating when it has a class of active.
So I'm going to set the border radius to four pixels and we're going to we're not going have a border,
we're going to have a box shadow.
So box shadow, let's do zero zero 10 pixels, our GPA and zero zero zero.
So red, green, blue zero and then zero point one for the alpha.
And you can see that the active one has that box around it.
And if I hover over any of them, it has that box as well.
Now the image.
So let's take the image that's in the rating class rating div and let's give that a width of 40 pixels.
It's going to make them a little smaller.
We also have the small tags which has the, you know, unhappy, neutral, satisfied, so let's say
rating small.
And I'm just going to change the color of that to five, five, five.
And let's set that to display in dash and block because these are small tags are inline by default.
And then I just want to add a margin to, say, 10 pixels, zero zero.
That'll push them down a little bit.
And then if it's active, I just want to change the color of the small to make it a little lighter.
So let's just take this.
So hover or small, I'm sorry, hover or active, but oops.
And then we just want to target the small tags for that and set that color to hexadecimal.
One, one, one.
OK, and then for the button style that so that has a class of buttons and set the background color
of that to hexadecimal value of three zero to D to be OK, it's going to be our background color.
So we want the color of the text to be white and let's set the border to zero.
Let's set the border radius to four pixels like everything else needs a little padding.
So we'll do padding 12 pixels top and bottom, 30 pixels left and right and make the cursor into a pointer.
OK, good.
Let's get rid of that outlines or say, class of BTN when it's in its focus state, we want to set the
outline to zero.
All right.
And then let's do big BTN.
And when it's in its active state, we'll go ahead and add a transform property and let's just scale
it down a little.
So from one, we'll go to nine point ninety.
So we just get that little, you know, scale down effect.
Now we can't see it just yet, but once we basically submit this form using JavaScript, we're going
to have an icon from font awesome.
Inserted with some text.
So I just want to add this style for that.
It's going to be a dash heart.
It's going to be the class for the icon.
I just want to make it red so color red and the font size, I'm going to make it bigger 30 pixels and
just set margin bottom just to push the content below it down.
Set that to 10 pixels.
OK, and that's it for this VSS so pretty simple.
In the next video, we're going to add the functionality where we can click and we can change the active
class and give it the the border, the or the box shadow.
And also so we can click this and it'll show us a page that basically says thank you.
You know, thank you for your feedback.
All right.
So we'll get into that next.