All right, so now we're going to add the JavaScript for this project and we're going to do do this
a little bit different.
We've had a few projects where we've had to click on something and just change the class to active.
And basically what we've done is kind of loop through the elements and then add an event listener on
each one.
In this project, we're going to use something called event bubbling to not have to add an event listener
on each element.
I mean, it's fine if you do in a case like this where we have three, but what if you have like 200
a table with 200 users with 200 delete buttons?
You're probably not going to want to add an event listener in every single delete button so you can
take advantage of event bubbling and event propagation.
So first thing we're going to do is bring in what we need.
Let's bring in ratings and ratings is there's those multiple ratings, which are the these three boxes,
basically.
So we want to use query selector all and get the class of rating and that'll give us a node list with
the three these three elements here.
We also want let's just copy this down twice.
So we also want the send button and that has an idea of send and we want to just use query selector
because it's just one element.
Same thing here.
We want to grab the panel, which has an idea of panel like that.
All right.
Now, like I said, there's a few ways we could do this.
We could take the ratings and we could do a foreach.
We could save for each rating.
We want to take that rating and add an event listener at a click event and so on.
But instead of doing that.
We're going to use event bubbling or we're going to take advantage of event bubbling, basically, when
we if we have an event on this button here and I click it, it's going to fire off for the button,
but it's also going to fire off for any of its parents.
So this panel, this box here is a parent of the button.
So if I were to take that panel and add an event listener onto it for a click event and then say when
the panel is clicked, then let's console log, we'll just console log, click, and I'm going to go
over here and open up my console.
Now, if I click this button, you'll see we get click even though it's not this isn't on the button,
it's not on send button, it's on the panel.
But the panel is a parent of the button.
If we look at elements here and we check out the button, you can see it's inside panel, OK?
Now, even if I were to click like one of these images, the smiley faces, that's still going to fire
that off because that's inside the panel.
So I'm clicking here and it's bubbling up to panel.
If I click on this this right here, it's going to work.
Now, I also want to show you, if we pass in an event object and then we console log e dot target,
you can call this E or a vent, whatever you want.
But if we look at the target and I click on the button, it shows us the exact element that I click
on.
If I click on this image, shows me the image, if I click on this box, not the image, but just inside
the box, that's a div with the class of rating panel itself.
If I click outside the panel, it's not going to do anything because it stops at the panel.
OK, so anything I click in here, it's going to fire this event off.
Now, what I want to do is target the these images because I want to click on these images and then
implement, you know, switching the active class.
So I'm going to check here, let's say, if he dot targets.
So if I see dot target, that's going to that's going to look at whatever element I click on and we
can look at different different aspects of this element.
I want to look at the class list.
So I'm going to say if e dot target class list, which is the list of classes, but then I can add this
method of contains and I can say, does it contain the class of rating?
If it does, then console log target.
So now if I click on the image notice it's not doing anything because this image does not have a class
of rating.
If I click on the box outside of the image, you know, in this box, but not the image, then it works.
And I don't want to do that.
I want it to be on the image itself, on the smiley face.
So what I could do is say if the target if what I click on, if the parent node class list contains
rating, then fire this off.
So now if I click on the image, you can see that it works OK, because I'm saying if the parent node
classless contains rating, which it does, which we can see right here, the image parent is this and
has a class of rating.
So you can target different elements based on pretty much anything really.
The IDE, the class, the type of element it is the node name.
There's there's all different, you know, properties that you can use.
So I'm just going to use this and I'm going to say, if this is true, then I want to take E dot target
and I want to add the class of active, but not on the target because that's the image.
I want to take the parent node and then take a class list, call ad and add active.
So now I'm just going to close this up for now.
So now if I go and I click on the image, you'll see now it has the box around it.
It's active.
Click on that.
That's also active.
Now, the problem is they're all active, which we don't want.
So we need to remove all the active classes beforehand.
So what we'll do is call a function here, let's say remove active.
And I'm going to go down here and create a function called remove active.
And we've done this before.
We could take ratings and do a foreach and, you know, remove all the the the active classes.
I'm going to use a for loop, which is probably not something I would do.
But just to switch things up a little bit.
So let's say let I equals zero.
So I is going to start at zero and the condition is going to be if I is less than the ratings Daudt
length.
And then we also want to increment by one through each iteration.
So ratings is the you know, the these three boxes here.
So we're just going to say if it's if I as.
Less than whatever the length is, then let's go ahead and take ratings, which is a no list, which
is similar to an array.
So we want whatever the index of I and then class list dot remove and we want to remove the active class.
All right.
So now if I click on the second one, you'll see it's active and it took it off the first one or what
actually happened is it took it off all of them and then put it on the second one.
I click here, same thing.
So now I can switch it to, you know, whatever one I want.
Now, I also want to when I click on one of these, I want to save whatever the the rating is neutral
and happy and so on, because I want to put that in when we click send I want to put that in the panel.
So I'm going to initialize a very old variable up here called Selected Rating and set it initially to
satisfied, because that's what it's going to be on.
You know, when we reload, we come to the page.
That's what it's on.
And then down here, when we click, I'm going to take that selected rating and I'm going to set it
to E Target, which is what I click on, which is the image.
And obviously, I don't want to put the image in here.
I want this text, which if we look at the elements tab here, the text is in the small tag right below
image.
So small is a sibling to image right.
Rating is a parent to image small as a sibling there on the same level.
So here we can use dot next element sibling.
Right.
So that's going to select the small tag.
That's the next sibling.
And I want the inner HTML.
I want the content inside of it and I'm going to put that into this variable.
So now if I console log.
Next.
Not next to only sibling for console log selected rating.
And they click on one of these, we get neutral, unhappy, satisfied, good.
I just wanted to store that I'm going to just get rid of this console log.
Now, when we send this when we send review, it's not going to actually go anywhere.
It's not submitting a form.
But I just want to change the UI here.
So let's go right here and say send button.
We want to add an event listener of click.
And let's say when we click, we want to take the panel and we want to change the entire HTML to let's
use a template literal here and we want to put in I tag those so we want an icon.
So class is going to be FRSS f a dash heart.
OK, and then under that, let's put a strong
and here we're just going to say thank you.
Under that, I just want to space I'm going to put a line break excuse me, and then strong
and in here, I want a safe feedback colon and then my variable syntax so I can put in selected rating.
And then let's just put a paragraph in here.
We'll say we'll use your feedback to improve our customer support.
All right.
So now if I go over here and I suspect neutral and I click send review, we get the correct, you know,
panel here, feedback, neutral and so on.
But we have an error down here type error that says cannot read property class list of null online seven,
which is right here.
So remember how the bubbling works.
If I click this, it's going to call you know, it's going to bubble up to panel.
So even though I have the event listener on send button, it's also going to call the one on panel.
And in that case, this this doesn't exist anymore because we've changed the whole inner HTML of the
panel.
So to fix this, I want to target this.
You know, I don't want to use panel here.
I want to target it further.
So I'll use the ratings container, which wraps these three boxes because the button is not in rating's
container, so it's not going to fire that off if we use it.
So here, I'm just going to copy this down and say ratings container and we want to use query selector
because it's just one element.
And then the class of ratings Dasch container and then instead of panel, say, ratings container.
So now if I select something and send review, we're not going to get that error because this is not
being fired off because it's not a parent of send button, OK?
It's actually sibling.
So we have ratings container and then we have send button.
All right.
I hope that makes sense that you can read more about event bubbling, event propagation.
And also, if I don't click anything and send, I should still see satisfied because we set that initially
here.
All right.
So hopefully you enjoyed this.
Again, this there's so many different ways to do stuff with vanilla JavaScript.
But I just wanted to show you a little bit about event babbling methods or I'm sorry, properties like
Parent Node, Next Element Sibling.
This helps you navigate the DOM because you need sometimes you need to get to other elements.
And there's just a ton of different methods to to do that.
So I wanted to introduce some of those.
All right.
That's it.
Thanks for watching and I'll see you in the next project.