All right, in this project, we're going to build a custom range slider, so in with a team of five,
you have an input type of range, but it's you can't really style it.
You have to basically tell the browser that you don't want it to show and then you can style the track,
which is this part here, and you can style the thumb, which is this part here on your own.
So that's what we're going to do and is going to be quite a bit of success because we have to pay attention
to which browser it's being shown on because it's different in every browser.
So we'll have the Web kit prefix for, you know, safari and chrome emoji from A and from Microsoft.
And then we're going to add some JavaScript for this label so that it will show whatever the value is
from zero to 100.
But not only that, it's going to calculate the it's going to be this is positioned absolute and it's
going to calculate the left value to move it along with the thumb with a little ball here.
All right.
So it's just a nice little widget that you can use in your applications and stuff in your uses.
So let's go ahead and get started.