All right, so we're going to get started on our custom range slider and the Tmall is going to be really
simple.
We're just going to use an input with a type of range.
But the styling is pretty tricky because these show up different depending on the browser you're on.
So we're going to have to add styles for all of the browsers.
Basically Web that we using the web kit prefix is going to be Chrome and safari.
The Mozi prefixes as Firefox and AMS would be, you know, Microsoft, Internet Explorer.
And what I'm what I have here is Chrome on the side, but I also have Firefox as well, so we can check
that too.
So the like I said, the e-mail is pretty simple.
So let's just say custom range slider and we're just going to have an H here with the same thing, custom
range slider.
And then let's do a class of range dash container.
And inside here we'll have an input with the type of range we don't need a name.
The ID will be range and we can set a minimum tax on this.
So basically where we want it to start, which is going to be zero and then where we want it to end,
which is going to be one hundred.
And then underneath that, let's put a label for range and I'm going to just hard code 50 in there for
now.
Ultimately, this is going to change depending on where this is.
So if it's at the beginning, it'll be zero at the end, hundred and then anything in between.
It's also going to be positioned right above this.
And we want it to move along with this.
So we'll need to use JavaScript to do that.
But that's it for the HTML.
Very simple for the CSFs.
Let's bring in the little font.
So family equals Plato and let's apply that down here.
And I see so like I said, we're basically going to have to style the track, so this is the track,
this line here and then this is the thumb.
We're going to have to style both of those differently for for basically all of the different browsers.
So the body here, I'm just going to keep the same let's move the heading up to the top, so I'm just
going to position it absolute within the body and then say from the top 10 pixels just to move that
up out of the way and then for the range container.
I want to position that relative, because the label this right here, the number is going to be positioned
absolute within it and we're going to calculate the position in JavaScript so that it can follow the
thumb here.
Now, we do have some some base styles for the range.
So let's say input, and we can target it with brackets and adding type equals range.
And I'm going to set the width to 300 pixels, get a little wider and margin.
I'm going to just do 18 pixels on the top and bottom because the label is going to be above it.
We want some space above it.
So let's see.
I'm trying to think before we can style this because we can't actually style it as is.
We need to basically make it go away.
And we can do that with dash web kit.
And I'm talking about the track the line.
So if we do a Web kit appearance and set that to none and save, you'll see that it goes away.
Now, we can actually style it on our own.
But before we do that, let's style the label actually know.
Let's let's give us a background.
We'll say let's do background image and we'll use a little linear gradient, let's say 135 degrees.
And then for the color here, let's do hexadecimal value F five F seven F A and that's from zero percent.
And then the next color, let's do hexadecimal C three C F each two to one hundred percent.
They are.
So you can see that this is just white now, OK, because we did that web kit appearance none.
So I just want to before we do the track, I want to style the label.
I just want to put it above.
It'll start off in the middle here.
So we'll take the range and let's do let's say plus label.
And for the label, we're going to set the background color to white and let's let's position it.
So I'm in a position that absolute within the range container.
And we'll say we want it from the top negative 25 pixels, so of move it up and we want it in the middle
of the range.
So we'll say from the from the left.
Let's do one hundred and ten pixels and let's give it a width of 80 pixels and padding.
We'll do five pixels top and bottom.
Let's text the line to the center and let's do a broader radius for pixels and let's add a little box
shadow.
So we'll do zero zero for the offsets, five pixels for the blur, our GBA black and zero point three.
So that gives a little box shadow.
All right.
So it starts off in the middle right where the thumb starts.
And ultimately, when we add our JavaScript will have it follow along this.
But that's good for now.
So now let's dial the track.
And this is only going to be four for Chrome and Safari right now because we're going to take the input
range and then do Colen Colen Web Kit Dash.
And it's this is the track.
So we want slider Runnable track.
That's what we're styling here.
And I'm going to set the background to purple.
So as soon as I do that, the color changes.
But you'll see if I go to Firefox, it's still white because we need to use the emoji prefix for that.
But let's do chrome first.
So purple.
Let's do a border dash radius and we'll set that for pixels and let's set the width.
To 100 percent, the height I'm going to set that to 10 pixels, make it a little thinner and set the
cursor to a pointer so that styles the track in chrome.
Now we want to do the thumb, which is this round part.
Now, again, we can't style it directly.
So let's first select it with dash web, kit, dash, slider, thumb, and we have to add Web kit dash
appearance none.
OK, so now it completely goes away.
But we can, we can customize it.
Now let's give it a height of twenty four pixels and a width of twenty four pixels and we'll give it
a background of white.
So now you can see it's just a, it's just a square.
So you can, you can add images.
You can this however you want.
We're just going to make it a circle.
So let's say border dash radius 50 percent, which will turn it into a circle.
I'm going to give it a border, one pixel, solid purple.
And it's it's off the track, it's too low, so let's say margin top and let's do negative seven pixels,
so that'll push it up more.
And I think that's really all I want to do.
Now, this border around it, we want to get rid of that.
So let's take let's put this.
Up here, so we'll say range, and then when it's in its focus state, let's set the outline to not.
OK, so that gets rid of that ugly border and again, if you check Firefox out, it still looks like
this because we haven't added the prefix yet.
All right, and I think I think that's I think that's it as far as the style goes for Chrome.
So now what we'll do for Firefox and let's just sort of comment right here.
So this is for Chrome and Safari.
And then I'm going to just copy what we did here with the track and the thumb and let's say Firefox
paste that.
And now instead of Web kit, slider Runnable track, it's Mozi Range Track.
So Dash and Mosi, dash range, dash track.
And as far as the styles here, I'm going to just keep what we have and then for the range it's going
to be Mozi dash range.
Dash thumb.
I'm sorry for the thumb, not the range.
So it's the track and the thumb.
Now I'm just going to save this and go to Firefox now and you can see we have pretty much the same thing.
For some reason it has this white background and I can't figure out how to get rid of that.
So one thing we could do is increase the height on Firefox to 12 pixels and the purple should cover
the white.
I guess we could do like 13 like that.
You might have to kind of mess around with it a little bit.
Let's also add a cursor pointer to this right here.
So say cursor pointer there.
We'll add that up here as well on the Web kit.
So it's just it behaves a little different in in other browsers, so you just want to be aware of that.
Now, for Microsoft, I mean, I don't have, you know, Internet Explorer on this machine.
I can't test it, but I'm just going to grab what we have for we'll just copy what we did for Firefox.
And Seiichi, so the prefix we want to use here is a mess, and it's going to be moustached track.
And this is going to be.
Moustache Thum.
And I mean, if you want to test it on an Internet Explorer, you can if it looks a little weird, you
can, of course, change some of this stuff up.
But, yeah, I'm just going to keep it like that.
So now we have the style down.
Firefox looks looks good.
I'll keep that open.
Chrome.
And of course, if you want to change colors or change the shape of this or the size of the thumb here,
you can do that.
But in the next video, we want to make this function so that this number changes depending on the value.
Also, we want the position of the label to follow the thumb as we move it.
So we'll get into that next.