OK, so now we want to add our JavaScript to do two things, we want the value to display in here when
we move this, that's not going to be too difficult.
We also want the position of the label to follow the thumb, to be right above it.
So that's going to be a little more complicated.
So let's jump into our script here and let's get our range input.
So has an idea of range.
So we'll do document doget element by D, get the idea of range and then we want to add an event listener
onto that input so that listener and the event is going to be input that will fire off whenever we move
the range slider and we want to have an arrow function with our event object passed in here and then
we can get the value.
Let's say const value equals e dot target dot value.
So EGT target represents the element that this event listener is on, which is the range.
Now I do want this to convert to a number, so I'm just going to add a plus sign here and then I'll
just give it the type of number.
So then we'll go ahead and add it to the label.
Now we can get the label, let's say const label and we have access to IDOT Target, which is the input.
Now though, the label is directly after it and it's it's basically it's the next sibling.
So we're going to use the method called are the property of next element sibling.
That should give us the label and then we can say label dot, inner HTML and we can set that to the
values.
Now save that.
And when I move this you'll see that goes from zero to 100 and that's I mean, that's pretty simple.
Now for this to follow the thumb, we need to basically calculate the position of this label and keep
it above the thumb.
So this is going to be a little more difficult.
So let's let's do that at this at the very end where we assign the label and then we want to get the
the width of the range, which is actually set in the case file to 300 pixels.
So let's say consed range width and there's a function called get computed style.
And so allow us to get we can actually get values from our success, like the range is the width of
the 300 pixels.
That's what we want to get.
So we want to get the computed style for ITG Target, which is the input.
And then there's a method called get property value.
And the property we want to get the value for is the width.
So I'll go ahead and just console log here.
The range underscore with.
Now, if I open up my console and I fire that event, you can see it's 300 pixels if I change in my
success, so I change this to 400 and save and fire this off, you'll see it's 400.
All right.
So I'm going to set that back.
And that gives us the range with now we also need to account for the label with so for that, let's
actually just copy this and we'll call this one.
Say, label with and we want to get the computed style for the label, so instead of Target, which
is the input that that the event listeners on, we want to get it for the label and we want to get the
width.
OK, so that'll give us we can go ahead and cancel log that.
And when I move this, we get three hundred and eighty pixels.
And so it's going to stay the same because we're just getting the width of this and the width of this.
Now these, both of these have peaks on them.
I just want the number.
So let's actually create another variable called num underscore width.
And basically what I want to do here is just get the number for the range with.
So let's first convert it to a number with a plus sign and then we'll say the range with which right
now is just 300 pixels.
So we're going to use dot substring.
And say zero and then whatever the the length of the range with so let's say range underscore with dog
length, because it could be anything, it could be three pixels, it could be three million pixels.
So we want to get the length and then just subtract two because we're taking the peaks off.
We're taking the pixel off.
So now let's go down here and let's see what number with gives us that.
And you can see it gives us 300 and it's a number we also want the number with for the label.
So let's call this.
We'll say no, underscore, label, underscore with.
And actually, I'll just copy this whole thing here, but instead of the range with here, we want the
label with
an substring and let's change this to label with.
And then if we cancel log here, num label with, you'll see we should get three hundred and eighty
as numbers.
So now let's get the let's get the men in the max values because remember we set that in the HTML,
we set zero for the men, 100 for the max.
So we'll create a variable here called Max and set that to e dot targets and we can get it very simply
with just Max and we want to convert it to a number.
So out of plus sine and we can do the same for men.
So men set that to men and we can test that out.
And Max, and we should get zero in 100 good, because you could set the the men, Max, to anything,
we want to make sure that we have those values that we need to use this information, that we have to
apply the left property to this, to calculate it, to follow the thumb.
The ball here left is initially set on the label.
Where is it?
Right here to 110 pixels, which is right in the middle.
But we want that to change depending on where the thumb is.
So to do that, let's create a variable called left.
And we want to do a little bit of calculation here, we're going to take the value, so whatever the
the current value is zero to 100 and we want to multiply that by whatever the NUM with is.
And we want to divide that by the max, which, you know, in this case is going to be one hundred.
And then we want to take that and subtract the NUM label with which is the, you know, the number of
whatever the width of the label, because we want this to work regardless of how wide the the track
is or the or the label.
And we want to divide that by two.
So if we save that, actually, let's just cancel log left and see what we get down here.
So if I go all the way over, we get what, negative 40?
If I go all the way this way, we get to 60.
Now, let's apply that to the left CSFs property of the label so we can do that by saying label dot
style and we want to set the left value.
Now, we can't just set it to left because that's a no.
It has to be whatever pick whatever works like this.
Right, 110 pixels, not just one hundred and ten.
So let's make this so he's back ticks here and then Passan left here and then he.
So now if I go and I move this, you can see that it moves along with the ball here.
Now notice how it becomes off center as you move over on each side.
We want to account for that about ten pixels.
So there's a solution we can use.
I'm just going to bring this window over real quick.
So this is a stack overflow post and I'll copy this link and put it in the in the script.
But this is to map a range of numbers to another range of numbers.
And we've used this in another project in this course.
I'm not sure if I'm not sure of the exact order of the projects yet.
So we might have used it already.
We might have not.
But basically this scale function that someone created takes in a specific number and then a min in
the max.
So in in min in max and then in Outman and out Max, you can map a specific range.
In our case it'll be, you know, zero 100 because that's our men and Max.
And then we'll map it to negative 10 I'm sorry, ten and negative ten to kind of make up for that difference.
So I'm going to copy actually.
Let me just let me just paste this link here and just want to comment that I have and then I'm going
to grab this function here
and put that in.
All right.
So we have our scale function and then we can just go back up to our calculation here and just add to
that scale, which takes in first a num, which is going to be our value, and then a minimum tax,
which in our case is going to be Min and Max in in our case is zero and one hundred.
And we want to map to ten and negative ten.
So if we save that, we try this again.
Now you'll see that it always stays in the middle.
OK, instead of veering off to the side, so I know that this is quite a bit to this just to get this
little bit of functionality, but now you can use this in applications.
You have this nice little widget and of course, you can style it, you know, however you want.
But that's going to be it for this project.
I will see you in the next one.