Hey, guys, welcome to your next project.
So in this one, we're going to create a pretty cool mobile navigation effect, responsive navigation
hamburger menu, and we branded it Netflix mobile navigation.
But it's just because of the color scheme.
It's not the actual Netflix menu, as far as I know.
But we basically just have a little hamburger menu up here, a little hamburger icon, I should say.
And if we click it, we get this cool effect where there's three separate parts that come out in the
transition and some of them have delay.
So we have the black, red, white, and they come out and then when it goes in white, red, black.
So it's just a nice little effect.
It's a clean looking menu.
Obviously, you could put whatever you want in the page.
We're just going to put the logo in context.
But this would be whatever you would want to put in the page.
And of course, if we make this really small still, you know, works the same way, looks good.
I think there's a minimum width of three twenty or so.
So it should look good on, you know, smartphones and so on.
So that's what we'll be building.
Let's go ahead and jump into it.