All right, so we're going to get started on our Netflix branded navigation here, so I have my products
Storrar I do have a link to the font awesome CDN because we will be using two icons from font.
Awesome.
So down in the body, who actually gets to the title first.
So in the title here and it changes to Netflix, mobile navigation.
That's the name of the project.
And then down here we're going to first have our open button.
So let's add a button here.
And this is going to have two classes, NAV, Dash, BTN, which is going to be on both the open and
close and then open Dash BTN and we're going to use an icon with the class of facts and then a dash
Barzeh, which will give us a hamburger menu, hamburger menu icon.
So under that we're going to have the image, the logo, the Netflix logo is going to go in the middle
of the page.
It's also going to go in the NAV itself.
So we'll have two of them.
But let's say image with the class of a logo and the AltX will just say logo and then the source is
going to come from a remote link.
You can, of course download any logo or any image and put it in here.
But I'm just going to link to this Netflix logo and then let's do a paragraph with the class of text.
And I just want that to say mobile navigation.
So this is just the content that's going to go in the middle.
And right now the logo is huge.
In fact, I'm just going to add in the stylesheet real quick logo and let's say with one hundred and
fifty pixels.
All right.
Just so we can actually see stuff now, underneath that, under the paragraph is where we're going to
have our navigation is going to be three separate parts that that slide out.
You're going to have the red, white and black.
So what we're going to what we're going to do is have three NAV classes.
The first one is also going to have nav dash black and then inside that will have another nav class
with a class of nav dash red and then another one with nav and let's to nav dash black, not black.
We already did black white.
So the white is where the actual content is going to go, the, the links and stuff.
First thing I'm going to put in here is the close button so that have a class of nav btn just like the
open and then let's do close dash BTN as well and we'll use eFax for a dash times.
OK, so there's a close button and underneath the button is going to be another image for our logo.
So I'm just going to grab this here and put that here.
OK, and then we want our our links or our menu items, so we're going to have a you Alan Unnoted list
with a class of list and let's do an ally here with a link inside of it.
Link doesn't have to go anywhere.
And this will say teams.
We're going to have three here to begin with.
So teams, locations and let's say life at Netflix.
Now, within this, we're going to have a nested well.
So let's put another list item here.
But inside that will have a pool and a list item with a link.
And this is going to say Netflix culture.
Memmo, we're going to make all these uppercase using access so it doesn't matter if you make these
lower case or upper case.
So let's see, we have that and then we have work life balance.
Then we're going to do.
Inclusion and diversity and blog.
All right, so those are links, so it doesn't look very good, but we're going to go ahead and style
it now.
So let's jump in here.
And I'm not sure if we'll get to all the success in this video.
We might have to do the rest in the next one.
But let's start here with the fonts.
I'm going to use the Mieuli font.
So it's a question mark family and set that to them.
You apply and then we'll add that down here.
And maybe I could display Fleck's column.
That's good.
Height 100 viewport heights.
We don't really need an overflow and then we don't really need margin zero because we want it to be,
you know, right at the edge here.
So that should be good for the body.
The this text that's in the main part of the page.
I want that to be uppercase.
So we're going to say text transform, set that to uppercase.
And then that's I mean, that's pretty much it for the entire page.
Of course, you could put whatever you want here.
So we just have, you know, the where is it up here, the image in the text.
But you would have your page content here and then have the menu down here.
So next thing I want to do is the NAV button, which is this one here.
I want to position it up here, make it look a little better.
So let's add nav dash button and let's take away the borders of water.
None.
And this applies to both buttons.
So bored or none.
And then the background, we want to get rid of that grey.
So we're going to set it to transparent.
We're also going to make sure the cursor is a pointer.
And let's set the font size to a little bit bigger.
Twenty pixels.
So that's the nav button, which is on both.
Now let's do just the open button, so open dash button.
And for that we want to position that fixed within the viewport.
So position fixed.
And I want it to be ten pixels from the top and ten pixels from the left which is going to place it
right up here in the corner.
So for the nav now remember this three NAVs here.
So we're going to style the nav and then each color because it's going to come out to a certain point
so we can see all three colors.
So let's do the nav first so the nav class and that's going to be position fixed and we want it to be
right, right in the top corner.
So top zero left zero.
OK, so you're going to see that move up if you save.
And then the height of this is going to be the entire viewport.
So 100 viewport heights.
All right.
And then as far as you know, the sliding effect here, the way we do that is with a transition on the
transform property using translate excuse, translate X effects, you know, moving along the X axis,
which is the horizontal axis.
So let's add a transform here and let's say we want to translate on the x axis.
And to start off, we want it to be way over to the left off the screen, which will do negative one
hundred percent, which brings it off the screen now to have it come in.
What's going to happen is we're going to add the class of visible to each of these.
I'm just going to add it manually now.
But later on, we'll remove this and we'll just have it done with JavaScript.
But just so we can see it, we're going to set visible on all three of those, make sure it's on all
three.
And then what we'll do is take NAV.
And if it has a class of visible, then I'm going to copy this transform here and set it back to its
normal position, which is zero.
So now we can see it because visible is on all three of those.
Now we want it to have a smooth transition when it switches from this to this and back.
So we'll set a transition on the transform property.
And let's do point three seconds for the duration.
So how long it takes and then ease in out.
All right.
So I think that that's all we're going to do in this video.
And the next one will continue with the styling and then we'll add the JavaScript so we can make the
the open and close buttons function.