All right, so now we're going to finish most of the cost and then add the JavaScript for the button
functionality, and then I want to add some other effects later so we can delay because we have three
boxes, the red, white and black.
And I want them to come out like one after another.
So we will add some transition delays.
But for now, let's finish the basic styling.
So we're going to add now black ember, this black, red and white.
So for black, let's set the background color to be and let's do three, four for black.
I'm sorry for red three one.
So just really low numbers.
It's not quite black, but it's dark.
We can't see it yet because we want to add a width.
Let's do 60 percent and then I want to add a max width of 480.
So it shouldn't come out past 480 no matter what.
And then a Menwith.
So the Menwith will do three 20.
All right.
And then.
Yeah, that should do it for now.
So then the red let's do Naved Dash Red and we're going to set our background color for that to be and
then pass in for red two to nine.
So really high number and then nine and 20.
OK, now we can't see that just yet.
So let's.
Let's add a width of 95 percent.
OK, so now you can see the red comes out, but you can still see the black behind it on the side here,
which is what we want.
And then for the white part, so it's a Naved Dash White.
For that, the background color is going to be pure white, so I'll just use hexadecimal and we want
it to come out, so let's say with 95 percent and now we have what looks like a black and red stripe
here.
So when it comes out and goes in, it's going to do it at different rates.
We're going to add a delay.
But like I said, I just want to get the basic styling down first.
So I'm also going to add padding here.
Since this is wrapping, the content will do 40 pixels padding, move everything in.
Let's position this relative because we are going to want to position the close button absolute within
it.
And yeah, that's it for now.
And then for the close button, say close dash BTN, we're going to position that absolute.
And where I want to put this within the nav white container is 40 pixels from the top and 30 pixels
from the right.
So now you can see that we're also going to make it a little lighter by adding an opacity value of zero
point three, which will feed it out a bit.
Now, let's see.
This is what we have left is the list.
So let's say for the class of list, which is the the initial you will and I want to get rid of any
bullet points.
So list, style type, we're going to set that to none.
And the padding, I'm going to get rid of the default padding zero and then the list items.
So list L, I want to spread them out.
So margin 20 pixels on the top and bottom that'll spread them out.
Then we're going to do the links so the ally tags and let's set the color of that, the color I'm going
to set to be the same black that we have for the background of one of the maps.
And then let's make the font size.
Font size is going to be fourteen pixels.
I've got my semicolon here, OK, and then we want to get rid of the text underline.
So text decoration is going to be fun and let's also make it uppercase.
So text transform.
I'm going to set that to uppercase.
All right.
So looks pretty good.
Now we do have a little nested within the list and you can see it has the bullet points here.
So let's say list and then the you'll within the list will set the list style type to none.
And for padding left, it's a padding left.
We're going to set that to twenty pixels because we do want it to stick out a bit.
All right.
So I think that looks pretty good and that's most of the CSFs.
Now, I want to jump into the JavaScript here, and there's basically three things you want to grab
the open button, the closed button and the nav, although we have multiple classes of NAV one on each
of these colors.
So let's first bring in, let's say, open, underscore, beaten, and we're going to use document dot,
query selector.
And that has a class of open dash BTN.
So it's just a convention that Floren and I like to use is dashes or hyphens and access.
And then if you're going to create a variable here, you can't use a hyphen.
So you use an underscore or sometimes you'll see, you know, the camel case.
But in this case, we're just going to do underscore and then we're going to get the close button as
well.
And you could use an underscore in your classes.
I just don't like doing that.
So close button now for the NAV.
We have multiple of those.
So what that means is we have to use query selector all and we want to grab the class of NAV and that
will give us a node list that we can basically loop through.
So let's take the open button and let's add an event listener.
Right.
So out of that listener, we want to listen for click event.
When that happens will fire off a function.
And we don't have to use curly races here, but I'm going to just to make it neater.
So we'll take our NAVs and we're going to loop through.
So for each because there's multiple NAVs and we'll save for each nav element.
We want to take that nav element and we want to add the visible class.
So l dot class list dot add and we want to add the class visible.
All right.
Because we're adding it on.
Multiple now, that's why we have to loop through the node list here now, close button is going to
be pretty much the same thing, except we're removing the class.
So I'm going to put that in here and grab the close button at a click event.
And then for each nav, we want to then remove the class visible.
All right.
So I'll save that and I'm going to go ahead and delete these visible classes that I just, you know,
hardcoded in here.
So I'll get rid of those.
And it should now be off the screen.
If I click, it's going to go ahead and open.
If I click, the exit closes.
Now, it doesn't have the effect that I want.
I want it to be I want the three parts to come out kind of separately to give it a cool little effect.
So in our stylesheet here, we're going to add on to let's see, so on the nav black, basically, we're
going to just add transition delays on certain colors.
So now black right here.
Let's say we want to add a transition delay, which means that it'll just wait however long we we put
here before it actually fires off.
So I'm going to delay it by point.
Four seconds for the black.
OK, so now we close.
You can see the black takes a little longer.
Now we also want to add a delay or I should say remove the delay on the visible for black.
So what we'll do is say now dash black and if it has the class of visible, then we want the transition
delay to be zero seconds.
All right.
So it comes right out and then it kind of lags when it goes back in.
So on the red we have now red right here, let's add a transition delay, which is going to be a little
faster than the black because it's it doesn't stick out as much.
So let's do instead of what we do for for the Black Point, for let's do point two seconds for that.
And now you can see it has that effect where, you know, the red goes in and then the black goes in.
Now, when it's visible on that red
navarrette visible, basically when we open it, we want to add a transition delay of point two seconds.
So now when I open, you can see that the red has a little delay.
Now we want to do the same for the white because you can see when it opens, the red and the white come
in at the same exact time.
I don't want that.
I want the white to fan in as well.
So let's go to now of white.
And when it's not visible, we're going to set the transition delay to zero seconds.
But on the visible.
So now dash white.
And when when I say visible, that is basically when it opens.
So when the visible let's do a transition delay of point four seconds.
OK, so now you can see black, red, white when it goes in white, red, black.
So it's just the timing of the transition delay.
All right, and that that's pretty much it.
So it's just a cool little effect.
It's of course, it's responsive, you know, small screens.
This will work fine.
But yeah.
So that's going to be it for this project.
Guys hopefully liked it.
And obviously you can branded as something else, just Netflix seem to go with the colors.
So that's it.
Thanks for watching and I'll see you in the next project.