All right, so let's start on the table for our quiz title, say quiz app.
And essentially, what we're going to do is just have a placeholder, kind of a placeholder for a question,
it'll be an H2, will give it an ID and then we'll have a bunch of radio inputs for the answer.
And those will also be placeholders.
And then later on, when we get to the JavaScript, we will replace the placeholders with the actual
questions and answers and we'll use that as basically as a template for each one.
And then we can have as many question answers as we want.
So let's start off by just creating a quiz container and I'm going to give us an idea of CUI'S.
And then we'll have a class of quiz heter.
And inside here, we'll have our question, which is going to be an H2 with an idea of question, and
I'm just going to, like I said, put a placeholder here.
We'll just say question text and then under that will have a UFO with some list items in each list item
will have a radio input radius, radio input with a name of answer.
And then the ID is going to be a for this one.
And let's see, we also want to do a class answer and that should be good.
Then underneath it, we're going to have a label for is going to match the ID of the input, which is
a and let's also give this an I.D. of a underscore text because we're going to insert the question in
here.
We'll just say question for now.
So basically, we just want to copy this and each question will have four answers.
So that's one, two, three, four.
And then we just want to change some of this stuff.
So the second one, so we want the name to be answer for all of them, but the idea is going to change.
So that's going to be B and the four attribute on the label as well is going to be B and then the ID
here is going to be BTX.
And then we want to do the same here, so let's go here, here and here and let's change that to see.
And then we'll go here, here and here, and it's going to be OK, and then we want submit button that's
going to go outside of the header.
So right here and let's add a button.
We're going to give this an idea of submit and we'll say submit.
All right, so it doesn't look very good right now, but we're going to go ahead and add the success,
which isn't too bad.
So let's jump in to our stylesheet and we're going to use the Poppins font.
So I'm going to say success to questionmark family.
And let's set this.
To Poppins and then let's do a wait so t say at and then 200 semicolon 400.
I'm going to change the body font to that Poppins.
All right, so we want we also want a background color on the body, so let's set that background.
Color is going to be hexadecimal value B eight, C, six DB.
OK, and then let's add actually, that will be the background color.
We're going to use a gradient, a linear gradient for browser's and support that.
So let's use background image and set linear gradient and we'll do three 15 degrees and the colors for
this, the first one, let's do hexadecimal.
Actually it's going to be the same color here.
So we want to do that at zero percent and then comma in the next color will be EF five, EF seven F
A to 100 percent.
So give it just a little bit of a gradient look, and then we have our flex box, we can get rid of
Flex Direction column.
And let's see a line item that's good press should be OK.
So now the quiz container which wraps around everything.
So for that, I'm going to set the background color to white.
And let's give this a broader radius of 10 pixels and let's do a box shadow, so four box Shadowville
do zero zero for the offsets, 10 pixels, two pixels, and then our GBA and the car will be one hundred,
one hundred, one hundred.
And then for the alpha value will be zero point one.
OK, let's set a with here as well of six hundred pixels.
And then I'm going to set an overflow of hidden so nothing goes out of the container and then for the
for the header, remember, this whole part is the quiz header and then you have the button below it.
So let's say for the quiz had class, I want some padding and we'll just do forum, which is going to
be four times whatever the root HTML elements, font sizes.
And then for the H2, which is the question or style that let's do padding will do one room and let's
do text a line to the center and get rid of any margin.
And then for the U.S., all we don't want any bullet points.
So let's set list style type to none and let's set padding to zero.
Now for the list items say U.S. ally are U.S. ally, and I'm going to set the font size to be a little
bigger.
Let's do one point to get one point to them and then we'll set the margin on that to be one on the top
and bottom zero on the left and right and for the label.
So you'll ally label.
I just want to make the cursor into a pointer.
All right.
So if we hover over these, we get our, you know, our pointer.
So last thing we want to style is the button.
So describe button.
Let's set a background color.
And that's going to be eight E four for a D and then let's take away any border source that border to
none.
Let's also make the color of the text white.
And we want to display this as a bloc level elements, and I want it to go all the way across, set
the width to 100 percent, and let's make the cursor into a pointer.
Oops.
And for the font size, I'm going to make that one point, one RAM unit.
And then let's see for the font family we just want to inherit, so we use that Poppins font and then
the padding for the button is going to be one point three ram.
OK, so looks pretty good now for the hover save button.
And when it's in its hover state, I want to change the background color and I'm going to change it
to 73 to Denine one on hover.
OK, so it's just a little darker and then I want you to see this outline what's in its focus state.
Want to get rid of that.
So it's a button in its focus state.
Let's set the outline to none.
And I'm also going to set the background color to five E3 and three seven.
Oh, all right.
So the success is done, we have basically just a template here that we're going to use and then the
next video will have our questions in a JavaScript array and we want to basically replace it.
We want to be able to, you know, have a correct answer for each question and check that we want to
be able to submit and load the next question.
So we'll get into that next.