OK, so now we want to go ahead and make this quiz function, we just have the UI for it now.
So for the quiz, for the questions and all that, it's going to go into an array.
And I'm just going to paste this in because I don't want to just type all this out.
And basically we have just a variable called quiz data.
It's an array of objects that has a question and it has an ABCDE answer and then it also has a correct.
So the correct is obviously going to be whichever one of these is correct.
And we just have some simple questions here.
Which language runs in a Web browser?
What is CSFs HTML stand for?
What year is JavaScript launch?
Obviously you can change this, but we're going to go ahead and go with these questions.
Now, let's bring in everything we need.
First of all, we need the quiz itself, which wraps around everything.
So it's to document doGet Element by D and we're going to get the ID of quiz now for the answers.
So let's say Consed and we'll call this answer Owles.
So answer elements and we want to use document dot query selector all because there's more than one
member.
Each of these has a class of answers.
So that's what we want to get here.
So it's a class of answer and then we want the question element.
So let's say consed question element and that's going to be document dot get element by D and the H2.
The question has an idea of question.
Now we want all the the answer IDs.
So basically you know a a text through D text, so let's say const a underscore text and set that to
document dot get element by D and that's going to be a underscore text and then I'm going to copy this
down three more times.
So this one.
This one.
Let's change that to be.
This one and this one will change to see this one, and this one will change too deep.
OK, and then finally, we just need to submit button.
So let's say consed submit beaten and set that to document dot get element bidi and we're going to get
the idea of submit.
OK, so that's everything we need.
For now.
We need an index of basically the question are the current quiz.
I guess each one of these pages in each one of these is going to be a quiz.
So let's say CONSED and we want the current quiz, which is going to always start at zero.
Right, because it's an array, it's going to zero, it starts in a zero index.
And actually we're going to set this this is going to change and be reassigned.
So we want to use the let here.
And then let's also create a variable for the score, which obviously starts at zero.
And then we're going to call load quiz, which is a function that we're going to create right now.
So low quiz, we want to get the current quiz data, so let's say consed current quiz data and we'll
set that to quiz data, which is the array that we have above.
And then the index for this is going to be the current quiz values.
So this right here, which is initially set to zero.
All right, then we want to get the question aliments.
So question Àlex, that should be a lowercase L.
OK, so question element in urtext.
And we're going to set that to whatever the current current quiz data question is, because current
quiz data is one of the objects in the array and we have a question value.
So that's what we're getting here and we're going to put it into that in our text.
So if I save, we're going to see the first one here which language runs in a Web browser.
If I change the current quiz, too, we're going to see the second question.
All right.
I'm sorry.
That would be the third one would be the second question.
OK, now for the for the answers.
Remember, we have a underscore text and we're going to set the inner text and let's set that to current
quiz data.
Dot a.
Because if we look and know, if we look up here, each one of these has a value, that's what we're
getting here and putting it into the underscore text I.D. We want to do the same for the other three.
So that'll be B and this will be B, text C text will be current quiz DataDot C, and then this one
will be D.
Now one issue we're going to have when we add our eventless are on the submit and we load the next quiz
or the next, you know, question answer that we're going to have the something selected and we want
to deselect everything beforehand.
So right.
When we load load the quiz here, let's called what's called deselect answers and then we'll create
that function down here.
So deselect answers, and this is pretty simple.
We already have our answers elements, which is a no list because we query selecter all and we just
want to loop through so for each and we'll say for each answer element, then let's set the at that
particular answer element.
We want to set the check to value equal to false which will remove any checks or any selections.
All right.
Now let's add an event listener so we have our submit button.
We want to add an event listener.
So we want to listen for a click event.
And when it's clicked, we're going to call a function and we need to get the answer.
So let's say CONSED answer and we'll set that to a function called Get Selected and we'll put that function
right up here, get selected and I'm going to initialize answer.
So I'm just going to initialize this variable and then take the answer elements and loop through.
So for each answer, for each answer element then I want to check to see which one is checked.
So we'll do an if statement here and just say if that particular answer element dot checked, which
gives us a true or false, then let's set answer equal to the answer element dot I.D..
OK, we're going to set it to whatever the ideas.
And then after this for each year, we're just going to return the answer.
All right, so that will get us the answer.
In fact, let's test that out if we do a console log of answer and then I'm going to go over here,
open up my console, I'm going to choose C, which is obviously wrong.
But you can see that at log's B, Python is C, Java is A, JavaScript is D, so we're getting the not
the correct answer, but we're getting the answer that's selected.
So now we want to match that with the correct answer.
So let's get rid of that and we'll say if there's an answer.
So if I answer, then we want to check to see if the answer is equal to the correct answer, which remember
is in the array, so we can use whois data and we want whatever the current quiz is.
So we pass in that current quiz index, which starts at zero, and we want to check the correct value.
So if the answer that we select is equal to that, then we know that that's correct.
So we want to take the score and just increment it by one.
So just score plus.
Plus.
OK, then we want to go on to the next quiz.
So I'm basically saying each each of these screens is a quiz.
So we'll take the current quiz and we'll just increment it to move on to the next.
Now let's check to see if the current quiz is less than the length of the array.
So if if it's less than the quiz data, the length, that means we're not at the end.
So we want to once again called load quiz or else.
So that means that we're at the end.
We answered the last question that I'm going to take the quiz element, which is just the entire wrapper,
and I'm going to set the entire HTML and let's add that to some back ticks.
And in here we'll put in H2 and just say you answered
correctly at and then we're going to put the score so in here.
So score slash and then whatever the length of the quizzes, so we can get that with the array, which
is quiz data and then the length.
So it'll be like, you know, three out of four or whatever, and then just put questions and are each
to OK and then let's have a reload button.
So round the two will have a button and we'll just do an in line on click here and set that to location
reload.
Which will just reload the page and it will start over and he'll say reload.
So let's save it, let's try it out, I'm just going to reload this and let's go ahead and select JavaScript.
So what is Cezannes stand for?
I'm going to choose the wrong answer on purpose here, html.
Stand for choose the right answer JavaScript.
I'll choose the right answer and submit.
And you can see I answered correctly at three out of four questions.
Let's rephrase that.
You answered three out of four questions correctly.
OK, and just to show you that the reload button works, I'm just going to choose a bunch of wrong answers
here.
And if I click reload, it starts the quiz over.
All right.
So very simple little application.
Obviously, you could add much more to this.
And if you wanted to add more questions, all you would do is add to this array, OK?
And you could have these questions coming from some kind of database, coming from some kind of API.
But that's it.
Let's go ahead and move on to the next one.