OK, so we're going to get started on our testimonial box, I'm going to keep this the browser pretty
wide just so we can see the whole thing at at a at a wider width.
So in the HTML here, I just have a link to font.
Awesome.
And you can get that if you go to CDN, NJ Ask.com, just search for font.
Or just go to the font.
Awesome Web site, grab the CDN link and then let's change the title here to a testimonial box and down
here I'll get rid of this H1.
So this is going to be the container.
So testimonial Dasch container
and we want we're going to have a progress bar.
So I'm going to add that here.
So just progress dash bar, nothing inside the div.
That's where the animated line progress bar is going to go.
And then we want our quotes.
So I'm going to give us a class of eFax for fun.
Awesome.
And I want a dash quote dash.
Right.
But I'm also going to give it just a class of F a quote and I'm going to add that to both of them.
So let's copy that down and let's make this left.
And if I save that, we'll just going to see our two quotes right here.
So under the quotes, we'll have a paragraph with the class of testimonial.
And obviously this is going to be dynamic.
But for now, I'm just going to paste in some text so you can put whatever you like here or you can
just get that this exact text from from the repository.
All right.
And then under the paragraph, we're going to have a user class, which is going to have the user stuff
like the image.
So let's say image.
I'll give this a class of user das dash image.
And for the image, I'm going to take it from this random user.
So random user dot me slash API slash portraits
and let's do slash woman slash forty six jpeg.
So just give us a random image of a woman and then also I'm just going to say user.
All right.
So I save that every go now under the image we're going to have the user details so we'll have a class
of user details and then I'll have an H for and I'm going to give this a class of user name and we're
going to say my miles and then a paragraph with the class of role.
And her role is going to be marketing.
And that's it.
That's all the HTML.
So pretty simple.
Let's jump into the stylesheet here.
Now, I'm not going to use the Raboteau font with this, so I want to get rid of everything up to success.
And then from here we'll do questionmark and set the family equal to.
And I'm going to use what font to my using here.
Monserrat So M0 and T s e r a t and I'm just going to grab that font and put that right here for the
body.
K changes the font up.
I'm going to add a slightly light gray or slightly darker background color with the light gray.
So let's do it for three times and display flex.
We want everything centered.
That's correct.
Height 100 viewport heights because we want it centered both horizontally and vertically.
And then I'm just going to do padding ten pixels just so when it's on smaller screens.
We have a little bit of, you know, Rome on the edge here.
So this is the testimonial container wraps around everything Sloots style that we can actually make
this smaller.
Yeah, so let's do the testimonial container.
So for this, let's set the background color.
I'm going to set it to a hexadecimal blue, which is four, seven, six, C four, and will set the
color to be white.
And let's set the border radius rounded corners.
So I'm going to set this to, let's say, 15 pixels and let's do margin, 20 pixels, top and bottom.
Auto left and right.
Padding is going to be 50, top and bottom 80, 80 left and right.
And then let's give it a max with as well.
So, Max, what I'm going to do 768.
Yeah, and then I'm going to position it relative, because the quotes inside, I want to position those
absolute because I want the quotes like one here and one here.
So let's actually do that next.
So we have a dash quote is on both quotes, so I'll give those a color.
I want them to be kind of transparent looking.
So we'll do our Giba White.
So 255 for red, green, blue and then zero point three for the alpha because at that transparent type
look and then font size.
So let's make it bigger to twenty pixels.
Right.
And then we're going to position these to be absolute and let's set from the top 70 pixels.
So if I save that, both of them are going to be in the same exact spot.
So what we'll do is we'll first grab the right kwoh.
So F.A.A. quote dash.
Right.
And let's set that position from the left.
Forty pixels, which is going to move it over here.
Now this one, I want to be on the other side, so I'll just copy this down and let's set this quote
left and we want to go from the right.
Forty pixels.
Good.
Now if it's if the screen is smaller, like, you know, if it's around, if it's if it's under seventy
seven, sixty eight, then let's remove the quote.
So what we'll do is just add a media query down here by doing at media and inside here we want to set
the max with to seven sixty eight pixels, meaning that these styles are only going to apply if it's
under 768 pixels.
And we'll take the FAA dash quotes and display none.
OK, so if it's smaller than that, it's going to display none.
I'm also going to lessen the padding on the container if it's smaller like this.
So let's take the testimonial container and set the padding.
I believe it was fifty to twenty pixels, top and bottom and thirty left and right.
There we go.
All right, so let's move on from the quotes I want to go back above the media query here and we have
the testimonial, which is that the paragraph?
So it's a testimonial.
And I just want to change the line right here to 28 pixels just to spread the lines apart.
And as far as the text line, let's do justify like that.
OK, now for the user section here, say user, and I'm going to display as flex box and I want to center
everything, so I'm going to align items center and also justify content center.
All right, now for the image we have, the user image shows a user user image, and I want this to
be circular.
So I'm going to do a border radius of 50 percent to make it circular, a rounded and let's set the height
and the width to let's do seventy five pixels.
So that'll be the height and width, make it a little smaller and I'm just going to set object fit to
cover, which we actually don't need to have that.
But just to make sure it covers the back, the, not the background image but the, the image itself
and then user details.
So it's a user user details.
I'm just going to add margin yellows to margin left 10 pixels.
So this right here, we just want some spacing in between these.
Here are, you know, this these are pretty far apart.
So the user name, I believe is an H four.
So let's take the user name and let's remove any padding from it.
So I'm sorry, margin, remove any margin from it.
And then for the role of, say, user roll, I'm going to set the font weight to make sure the font
weight is set to normal and let's set margin.
We'll do two pixels on the top and bottom zero on the left and right.
Actually, that's kind of close together.
So it's to.
It's to 10.
Yeah, it's fine.
So the progress bar right now is just it's an empty divx, that's where we're going to have the animated
line.
So let's style the progress bar.
I'm going to give it a background of white background, color of white, and then let's give it a height
of, let's say, four pixels.
Now we can see the line, the width, make sure it's 100 percent.
And then we're going to have an animation called Grow.
We haven't created that yet, but we will it's going to take 10 seconds.
OK, so this is important because when we write our JavaScript, we want the box to change every 10
seconds as well.
So we want this progress bar to take 10 seconds to grow and we want it to grow in a linear style and
infinite so that it repeats and that should do it.
We just need to create that animation.
So let's create that in a key frame.
So the key frames and call this grow.
And this is going to be pretty simple.
We're just going to say at zero percent, we want to add a transform property and we want to scale X,
so it's going horizontal.
So X and set that to zero.
So now if I save, that's not right.
That's coming from the middle.
So we can actually change that by adding a transform origin up here.
So transform origin.
I'm going to set that to left.
There we go.
So that gives it, you know, positions it differently.
If we could also do right.
If you wanted to go that way.
But yeah, we're going to set that to left.
So that takes 10 seconds total to get to the end here, which is what we want.
So in the next video, we're going to jump into the JavaScript.
And as soon as it hits the end, you can see right now it just doesn't do anything.
It just starts over.
We want the testimonial.
We want the content to change.
So we need to use JavaScript to to manipulate the DOM.
All right.
So we'll do that next.