OK, so now we want to start the JavaScript for this project right now, when this progress bar hits
the end, it just starts over and nothing changes.
It's not dynamic.
So that's where JavaScript comes in.
So let's start off by just grabbing everything we need.
We want the testimonials and testimonials container.
So I'm just going to use document dot, query selector and we have a class of testimonials container.
So we'll grab that.
Let's grab the testimonial itself, which is the text.
So we want the class of testimonial that and then we want the image.
So we'll call this user image and that has a class of user dash image.
And we also want the user name that has a class of user name, because this is all stuff that we need
to SWAPO.
So user name.
And then finally we want the role.
So class of role and change that to roll.
All right.
So we're grabbing everything that we need from the DOM.
Let's actually just make this a little bigger.
OK, so once we do that, we need to have our testimonial stored somewhere.
Now we're just going to have them right in an array.
So let's call this testimonials we don't have.
Yes.
So we don't have testimonials up here.
I call the testimonials container.
So this is just going to be an array which I'm going to grab and paste in.
Now, ultimately, you could have this stuff coming from a database.
You could just make a, you know, a simple fetch request if you had some kind of back end API that
served this Jason data.
But for us, we're just going to have it right in here.
And I mean, that might be something you want to move on and do yourself in a lot of these projects.
I would suggest trying to add on to them, make them better, make them your own.
So we have these testimonials.
I'm going to define a variable for our index and that's going to start at one.
And then what we'll do is create a function to update the testimonial, because that's what we want
to do essentially is we want to update this data, this text, the user, the image and so on.
So what we'll do here is get from so we have this testimonials array and we can access if we have,
like, you know, testimonials one.
I'm just going to console log this for now and go down here and I'm just going to call, update, testimonial.
And if we go over here and we check out our console and see we have an object with Junn Char.
So if we go up here, you'll see Junn Char is the second one.
All right, because arrays are zero based.
So we have June char.
And obviously, if we put like two, we're going to get the next user, which is this Iida A. Niskanen?
I don't know.
Floren chooses some weird names.
So that's testimonials to which is the third position.
So what I want to do is just pass in here the index.
And I want to take from that.
I'm going to use just d structuring to pull out the fields because I don't want to have to say testimonials,
dot, index, dot, you know, dot name or whatever.
So we have these fields here, name, position, photo and text.
So what I'll do is say Consed and then with some curly brackets here, I want to pull from that item,
I want to pull the name, the position, the photo and the text from whatever the current testimonial
is using this index.
And then let's take testimonial.
So testimonial is going to be the paragraph that I brought in up above.
So bring that in and I'm going to set the inner HTML equal to the text of the current testimonial,
OK?
And then we're going to take the image.
So what does I call that.
So user image, we want to set that.
So let's say user image and we want to set the source.
We're going to say user image source equals the photo that we pull from the current testimonial.
Then we want to take the user name and we want to set that in our HTML and we're going to set that to
whatever the name is of the current testimonial.
And then finally, the role of the role set the inner HTML and we're going to set that to the position.
So the role is the same as the position.
The user name is the same as the name that we just use different classes in the in the HTML.
So now after we do that, after we set all that, we want to take that current index and increment it
by one.
So just index plus plus.
Now if we get to the end, we want to start over.
We want to go back to the first testimonial.
So let's create an if statement here.
And let's say if the if the index is greater than the testimonials dot Langguth.
So the entire length of the array and I believe we have seven of these total seven testimonials.
So the last one is going to be the six position.
So we want to say testimonials length minus one.
If index is greater than that, then we're just going to set index to zero and I'm setting index to
one initially up here because the first one is already in the HTML here.
OK, so that's going to show first and then as soon as the ten seconds pass, when that progress bar
is up, we want to call, update, testimonial.
So back in the JavaScript we have the function call right here.
But what we want to do is.
This into a set interval, because we want this to be called every 10 seconds, so set in Deyrolle takes
in a function which in this case is going to be our update testimonial and then the amount of milliseconds
that we want to call this.
So 10000 milliseconds, which is going to be 10 seconds.
And it's very important that this matches.
This right here.
So if you want this to be shorter, if you want it to be five seconds, just change this to five seconds,
change this to five thousand.
OK, so let's save that.
Let's see what happens.
So as soon as this hits the end, it should all this content should change.
OK, there he goes.
Now you can see the text changed, the user image, the user name and the role have all changed because
we assign them to whatever the current index is.
And you could do things like change the background color or something like that as well.
And like I said, you could pull this data instead of having just a static array.
You could pull it from a database or pull it from some kind of API.
So there's a lot you could do here.
This is basically just the, you know, the front facing user interface.
But but that's going to be it for now, guys.
Hopefully you enjoyed this project and I'll see you in the next one.