All right, and this project, we're going to build a random image feed where we come to the page and
it's just going to get a bunch of random images for us and we'll be able to, in the JavaScript, put
in the number of rows we want here.
I have five rows of images, three in each column or three columns in each row, I should say.
And we're not using any kind of API or anything.
What we're going to do is get the images from this this neutral source start on, splash dot com random,
and then you can put slash and then a size like 300 by 300.
OK, if I put, let's say 300 by three one, that's going to give me a different image.
And what we'll do is have that size will generate a random size and then insert those images into the
dorm using JavaScript.
So no API, no no feature requests or anything like that.
We're just going to insert random images into the dorm.
So this will be a very short project.
We can probably get it done in like a ten minute video.
All right.
So let's get started.