All right, so let's get started the should we should be able to do this in one video because it's not
too much.
So let's add a title of random image feed and then we'll add the same for this one here.
And all we really need in the HTML is a container to put everything to put our images in.
So that's that's going to be it for the HTML.
Now, before we do any styling, I just want to be able to get the images and put them in the dorm here.
So we're not actually using an API, like we're not making a request to an API that gives us imagery
URLs.
We're going to use a random Eurail from UN Splash.
In fact, I'll just show you some make it a little bit easier to understand if I put in this.
You earlier saw start on splash dot com slash random.
It's going to give me a random image.
Now, if I reload, it's going to be the same image.
So what we want to do in our script is, is create a bunch of image tags with this.
But we also need a size.
So like 300 times three hundred.
Give me a specific image, if I do three oh, one times whatever, 302, that's going to give me a different
image.
So we want to use those image sizes as well.
And those should be random.
So first thing we'll do is bring in our container.
And as I'm as I'm going here, if it's becoming clear what I'm going to do, I would suggest pausing
the video and trying it yourself.
And I know I've said that over and over in this course.
I'll probably say it a million more times, but I definitely, you know, recommend doing that.
So let's use query selector here.
And we have a class of container.
Now, the UN you URL that we're going to use, I'm going to put that into a variable called Unflashy
URL, which is http s and then saw Stotz on splash dot com slash random slash.
So that's the like the root Eurail.
We do want to have a size, but we're going to generate that randomly.
I'm also going to put the number of rows that we want.
So I want to get 10 rows of images with three images in each row.
So we'll have a for loop here and let's say let's equals zero.
And we want to say as long as I is less than whatever the rows is.
But we want to multiply that by three because we're going to have three images per row and then we want
to increment I.
And let's create an image tag so we can use create elements sorry, it should be document dot, create
elements and in here let's create an image tag and then for the source.
So image dot source, we're going to set that to some back text with the.
On Splash You, Earl, but we also need a random size, so down here we're going to have a function.
We have two functions.
One is going to be to get a random so get random number.
And we want a random number between like three hundred and three, ten.
So let's return from this function.
I want to round it down some math dot floor and here we want to take math dot random, which gives us
a random decimal and we want to multiply that by ten to give us, you know, a random number between
one and ten.
But we just want to add 300 to that.
OK, so if I go up here and I can still get a random number and we look in our console.
We get 306 by reload, three seven three three, three or six, so I want to now have a function to
get a random size and a random size being, you know, three, one times three or six or something like
that.
So let's return here.
And the tactics we're going to do get random number outside of the the curly brace will do at times
and X and then another get random number.
So if we go up here and we console log, get a random size, we get three or nine by three or seven,
there are two by three or seven.
So there's a lot of different combinations.
I mean, you might get a repeat image, but actually I know you won't because when you use the sizes,
it's always random.
I believe.
So now that we can get a random size, let's go up here.
And right after this on Splash you, Earl, we're going to put in get a random size, make sure you
put your parentheses, and then we just want to put that into the container.
So we'll grab the container and we'll append child because we're putting this inside the container,
all the images, and it's going to give us, you know, 10 rows of three.
So if I save that, you'll see that it's going to put all those images in the dorm.
Now, we want to style these.
You want to create our rose and stuff.
So in our stylesheet let's go ahead.
And for the body here, we're going to keep display flex flex direction column, align everything to
the center.
Let's get rid of overflow hidden so that we have scrollbar.
And instead of height 100 reports, let's do a mean height of one hundred reports.
So now we can see our title.
All right.
And then for the title, I'm just going to style that real quick.
Just add a margin here of let's do 10, Texel zero zero and let's do text align center.
I mean, technically, we don't need that, but we'll just add it and then for the container.
I want to display flaks, remember, all of the images are in the container, so if I turn the container
into a flex box, it turns them into a row.
And I want to just make sure I line items and justify content to center.
And then let's have them wrap on to the next line.
So do flex, wrap, wrap.
And we want to have we want three to be the max in the row.
So what we'll do is set a max with onto the container.
So Max with will do one thousand pixels because each one is going to be three hundred pixels.
So it shouldn't go past that.
All right.
And we're going to change the size, see how they're slightly different because of the sizes they're
all in the three hundred to 310 range, but they're slightly different.
So we will add a size onto the images.
So that's it for the container.
Now let's do the image.
So we'll do container image and let's just do an object fit cover.
We want to see the whole image and then we'll put some margin in between that and let's set the height
to three hundred pixels, also the width.
To 300 pixels now they're all going to be the same size and let's do a max width of one hundred percent
so they don't go out of the container and that should do it.
So if I reload, we should get a whole bunch of different random images.
And I mean, it's not going to be the most performant because we're just, you know, we're inserting
all these image tags.
But and some of them will repeat if they have the same size, apparently.
But yeah, we should have 10 rows total.
So let's see, one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10.
And if you wanted to, you could change this to, let's say, five rows and save.
And now you're should only get five rows of images and you could even put a select box here at an event,
a change event to it.
When you select, you know, five or 10 or 20, you can change the rows and you could do something like
that to add onto it.
But that's all we're going to do.
It is responsive.
So we're using flex wrap, so it'll knock on to the next line.
So on small screens is just going to be I mean, the rows, I guess, doesn't you know, we don't have
ten rows because or five rows in this case because it's only everything is stacked.
But at full screen it's going to be whatever number of rows you put here.
All right.
So I know this is a really simple project, but it just kind of gives you an idea of how you can put
things into the dorm.
We have random images, random image sizes and putting them into the source attribute of the images
and then putting them into the container.
All right, that's it.
Let's move on to the next project.