All right, so in this project, we're going to create a to do list, which looks pretty nice, pretty
nice clean design, and we're able to add it to do down here.
I'll just say to do one and you'll see that gets added.
I'll see to do two.
To do three.
And it's just going to get keep getting added down here.
Now, if I reload this, they're going to stay because we're actually going to implement local storage
at the end.
So first we're going to create the design or the the layout here.
Then we're going to add the functionality in the dorm where we can add it to do we can also mark as
completed.
So if I left click, it's going to mark as complete and if I right click it'll actually delete that.
To do so.
We'll add the dorm functionality first and then add in.
The last video will go ahead and implement local storage so that you can leave the page or reload the
page and the to dos will stay.