OK, so we're going to start on our To-Do list, so we jump into the HTML here and let's change the
title to to do list and for the body, we're not going to have much.
Basically, we're going to just have let's do an H1 will say to DOS and a form which I'm going to give
the idea of form.
And let's see, we don't need an action.
And then in this form we're just going to have one input.
So let's do an input with the class of input and also an idea of input.
It's going to be text and then I'm going to set the placeholder.
And we'll say enter your to do and I'm also going to set autocomplete to off.
OK, under that input, we're going to have a little and give that a class of to DOS and an I.D. of
to DOS.
Now this all the list items will get put in here.
When we add our to do so, it will be dynamic, you know, added to do in the input and then it'll get
shown as the list item.
But for now, I'm just going to put a sample list item.
We'll just say my first.
To do its put to actually.
OK, so that's our time.
Let's jump in to our stylesheet, and we're going to be using the Poppins font.
Poppins, and then we want to set the weight here to 200, 400, and for the body, let's set a background,
color, background, color.
We're going to do five, three times, which is a light gray.
And then the color we'll do four, four, four, which makes it a little lighter.
And we want to display flex line items now.
Flex direction.
Yeah, we'll keep flex direction as column the rest of the.
Yeah.
The rest of us should be fine actually.
Let's take off overflow hidden just in case we need scroll bars.
OK, and then the one I'm going to make it look really nice.
So let's styled that.
So the color we're going to be and is going to be one seven nine four red one three one four green and
two two six four blue.
We're going to make it really big.
So let's do font size.
Set that to ten REM.
It's going to be nice and big and we're going to make sure we text the wine center and I want it to
be.
Faded or transparent, so we're going to see the opacity to zero point four.
All right.
So that's our one now the form.
Form, I'm going to set a box shadow and for the offsets we'll do to zero and for 10 pixels for the
blur gba for the color, which is going to be black and then zero point one.
Let's give it a max width of one hundred percent and let's give it a width of 400 pixels.
All right, so that's the form itself now, the input.
Let's do that next.
So we gave I gave it a class of input and I'm going to just say border none.
And the color for that is going to be four.
Four for the font size is going to be two REM.
OK, so nice and big.
And let's add some padding to the input.
Will do one REM top and bottom two REM left and right.
And let's set, let's make it display as a block level element and set the width of it to 100 percent
of its container.
I see that already looks pretty good placeholder, let's change the color of that or say input Kalanchoe
and placeholder and then color is going to be hexadecimal value D five three times.
So it's nice and light placeholder.
And then let's do the list item.
So these right here, those don't look very good.
So let's say input list item, not input list item to do list item.
So let's do the to dos first.
Set a background color on these of white.
All right, and then let's set the padding on the to DOS to zero, and we want to get rid of those bullet
points, a LA style type.
We're going to set that to none.
And let's take off any margin as well.
OK, and then that should be good for to DOS.
Now for the allies, say, to Dos Elai, I'm going to set a border on the top for one pixel solid and
e five three times.
OK, so we can afford a top.
Let's give the cursor a pointer when we hover over them because we're going to be able to.
Right.
Click and delete them and also mark them as complete as well.
So the font size to make that bigger font size will do one point five REM and let's add some padding,
will do one room house, one room and two room on the sides.
All right.
So I think that looks pretty good.
Now, when they're completed, when they're completed, we're going to want a line through.
So let me just add manually a class here of completed and now here will say to DOS Ally, if it's completed,
then we're going to set the color to be six, three times.
And let's also give it a line through.
So text decoration will be set to line through.
OK, so if it's completed, it will look like that.
Now one thing I just realized is I forgot to put the little text at the bottom that says you left,
click the toggle complete and then right click to delete.
So we're going to go under the form here and let's add in some small tags and we'll say, say, left
click to toggle completed.
And then I want to just have a line break.
So we'll put a VR tag here and then say right click to delete to do.
All right, so that doesn't look very good, so we're just going to add a little bit of styling to the
small.
OK, so small, let's change the color or make it lighter, so I'm going to give it a value of five,
three times and let's move it down.
So margin top, I'm going to set two three ram to push it down and let's just text a line center.
OK, so I think that looks pretty good.
So now we have the UI here.
Let's actually make the outline of this the same color as the H1, though, so I'm going to grab that
right here and then let's take the input, so say input, colon focus.
So when it's in its focus state, we want the outline color.
To be that purple.
All right, cool.
So in the next video, we're going to make this function will be able to add to DOS and they'll get
Sèvres to local storage, will be able to delete them and make them complete.
So I'm just gonna I'm going to get rid of the two list items that are in here now, because that was
just to see it and style it.
So ultimately, that's going to start with nothing.
So that's it.
Let's go ahead and jump into the JavaScript in the next video.