All right, so we're going to start in our JavaScript.
Now we're going to add the just the DOM functionality for now so we can add it to do and enter and it'll
get added here.
We'll be able to market as complete and remove it, but we'll do the local storage stuff in the video
after this one.
So let's go ahead and first bring in what we need.
So we want our form document get element by D form has an idea of form and then we also want our input
so we can get the value.
And that has an idea of input.
And we also want the to dos ul so say to dos you l and that has an idea of to dos.
All right.
Now on the form we're going to add an event listener.
We want to listen for a submit of the form.
When that happens, we'll have a function, takes an event, object as an argument, and then we can
take that event object and call prevent default to prevent the form from having its default behaviour.
Then we're going to call a function called ADD to do.
All right.
So for this function, say add to do and it's going to have the option to take in a to do.
And what we'll do is initialize a variable called to do text and set that to whatever the input value
is.
Now if a to do is passed in here, then we want to set to do text two to do and then dot text.
OK, if, if it's Pastan initially, if we're just submitting to do here, it's not going to get passed
and so it'll be whatever the value is.
All right.
In fact, we can just console log and see to do text is type something in hit enter and you can see
it's getting logged.
All right.
Now, next thing is to construct a list item.
So we just want to make sure that to do text exists.
So if to do text, then let's create a to do element and we'll set this to document create element and
we're going to create a list item and then we want to check to see, let's say, if to do and to do
dot completed.
Then we're going to add the class of completed.
So to do elements dot class list dot and we're going to add the class of completed.
All right.
Outside of that let's take the to do element and let's set the entire text.
So the list item in a text is going to get set to whatever to do.
Text is all right, so save that.
Now, if I do this, nothing is going to happen just yet.
Let's go ahead and add that to the DOM.
So we'll take the to dos you l so to dos you ul and we want to append a child element and what we want
to append is the to do element, which is the list item.
And I just want to clear the form.
So we'll take the input and we'll set the value equal to nothing.
So now if I say to do one enter.
To do.
To enter.
They're going to get at it now.
Nothing happens if I click or right click or or anything.
If I reload, they're going to go away.
So the keeping them there in local storage will do that in the next video.
But I do want to be able to at least delete them and and also mark them as completed.
So let's go right above where we added it to the dorm and let's take the specific to do element and
add an event listener to it.
So say add event listener and we want to listen for a click.
And when that happens, we'll have a function and just one line.
So we don't need curly braces.
We'll just take the to do element and we want to take the class list and call actually not add.
We want to toggle because we want to be able to toggle completed.
So toggle the class of completed.
All right.
Now if I save that this is they're going to go away when I save just because the page reloads.
But let's just say to do one.
And now if I click on it, you can see that the class of completed is applied.
If I click again, it's taken away.
So it's going to toggle that class.
All right.
Now to remove we want to do a right click.
So I'm going to add another event listener.
I'm going to just grab this and instead of click, we're going to listen for context menu.
So that's going to be a right click.
So when that happens, we want to prevent the default behavior.
So I'm going to say we want this to be to go to some curly braces that and we want to also pass in,
because right now, if you right.
Click, it's going to bring that up.
We don't want that.
We want to prevent that from happening.
So let's idot prevent default.
So if I were to put something in here and now I'm right clicking I'm not seeing the, you know, the
default, the native context menu.
What I want to do though is take that to do element and remove it completely from the DOM.
So we just call removes.
Now if I put something in here and I right.
Click That goes away.
That goes away.
OK, so that's pretty much it as far as the functionality for the DOM.
So in the next video we're going to apply local storage so that every time we reload or come back to
the page, they're not gone.