OK, so now we want to basically save our to DOS to local storage and with local storage, we have a
browser API that we can use to say local storage, and we can set Eitam using set item.
We give it a key such as name and a value such as Brad.
So it's how we can set an item.
Now, when you save something in local storage, it's going to be saved as a string.
If you have an array or an object or something like that, you can save it, but you have to first wrap
it in Jason Dortch String Afie, which will do just that little string string, iffier object array,
whatever it is.
And then when you pull it out from local storage, sort of get something we say local storage doget
item and let's say it's like an object but it's string of.
So when you take it out you want to wrap it in Jason Dot parse.
OK, so you want to remember those two four objects in arrays and stuff, string Afie and parse.
OK, and to remove items you can do local storage not remove items.
So it's pretty easy API to work with.
Now we're going to go ahead and let's start with checking our local storage first, because obviously
if there are items in local storage, we want them to load here.
So up at the top, let's say conse to Duse, set that to local storage dot get item and we're going
to call it to Duse.
Now, as I said, it's going to be stored as a string.
We want to pass this back into an array.
So let's say Jason pass, OK, so that those will be put into DOS.
And then we want to say if there are to DOS in local storage, then let's go ahead and loop through
each one.
So to do support for each and say for each to do we want to add to do and pass in the to do OK or else
if there's not, I mean I guess we don't need that house because if there are to do that we'll do this.
If not, it won't.
So if I save that, you'll see it's not doing anything.
And if I open up my, my dev tools here and I go to application, you can see what you have in local
storage right here.
So we I actually have my empty notes, array or string a wide array from another app.
In this course we can clear local storage if we want.
I can't really see this.
So if I click that, that gets rid of it, this will clear all.
So there's nothing in local storage right now.
So it's not it's obviously not going to show any to DOS.
Now when we add a to do let's see, let's go down to the bottom here and at the very end we're going
to have a function called update URLs.
So we're going to update our local storage.
And basically we're just going to have one function that's going to take all of the to DOS and the list
item in the list items and put them into local storage.
And then we can call update local storage when we add them, also when we market as complete or when
we remove them.
So it's kind of a function that will run in multiple places instead of just having an add to do and
then a remove to do and then doing our local storage in separate functions.
So let's say update else.
And like I said, we're going to take all the list items.
So to DOS, let's say to DOS element plural and set that to document and then we'll use query selector
all because we're selecting all of the list items which will put that into a node list which is similar
to an array.
I'm also going to initialize a to DOS array and what I want to do, no pun intended, is take the to
DOS element, which is all our elements, which are all the list items, and I want to loop through
those.
So for each to do elements.
So for each one of these, I want to take that to DOS Array that I just initialized and I want to push
on to it.
And what I want to push is an object that has a text value.
So text for the key and then to do elements of the current, to do inter text, whatever is in the inner
text is going to get put in there.
We also want to know if it's completed so we'll have a completed property here with to do element,
make sure it's singular.
It's it's this specific to do in the loop.
We want to see if the class contains so.
Class list that contains.
And we want to see if it contains the class of completed, if it does, then this is going to be true.
If it doesn't, then it will be false.
All right.
So now that we have this to dos pushing on everything that's in the list item, let's update local storage.
So after this, for each which ends right here, let's take local storage and say set item.
And we want to set this as to Duse and it's going to be the to dos Arae.
However, that's that's going to be an array.
So we need to wrap that in dot string of five first.
So we want to wrap to DOS in that and then stored in local storage.
All right.
So now if I save and they go here and I say to do one enter, you can see that it gets added down here
in local storage.
The value it looks like an array, but an array of objects.
But it's actually a string.
It's stratified.
But when we pull it out up here, we pass it back into an array and then we go ahead and we loop through
and we show it here.
So now if I reload to do what is still there now, if I market as complete, it works in the DOM.
But if I reload, it's not marked as complete because we did not update local storage when we marked
it as complete.
So let's do that.
Let's go down to let's see.
So right here we toggle the class of complete.
We actually want to change this to be a code block.
So we want our curly braces because it's going to be more than one line.
All right, so after we mark it as complete, let's call up the local storage, we want to do the same
thing when we remove.
So right after remove, we want to call update local storage.
So now, if I were to let's add another one.
We'll see to do two.
And if I go ahead and mark that as complete, that should change in here.
And you can see right here to do one complete is false.
If I click, that changes it to true.
And now if I reload, it's still there because it's again, it's fetching from local storage.
If I remove.
So if I.
Right.
Click here and reload and see it's still gone.
Click again.
That updates local storage as well.
So we have this one function that takes care.
We can just put it anywhere.
We want to update the local storage at any time based on the list items and based on if they're, you
know, completed or not.
All right.
So hopefully that makes sense.
I think it's it's a decent amount of functionality for such a small amount of code.
And I'd encourage you to create a different type of vape, maybe a workout tracker or something like
that with, you know, more fields and a different design and maybe add some other functionality like
update so you can update the resource as well.
All right.
So that's it, guys.
Hopefully you enjoyed this and I will see you in the next video.